<?xml version="1.0"?>
<CUSTOMSAMPLES>

  <SAMPLE>
    <AUTHOR>Byron</AUTHOR>
    <CONTENT>
I say 'tis blood -- my blood! the pure warm stream Which ran in the veins of my fathers, and in ours When we were in our youth, and had one heart, And loved each other as we should not love, And this was shed: but still it rises up, Colouring the clouds, that shut me out from Heaven, Where thou art not -- and I shall never be.
    </CONTENT>
  </SAMPLE>

  <SAMPLE>
    <AUTHOR>Shakespeare</AUTHOR>
    <CONTENT>
madam, yonder's my lord your son with a patch of velvet on's face; whether there be a scar under 't or no, the velvet knows; but 'tis a goodly patch of velvet. His left cheek is a cheek of two pile and a half, but his right cheek is worn bare. scar nobly got, or a noble scar, is a good liv'ry of honour; so belike is that. But it is your carbonado'd face. Let us go see your son, I pray you; long to talk with the young noble soldier. Faith, there's a dozen of 'em, with delicate fine hats, and most courteous feathers, which bow the head and nod at every man.
    </CONTENT>
  </SAMPLE>

  <SAMPLE>
    <AUTHOR>Shakespeare</AUTHOR>
    <CONTENT>
If I may trust the flattering truth of sleep My dreams presage some joyful news at hand. My bosom's lord sits lightly in his throne, And all this day an unaccustom'd spirit Lifts me above the ground with cheerful thoughts. dreamt my lady came and found me dead (Strange dream that gives a dead man leave to think!) And breath'd such life with kisses in my lips That I reviv'd and was an emperor. Ah me! how sweet is love itself possess'd, When but love's shadows are so rich in joy!
    </CONTENT>
  </SAMPLE>

  <SAMPLE>
    <AUTHOR>Shakespeare</AUTHOR>
    <CONTENT>
Come, thou shalt bear a letter to him straight. Let me carry another to his horse; for that's the more capable creature. My mind is troubled, like a fountain stirr'd; And I myself see not the bottom of it. Exeunt ACHILLES and PATROCLUS Would the fountain of your mind were clear again, that I might water an ass at it. I had rather be a tick in a sheep than such a valiant ignorance. Exit
    </CONTENT>
  </SAMPLE>

  <SAMPLE>
    <AUTHOR>Byron</AUTHOR>
    <CONTENT>
When the great signal ran from Heaven to Hell -- About ten million times the distance reckoned From our sun to its earth, as we can tell How much time it takes up, even to a second, For every ray that travels to dispel The fogs of London, through which, dimly beaconed, The weathercocks are gilt some thrice a year, If that the summer is not too severe:
    </CONTENT>
  </SAMPLE>

  <SAMPLE>
    <AUTHOR>Shakespeare</AUTHOR>
    <CONTENT>
'Justice and your father's wrath, should he take me in his dominion, could not be so cruel to me as you, O the dearest of creatures, would even renew me with your eyes. Take notice that I am in Cambria, at Milford Haven. What your own love will out of this advise you, follow. So he wishes you all happiness that remains loyal to his vow, and your increasing in love
    </CONTENT>
  </SAMPLE>

  <SAMPLE>
    <AUTHOR>Byron</AUTHOR>
    <CONTENT>
She was like me in lineaments -- her eyes -- Her hair -- her features -- all, to the very tone Even of her voice, they said were like to mine; But softened all, and tempered into beauty: She had the same lone thoughts and wanderings, The quest of hidden knowledge, and a mind To comprehend the Universe: nor these Alone, but with them gentler powers than mine, Pity, and smiles, and tears -- which I had not; And tenderness -- but that I had for her; Humility -- and that I never had. Her faults were mine -- her virtues were her own -- loved her, and destroyed her!
    </CONTENT>
  </SAMPLE>

  <SAMPLE>
    <AUTHOR>Byron</AUTHOR>
    <CONTENT>
There are seven pillars of Gothic mould, And in each ring there is a chain; That iron is a cankering thing, For in these limbs its teeth remain, With marks that will not wear away, Till I have done with this new day, Which now is painful to these eyes, Which have not seen the sun so rise For years -- I cannot count them o'er, lost their long and heavy score When my last brother drooped and died, And I lay living by his side.
    </CONTENT>
  </SAMPLE>

  <SAMPLE>
    <AUTHOR>Shakespeare</AUTHOR>
    <CONTENT>
Jupiter, how weary are my spirits! Care not for my spirits, if my legs were not weary. could find in my heart to disgrace my man's apparel, and to cry like a woman; but I must comfort the weaker vessel, as doublet and hose ought to show itself courageous to petticoat; therefore, courage, good Aliena. pray you bear with me; I cannot go no further. For my part, I had rather bear with you than bear you; yet I should bear no cross if I did bear you; for I think you have no money in your purse. Well,. this is the Forest of Arden. Ay, now am I in Arden; the more fool I; when I was at home I was in a better place; but travellers must be content.
    </CONTENT>
  </SAMPLE>

  <SAMPLE>
    <AUTHOR>Shakespeare</AUTHOR>
    <CONTENT>
My mistress' eyes are nothing like the sun, Coral is far more red, than her lips red, If snow be white, why then her breasts are dun: If hairs be wires, black wires grow on her head: have seen roses damasked, red and white, But no such roses see I in her cheeks, And in some perfumes is there more delight, Than in the breath that from my mistress reeks. love to hear her speak, yet well I know, That music hath a far more pleasing sound: grant I never saw a goddess go, My mistress when she walks treads on the ground. And yet by heaven I think my love as rare, As any she belied with false compare.
    </CONTENT>
  </SAMPLE>

  <SAMPLE>
    <AUTHOR>Shakespeare</AUTHOR>
    <CONTENT>
Now the hungry lion roars, And the wolf behowls the moon; Whilst the heavy ploughman snores, All with weary task fordone. Now the wasted brands do glow, Whilst the screech-owl, screeching loud, Puts the wretch that lies in woe In remembrance of a shroud. Now it is the time of night That the graves, all gaping wide, Every one lets forth his sprite, In the church-way paths to glide. And we fairies, that do run By the triple Hecate's team From the presence of the sun, Following darkness like a dream, Now are frolic. Not a mouse Shall disturb this hallowed house. am sent with broom before, To sweep the dust behind the door.
    </CONTENT>
  </SAMPLE>

  <SAMPLE>
    <AUTHOR>Shakespeare</AUTHOR>
    <CONTENT>
'"When thou impressest, what are precepts worth Of stale example? When thou wilt inflame, How coldly those impediments stand forth, Of wealth, of filial fear, law, kindred, fame! Love's arms are peace, 'gainst rule, 'gainst sense, 'gainst shame. And sweetens, in the suff'ring pangs it bears, The aloes of all forces, shocks and fears.
    </CONTENT>
  </SAMPLE>

  <SAMPLE>
    <AUTHOR>Byron</AUTHOR>
    <CONTENT>
Though thou seest me not pass by, Thou shalt feel me with thine eye As a thing that, though unseen, Must be near thee, and hath been; And when in that secret dread Thou hast turned around thy head, Thou shalt marvel I am not As thy shadow on the spot, And the power which thou dost feel Shall be what thou must conceal.
    </CONTENT>
  </SAMPLE>

  <SAMPLE>
    <AUTHOR>Shakespeare</AUTHOR>
    <CONTENT>
Nay, if there be no remedy for it, but that you will needs buy and sell men and women like beasts, we shall have all the world drink brown and white bastard. heavens! what stuff is here? 'Twas never merry world since, of two usuries, the merriest was put down, and the worser allow'd by order of law a furr'd gown to keep him warm; and furr'd with fox on lamb-skins too, to signify that craft, being richer than innocency, stands for the
    </CONTENT>
  </SAMPLE>

  <SAMPLE>
    <AUTHOR>Byron</AUTHOR>
    <CONTENT>
The poor dear Mussulwomen whom I mention Have none of these instructive pleasant people, And one would seem to them a new invention, Unknown as bells within a Turkish steeple; think 'twould almost be worth while to pension (Though best-sown projects very often reap ill) missionary author -- just to preach Our Christian usage of the parts of speech.
    </CONTENT>
  </SAMPLE>

  <SAMPLE>
    <AUTHOR>Byron</AUTHOR>
    <CONTENT>
You'd better walk about begirt with briars, Instead of coat and smallclothes, than put on single stitch reflecting upon friars, Although you swore it only was in fun; They'd haul you o'er the coals, and stir the fires Of Phlegethon with every mother's son, Nor say one mass to cool the cauldron's bubble That boiled your bones, unless you paid them double.
    </CONTENT>
  </SAMPLE>

  <SAMPLE>
    <AUTHOR>Byron</AUTHOR>
    <CONTENT>
Here Satan said, "I know this man of old, And have expected him for some time here; sillier fellow you will scarce behold, Or more conceited in his petty sphere: But surely it was not worth while to fold Such trash below your wing, Asmodeus dear: We had the poor wretch safe (without being bored With carriage) coming of his own accord.
    </CONTENT>
  </SAMPLE>

  <SAMPLE>
    <AUTHOR>Shakespeare</AUTHOR>
    <CONTENT>
Antony, thou wouldst say. my lord! Speak to me home; mince not the general tongue; Name Cleopatra as she is call'd in Rome. Rail thou in Fulvia's phrase, and taunt my faults With such full licence as both truth and malice Have power to utter. O, then we bring forth weeds When our quick minds lie still, and our ills told us Is as our earing. Fare thee well awhile. At your noble pleasure. Exit From Sicyon, ho, the news! Speak there! The man from Sicyon- is there such an one? He stays upon your will. Let him appear. These strong Egyptian fetters I must break, Or lose myself in dotage.
    </CONTENT>
  </SAMPLE>

  <SAMPLE>
    <AUTHOR>Shakespeare</AUTHOR>
    <CONTENT>
If thou survive my well-contented day, When that churl death my bones with dust shall cover And shalt by fortune once more re-survey These poor rude lines of thy deceased lover: Compare them with the bett'ring of the time, And though they be outstripped by every pen, Reserve them for my love, not for their rhyme, Exceeded by the height of happier men. then vouchsafe me but this loving thought, 'Had my friend's Muse grown with this growing age, dearer birth than this his love had brought To march in ranks of better equipage: But since he died and poets better prove, Theirs for their style I'll read, his for his love'.
    </CONTENT>
  </SAMPLE>

  <SAMPLE>
    <AUTHOR>Byron</AUTHOR>
    <CONTENT>
"Look to the earth, I said, and say again: When this old, blind, mad, helpless, weak, poor worm Began in youth's first bloom and flush to reign, The world and he both wore a different form, And much of earth and all the watery plain Of Ocean called him king: through many a storm His isles had floated on the abyss of Time; For the rough virtues chose them for their clime.
    </CONTENT>
  </SAMPLE>

  <SAMPLE>
    <AUTHOR>Shakespeare</AUTHOR>
    <CONTENT>
noble company! What are their pleasures? Because they speak no English, thus they pray'd To tell your Grace, that, having heard by fame Of this so noble and so fair assembly This night to meet here, they could do no less, Out of the great respect they bear to beauty, But leave their flocks and, under your fair conduct, Crave leave to view these ladies and entreat An hour of revels with 'em. Say, Lord Chamberlain, They have done my poor house grace; for which I pay 'em thousand thanks, and pray 'em take their pleasures.  Ye have found him, Cardinal. You hold a fair assembly; you do well, lord. You are a churchman, or, I'll tell you, Cardinal, should judge now unhappily. am glad Your Grace is grown so pleasant. My Lord Chamberlain, Prithee come hither: what fair lady's that? An't please your Grace, Sir Thomas Bullen's
    </CONTENT>
  </SAMPLE>

  <SAMPLE>
    <AUTHOR>Byron</AUTHOR>
    <CONTENT>
The Abbot said, "The steeple may do well, But for the bells, you've broken them, I wot." Morgante answered, "Let them pay in Hell The penalty who lie dead in yon grot;" And hoisting up the horse from where he fell, He said, "Now look if I the gout have got, Orlando, in the legs, -- or if I have force;" -- And then he made two gambols with the horse.
    </CONTENT>
  </SAMPLE>

  <SAMPLE>
    <AUTHOR>Shakespeare</AUTHOR>
    <CONTENT>
Are you agreed? Sir, I will serve him; for I do find your hangman is a more penitent trade than your bawd; he doth oftener ask forgiveness. You, sirrah, provide your block and your axe to-morrow four o'clock. Come on, bawd; I will instruct thee in my trade; follow. do desire to learn, sir; and I hope, if you have occasion to use me for your own turn, you shall find me yare; for truly, sir, for your kindness I owe you a good turn. Call hither Barnardine and Claudio. Exeunt ABHORSON and POMPEY Th' one has my pity; not a jot the other, Being a murderer, though he were my brother.
    </CONTENT>
  </SAMPLE>

  <SAMPLE>
    <AUTHOR>Byron</AUTHOR>
    <CONTENT>
When all the Chiefs Have been disposed of. Some have fled to Chiozza; But there are thousands in pursuit of them, And such precaution ta'en on terra firma, As well as in the islands, that we hope None will escape to utter in strange lands His libellous tale of treasons 'gainst the Senate.
    </CONTENT>
  </SAMPLE>

  <SAMPLE>
    <AUTHOR>Byron</AUTHOR>
    <CONTENT>
First Cit. 'Tis vain. cannot hear him. -- How his hoary hair Streams on the wind like foam upon the wave! Now -- now -- he kneels -- and now they form a circle Round him, and all is hidden -- but I see The lifted sword in air --  -- Ah! hark! it falls!
    </CONTENT>
  </SAMPLE>

  <SAMPLE>
    <AUTHOR>Shakespeare</AUTHOR>
    <CONTENT>
Come, neighbour. The boy shall lead our horses down the hill; We'll walk afoot awhile and ease our legs. Thieves. Stand! Traveller. Jesus bless us! Fal. Strike! down with them! cut the villains' throats! Ah, whoreson caterpillars! bacon-fed knaves! they hate us youth. Down with them! fleece them! Traveller. O, we are undone, both we and ours for ever! Fal. Hang ye, gorbellied knaves, are ye undone? No, ye fat chuffs; would your store were here! On, bacons on! What, ye knaves! young men must live. You are grandjurors, are ye? We'll jure ye,
    </CONTENT>
  </SAMPLE>

  <SAMPLE>
    <AUTHOR>Byron</AUTHOR>
    <CONTENT>
Saint Peter sat by the celestial gate, And nodded o'er his keys: when, lo! there came wondrous noise he had not heard of late -- rushing sound of wind, and stream, and flame; In short, a roar of things extremely great, Which would have made aught save a Saint exclaim; But he, with first a start and then a wink, Said, "There's another star gone out, I think!"
    </CONTENT>
  </SAMPLE>

  <SAMPLE>
    <AUTHOR>Shakespeare</AUTHOR>
    <CONTENT>
Marvellous well for the pen. do dine to-day at the father's of a certain pupil of mine; where, if, before repast, it shall please you to gratify the table with a grace, I will, on my privilege I have with the parents of the foresaid child or pupil, undertake your ben venuto; where I will prove those verses to be very unlearned, neither savouring of poetry, wit, nor invention. I beseech your
    </CONTENT>
  </SAMPLE>

  <SAMPLE>
    <AUTHOR>Shakespeare</AUTHOR>
    <CONTENT>
Let me see what he writes, and when he means to come.  'I have sent you a daughter-in-law; she hath recovered the King and undone me. I have wedded her, not bedded her; and sworn to make the "not" eternal. You shall hear I am run away; know it before the report come. If there be breadth enough in the world, I will hold a long distance. My duty to you. Your unfortunate son,
    </CONTENT>
  </SAMPLE>

  <SAMPLE>
    <AUTHOR>Byron</AUTHOR>
    <CONTENT>
Long years! -- It tries the thrilling frame to bear And eagle-spirit of a Child of Song -- Long years of outrage -- calumny -- and wrong; Imputed madness, prisoned solitude, In honour of the sacred war for Him, The God who was on earth and is in Heaven, For He has strengthened me in heart and limb. That through this sufferance I might be forgiven, have employed my penance to record How Salem's shrine was won, and how adored.
    </CONTENT>
  </SAMPLE>

  <SAMPLE>
    <AUTHOR>Byron</AUTHOR>
    <CONTENT>
Then Satan turned and waved his swarthy hand, Which stirred with its electric qualities Clouds farther off than we can understand, Although we find him sometimes in our skies; Infernal thunder shook both sea and land In all the planets -- and Hell's batteries Let off the artillery, which Milton mentions As one of Satan's most sublime inventions.
    </CONTENT>
  </SAMPLE>

  <SAMPLE>
    <AUTHOR>Shakespeare</AUTHOR>
    <CONTENT>
Alack what poverty my muse brings forth, That having such a scope to show her pride, The argument all bare is of more worth Than when it hath my added praise beside. blame me not if I no more can write! Look in your glass and there appears a face, That over-goes my blunt invention quite, Dulling my lines, and doing me disgrace. Were it not sinful then striving to mend, To mar the subject that before was well? For to no other pass my verses tend, Than of your graces and your gifts to tell. And more, much more than in my verse can sit, Your own glass shows you, when you look in it.
    </CONTENT>
  </SAMPLE>

  <SAMPLE>
    <AUTHOR>Shakespeare</AUTHOR>
    <CONTENT>
When in the chronicle of wasted time, see descriptions of the fairest wights, And beauty making beautiful old rhyme, In praise of ladies dead, and lovely knights, Then in the blazon of sweet beauty's best, Of hand, of foot, of lip, of eye, of brow, see their antique pen would have expressed, Even such a beauty as you master now. So all their praises are but prophecies Of this our time, all you prefiguring, And for they looked but with divining eyes, They had not skill enough your worth to sing: For we which now behold these present days, Have eyes to wonder, but lack tongues to praise.
    </CONTENT>
  </SAMPLE>

  <SAMPLE>
    <AUTHOR>Shakespeare</AUTHOR>
    <CONTENT>
He wears his honour in a box unseen That hugs his kicky-wicky here at home, Spending his manly marrow in her arms, Which should sustain the bound and high curvet Of Mars's fiery steed. To other regions! France is a stable; we that dwell in't jades; Therefore, to th' war! It shall be so; I'll send her to my house, Acquaint my mother with my hate to her, And wherefore I am fled; write to the King That which I durst not speak. His present gift Shall furnish me to those Italian fields Where noble fellows strike. War is no strife To the dark house and the detested wife. Will this capriccio hold in thee, art sure? Go with me to my chamber and advise me. I'll send her straight away. To-morrow I'll to the wars, she to her single sorrow. Why, these balls bound; there's noise in it. 'Tis hard: young man married is a man that's marr'd. Therefore away, and leave her bravely; go. The King has done you wrong; but, hush, 'tis so. Exeunt
    </CONTENT>
  </SAMPLE>

  <SAMPLE>
    <AUTHOR>Byron</AUTHOR>
    <CONTENT>
Many are Poets who have never penned Their inspiration, and perchance the best: They felt, and loved, and died, but would not lend Their thoughts to meaner beings; they compressed The God within them, and rejoined the stars Unlaurelled upon earth, but far more blessed Than those who are degraded by the jars Of Passion, and their frailties linked to fame, Conquerors of high renown, but full of scars. Many are Poets but without the name; For what is Poesy but to create From overfeeling Good or Ill; and aim Built up between us, and will die alone, Beholding with the dark eye of a Seer The evil days to gifted souls foreshown, Foretelling them to those who will not hear; As in the old time, till the hour be come When Truth shall strike their eyes through many a tear, And make them own the Prophet in his tomb.
    </CONTENT>
  </SAMPLE>

  <SAMPLE>
    <AUTHOR>Byron</AUTHOR>
    <CONTENT>
He ceased, and drew forth an MS.; and no Persuasion on the part of Devils, Saints, Or Angels, now could stop the torrent; so He read the first three lines of the contents: But at the fourth, the whole spiritual show Had vanished, with variety of scents, Ambrosial and sulphureous, as they sprang, Like lightning, off from his "melodious twang."
    </CONTENT>
  </SAMPLE>

  <SAMPLE>
    <AUTHOR>Byron</AUTHOR>
    <CONTENT>
And promised him an office of great ease. But, said Orlando, "Saracen insane! come to kill you, if it shall so please God, not to serve as footboy in your train; You with his monks so oft have broke the peace -- Vile dog! 'tis past his patience to sustain." The Giant ran to fetch his arms, quite furious, When he received an answer so injurious.
    </CONTENT>
  </SAMPLE>

  <SAMPLE>
    <AUTHOR>Shakespeare</AUTHOR>
    <CONTENT>
The moon shines bright. In such a night as this, When the sweet wind did gently kiss the trees, And they did make no noise- in such a night, Troilus methinks mounted the Troyan walls, And sigh'd his soul toward the Grecian tents, Where Cressid lay that night. In such a night Did Thisby fearfully o'ertrip the dew, And saw the lion's shadow ere himself, And ran dismayed away. In such a night Stood Dido with a willow in her hand Upon the wild sea-banks, and waft her love To come again to Carthage. In such a night Medea gathered the enchanted herbs That did renew old AEson. In such a night Did Jessica steal from the wealthy Jew, And with an unthrift love did run from Venice As far as Belmont. In such a night Did young Lorenzo swear he lov'd her well, Stealing her soul with many vows of faith, And ne'er a true one. In such a night Did pretty Jessica, like a little shrew, Slander her love, and he forgave it her. would out-night you, did no body come; But, hark, I hear the footing of a man.
    </CONTENT>
  </SAMPLE>

  <SAMPLE>
    <AUTHOR>Byron</AUTHOR>
    <CONTENT>
Thou hast known me From boyhood, ever ready to assist thee In all fair objects of advancement, which Beseem one of thy station; I would promise Ere thy request was heard, but that the hour, Thy bearing, and this strange and hurried mode Of suing, gives me to suspect this visit Hath some mysterious import -- but say on -- What has occurred, some rash and sudden broil? -- cup too much, a scuffle, and a stab? Mere things of every day; so that thou hast not Spilt noble blood, I guarantee thy safety; But then thou must withdraw, for angry friends And relatives, in the first burst of vengeance, Are things in Venice deadlier than the laws.
    </CONTENT>
  </SAMPLE>

  <SAMPLE>
    <AUTHOR>Shakespeare</AUTHOR>
    <CONTENT>
It is vain that you would speak with Timon; For he is set so only to himself That nothing but himself which looks like man Is friendly with him. Bring us to his cave. It is our part and promise to th' Athenians To speak with Timon. At all times alike Men are not still the same; 'twas time and griefs That fram'd him thus. Time, with his fairer hand, Offering the fortunes of his former days, The former man may make him. Bring us to him, And chance it as it may. Here is his cave. Peace and content be here! Lord Timon! Timon! Look out, and speak to friends. Th' Athenians By two of their most reverend Senate greet thee. Speak to them, noble Timon.
    </CONTENT>
  </SAMPLE>

  <SAMPLE>
    <AUTHOR>Shakespeare</AUTHOR>
    <CONTENT>
Hum! And to procure safe conduct from Agamemnon. Agamemnon! Ay, my lord. Ha! What you say to't? God buy you, with all my heart. Your answer, sir. If to-morrow be a fair day, by eleven of the clock it will go one way or other. Howsoever, he shall pay for me ere he has me. Your answer, sir. Fare ye well, with all my heart. Why, but he is not in this tune, is he? No, but he's out a tune thus. What music will be in him when Hector has knock'd out his brains I know not; but, I am sure, none; unless the fiddler Apollo get his sinews to make catlings
    </CONTENT>
  </SAMPLE>

  <SAMPLE>
    <AUTHOR>Shakespeare</AUTHOR>
    <CONTENT>
But I have cause to pry into this pedant; Methinks he looks as though he were in love. Yet if thy thoughts, Bianca, be so humble To cast thy wand'ring eyes on every stale- Seize thee that list. If once I find thee ranging, will be quit with thee by changing. Exit
    </CONTENT>
  </SAMPLE>

  <SAMPLE>
    <AUTHOR>Byron</AUTHOR>
    <CONTENT>
Orlando had Cortana bare in hand; To split the head in twain was what he schemed: Cortana clave the skull like a true brand, And pagan Passamont died unredeemed; Yet harsh and haughty, as he lay he banned, And most devoutly Macon still blasphemed; But while his crude, rude blasphemies he heard, Orlando thanked the Father and the Word, --
    </CONTENT>
  </SAMPLE>

  <SAMPLE>
    <AUTHOR>Shakespeare</AUTHOR>
    <CONTENT>
The other two, slight air, and purging fire, Are both with thee, wherever I abide, The first my thought, the other my desire, These present-absent with swift motion slide. For when these quicker elements are gone In tender embassy of love to thee, My life being made of four, with two alone, Sinks down to death, oppressed with melancholy. Until life's composition be recured, By those swift messengers returned from thee, Who even but now come back again assured, Of thy fair health, recounting it to me. This told, I joy, but then no longer glad, send them back again and straight grow sad.
    </CONTENT>
  </SAMPLE>

  <SAMPLE>
    <AUTHOR>Byron</AUTHOR>
    <CONTENT>
"But since he's here, let's see what he has done." "Done!" cried Asmodeus, "he anticipates The very business you are now upon, And scribbles as if head clerk to the Fates. as this, like Balaam's, prates?" "Let's hear," quoth Michael, "what he has to say: You know we're bound to that in every way."
    </CONTENT>
  </SAMPLE>

  <SAMPLE>
    <AUTHOR>Shakespeare</AUTHOR>
    <CONTENT>
O monstrous! but one halfpennyworth of bread to this intolerable deal of sack! What there is else, keep close; we'll read it at more advantage. There let him sleep till day. I'll to the court in the morning . We must all to the wars. and thy place shall be honourable. I'll procure this fat rogue a charge of foot; and I know, his death will be a march of twelve score. The money shall be paid back again with advantage. Be with me betimes in the morning, and so good morrow, Peto. Peto. Good morrow, good my lord.
    </CONTENT>
  </SAMPLE>

  <SAMPLE>
    <AUTHOR>Byron</AUTHOR>
    <CONTENT>
also like to dine on becaficas, To see the Sun set, sure he'll rise to-morrow, Not through a misty morning twinkling weak as drunken man's dead eye in maudlin sorrow, But with all Heaven t'himself; the day will break as Beauteous as cloudless, nor be forced to borrow That sort of farthing candlelight which glimmers Where reeking London's smoky cauldron simmers.
    </CONTENT>
  </SAMPLE>

  <SAMPLE>
    <AUTHOR>Shakespeare</AUTHOR>
    <CONTENT>
Lord, who would live turmoiled in the court And may enjoy such quiet walks as these? This small inheritance my father left me Contenteth me, and worth a monarchy. seek not to wax great by others' waning Or gather wealth I care not with what envy; Sufficeth that I have maintains my state, And sends the poor well pleased from my gate. Here's the lord of the soil come to seize me for a stray, for
    </CONTENT>
  </SAMPLE>

  <SAMPLE>
    <AUTHOR>Byron</AUTHOR>
    <CONTENT>
Then he was faithful too, as well as amorous; So that no sort of female could complain, Although they're now and then a little clamorous, He never put the pretty souls in pain; His heart was one of those which most enamour us, Wax to receive, and marble to retain: He was a lover of the good old school, Who still become more constant as they cool.
    </CONTENT>
  </SAMPLE>

  <SAMPLE>
    <AUTHOR>Shakespeare</AUTHOR>
    <CONTENT>
I'll to the Doctor; he hath my good will, And none but he, to marry with Nan Page. That Slender, though well landed, is an idiot; And he my husband best of all affects. The Doctor is well money'd, and his friends Potent at court; he, none but he, shall have her, Though twenty thousand worthier come to crave her. Exit
    </CONTENT>
  </SAMPLE>

  <SAMPLE>
    <AUTHOR>Byron</AUTHOR>
    <CONTENT>
Avolio, and Arino, and Othone Of Normandy, and Richard Paladin, Wise Hamo, and the ancient Salamone, Walter of Lion's Mount, and Baldovin, Who was the son of the sad Ganellone, Were there, exciting too much gladness in The son of Pepin: -- when his knights came hither, He groaned with joy to see them altogether.
    </CONTENT>
  </SAMPLE>

  <SAMPLE>
    <AUTHOR>Byron</AUTHOR>
    <CONTENT>
The spirits were in neutral space, before The gate of Heaven; like eastern thresholds is The place where Death's grand cause is argued o'er, And souls despatched to that world or to this; And therefore Michael and the other wore civil aspect: though they did not kiss, Yet still between his Darkness and his Brightness There passed a mutual glance of great politeness.
    </CONTENT>
  </SAMPLE>

  <SAMPLE>
    <AUTHOR>Shakespeare</AUTHOR>
    <CONTENT>
wonder how the King escap'd our hands. While we pursu'd the horsemen of the north, He slily stole away and left his men; Whereat the great Lord of Northumberland, Whose warlike ears could never brook retreat, Cheer'd up the drooping army, and himself, Lord Clifford, and Lord Stafford, all abreast, Charg'd our main battle's front, and, breaking in, Were by the swords of common soldiers slain. Lord Stafford's father, Duke of Buckingham, Is either slain or wounded dangerous; cleft his beaver with a downright blow. That this is true, father, behold his blood. And, brother, here's the Earl of Wiltshire's blood, Whom I encount'red as the battles join'd. Speak thou for me, and tell them what I did.
    </CONTENT>
  </SAMPLE>

  <SAMPLE>
    <AUTHOR>Shakespeare</AUTHOR>
    <CONTENT>
France is revolted from the English quite, Except some petty towns of no import. The Dauphin Charles is crowned king in Rheims; The Bastard of Orleans with him is join'd; Reignier, Duke of Anjou, doth take his part; The Duke of Alencon flieth to his side. The Dauphin crowned king! all fly to him! whither shall we fly from this reproach? We will not fly but to our enemies' throats. Bedford, if thou be slack I'll fight it out. Gloucester, why doubt'st thou of my forwardness? An army have I muster'd in my thoughts, Wherewith already France is overrun.
    </CONTENT>
  </SAMPLE>

  <SAMPLE>
    <AUTHOR>Byron</AUTHOR>
    <CONTENT>
Oh! that I had the art of easy writing What should be easy reading! could I scale Parnassus, where the Muses sit inditing Those pretty poems never known to fail, How quickly would I print (the world delighting) Grecian, Syrian, or Assyrian tale; And sell you, mixed with western Sentimentalism, Some samples of the finest Orientalism.
    </CONTENT>
  </SAMPLE>

  <SAMPLE>
    <AUTHOR>Shakespeare</AUTHOR>
    <CONTENT>
Away, old man! give me thy hand! away! King Lear hath lost, he and his daughter ta'en. Give me thy hand! come on! Glou. No further, sir. A man may rot even here. Edg. What, in ill thoughts again? Men must endure Their going hence, even as their coming hither; Ripeness is all. Come on. Glou. And that's true too. Exeunt.
    </CONTENT>
  </SAMPLE>

  <SAMPLE>
    <AUTHOR>Byron</AUTHOR>
    <CONTENT>
I love all noble qualities which merit Love, and I loved my father, who first taught me To single out what we should love in others, And to subdue all tendency to lend The best and purest feelings of our nature To baser passions. He bestowed my hand Upon Faliero: he had known him noble, Brave, generous; rich in all the qualities Of soldier, citizen, and friend; in all Such have I found him as my father said. His faults are those that dwell in the high bosoms Of men who have commanded; too much pride, And the deep passions fiercely fostered by The uses of patricians, and a life Spent in the storms of state and war; and also From the quick sense of honour, which becomes duty to a certain sign, a vice When overstrained, and this I fear in him. And then he has been rash from his youth upwards, Yet tempered by redeeming nobleness In such sort, that the wariest of republics Has lavished all its chief employs upon him, From his first fight to his last embassy, From which on his return the Dukedom met him.
    </CONTENT>
  </SAMPLE>

  <SAMPLE>
    <AUTHOR>Shakespeare</AUTHOR>
    <CONTENT>
Lost and recovered in a day again! This is a double honour, Burgundy. Yet heavens have glory for this victory! Warlike and martial Talbot, Burgundy Enshrines thee in his heart, and there erects Thy noble deeds as valour's monuments. Thanks, gentle Duke. But where is Pucelle now? think her old familiar is asleep. Now where's the Bastard's braves, and Charles his gleeks? What, all amort? Rouen hangs her head for grief That such a valiant company are fled. Now will we take some order in the town, Placing therein some expert officers; And then depart to Paris to the King, For there young Henry with his nobles lie. What Lord Talbot pleaseth Burgundy. But yet, before we go, let's not forget The noble Duke of Bedford, late deceas'd, But see his exequies fulfill'd in Rouen. braver soldier never couched lance, gentler heart did never sway in court; But kings and mightiest potentates must die, For that's the end of human misery. Exeunt
    </CONTENT>
  </SAMPLE>

  <SAMPLE>
    <AUTHOR>Byron</AUTHOR>
    <CONTENT>
I'll answer that anon. -- Away with me --  -- The clouds grow thicker --  -- there -- now lean on me -- Place your foot here -- here, take this staff, and cling moment to that shrub -- now give me your hand, And hold fast by my girdle -- softly -- well -- The Chalet will be gained within an hour: Come on, we'll quickly find a surer footing, And something like a pathway, which the torrent Hath washed since winter. -- Come,'tis bravely done -- You should have been a hunter. -- Follow me.
    </CONTENT>
  </SAMPLE>

  <SAMPLE>
    <AUTHOR>Byron</AUTHOR>
    <CONTENT>
"God save the king!" It is a large economy In God to save the like; but if he will Be saving, all the better; for not one am I Of those who think damnation better still: hardly know too if not quite alone am I In this small hope of bettering future ill By circumscribing, with some slight restriction, The eternity of Hell's hot jurisdiction.
    </CONTENT>
  </SAMPLE>

  <SAMPLE>
    <AUTHOR>Byron</AUTHOR>
    <CONTENT>
What matters my forgiveness? an old man's, Worn out, scorned, spurned, abused; what matters then My pardon more than my resentment, both Being weak and worthless? I have lived too long; But let us change the argument. -- My child! My injured wife, the child of Loredano, The brave, the chivalrous, how little deemed Thy father, wedding thee unto his friend, That he was linking thee to shame! -- Alas! Shame without sin, for thou art faultless. Hadst thou But had a different husband, any husband In Venice save the Doge, this blight, this brand, This blasphemy had never fallen upon thee. So young, so beautiful, so good, so pure, To suffer this, and yet be unavenged!
    </CONTENT>
  </SAMPLE>

  <SAMPLE>
    <AUTHOR>Byron</AUTHOR>
    <CONTENT>
You would but lop the hand, and I the head; You would but smite the scholar, I the master; You would but punish Steno, I the Senate. cannot pause on individual hate, In the absorbing, sweeping, whole revenge, Which, like the sheeted fire from Heaven, must blast Without distinction, as it fell of yore, Where the Dead Sea hath quenched two Cities' ashes.
    </CONTENT>
  </SAMPLE>

  <SAMPLE>
    <AUTHOR>Shakespeare</AUTHOR>
    <CONTENT>
Amen, if you love her; for the lady is very well worthy. Claud. You speak this to fetch me in, my lord. Pedro. By my troth, I speak my thought. Claud. And, in faith, my lord, I spoke mine. Bene. And, by my two faiths and troths, my lord, I spoke mine. Claud. That I love her, I feel. Pedro. That she is worthy, I know. Bene. That I neither feel how she should be loved, nor know how she should be worthy, is the opinion that fire cannot melt out of me. will die in it at the stake. Pedro. Thou wast ever an obstinate heretic in the despite of
    </CONTENT>
  </SAMPLE>

  <SAMPLE>
    <AUTHOR>Shakespeare</AUTHOR>
    <CONTENT>
How now, my son? 'Tis certain she is fled. Go in and cheer the King. He rages; none Dare come about him. All the better. May This night forestall him of the coming day! Exit love and hate her; for she's fair and royal, And that she hath all courtly parts more exquisite Than lady, ladies, woman. From every one The best she hath, and she, of all compounded, Outsells them all. I love her therefore; but Disdaining me and throwing favours on The low Posthumus slanders so her judgment That what's else rare is chok'd; and in that point will conclude to hate her, nay, indeed, To be reveng'd upon her. For when fools
    </CONTENT>
  </SAMPLE>

  <SAMPLE>
    <AUTHOR>Byron</AUTHOR>
    <CONTENT>
"And are you really, truly, now a Turk? With any other women did you wive? Is't true they use their fingers for a fork? Well, that's the prettiest Shawl -- as I'm alive! You'll give it me? They say you eat no pork. And how so many years did you contrive To -- Bless me! did I ever? No, I never Saw a man grown so yellow! How's your liver?
    </CONTENT>
  </SAMPLE>

  <SAMPLE>
    <AUTHOR>Shakespeare</AUTHOR>
    <CONTENT>
So are you to my thoughts as food to life, Or as sweet-seasoned showers are to the ground; And for the peace of you I hold such strife As 'twixt a miser and his wealth is found. Now proud as an enjoyer, and anon Doubting the filching age will steal his treasure, Now counting best to be with you alone, Then bettered that the world may see my pleasure, Sometime all full with feasting on your sight, And by and by clean starved for a look, Possessing or pursuing no delight Save what is had, or must from you be took. Thus do I pine and surfeit day by day, Or gluttoning on all, or all away.
    </CONTENT>
  </SAMPLE>

  <SAMPLE>
    <AUTHOR>Shakespeare</AUTHOR>
    <CONTENT>
my dear lord, lo where your son is borne! Thou antic Death, which laugh'st us here to scorn, Anon, from thy insulting tyranny, Coupled in bonds of perpetuity, Two Talbots, winged through the lither sky, In thy despite shall scape mortality. thou whose wounds become hard-favoured Death, Speak to thy father ere thou yield thy breath! Brave Death by speaking, whether he will or no; Imagine him a Frenchman and thy foe. Poor boy! he smiles, methinks, as who should say, Had Death been French, then Death had died to-day. Come, come, and lay him in his father's arms. My spirit can no longer bear these harms. Soldiers, adieu! I have what I would have, Now my old arms are young John Talbot's grave.
    </CONTENT>
  </SAMPLE>

  <SAMPLE>
    <AUTHOR>Byron</AUTHOR>
    <CONTENT>
Be patient but till midnight. Get your musters, And bid our friends prepare their companies: Set all in readiness to strike the blow, Perhaps in a few hours: we have long waited For a fit time -- that hour is on the dial, It may be, of to-morrow's sun: delay Beyond may breed us double danger. See That all be punctual at our place of meeting, And armed, excepting those of the Sixteen, Who will remain among the troops to wait The signal.
    </CONTENT>
  </SAMPLE>

  <SAMPLE>
    <AUTHOR>Byron</AUTHOR>
    <CONTENT>
Mont Blanc is the Monarch of mountains; They crowned him long ago On a throne of rocks, in a robe of clouds, With a Diadem of snow. Around his waist are forests braced, The Avalanche in his hand; But ere it fall, that thundering ball Must pause for my command. The Glacier's cold and restless mass Moves onward day by day; But I am he who bids it pass, Or with its ice delay. am the Spirit of the place, Could make the mountain bow And quiver to his caverned base -- And what with me would'st Thou?
    </CONTENT>
  </SAMPLE>

  <SAMPLE>
    <AUTHOR>Byron</AUTHOR>
    <CONTENT>
Mine were my faults, and mine be their reward. My whole life was a contest, since the day That gave me being, gave me that which marred The gift, -- a fate, or will, that walked astray; And I at times have found the struggle hard, And thought of shaking off my bonds of clay: But now I fain would for a time survive, If but to see what next can well arrive.
    </CONTENT>
  </SAMPLE>

  <SAMPLE>
    <AUTHOR>Byron</AUTHOR>
    <CONTENT>
"Wilkes," said the Devil, "I understand all this; You turned to half a courtier ere you died, And seem to think it would not be amiss To grow a whole one on the other side Of Charon's ferry; you forget that his Reign is concluded; whatsoe'er betide, He won't be sovereign more: you've lost your labour, For at the best he will but be your neighbour.
    </CONTENT>
  </SAMPLE>

  <SAMPLE>
    <AUTHOR>Byron</AUTHOR>
    <CONTENT>
And where is He thou lovedst? in the tomb, Where should the happy Lover be! For him could Time unfold a brighter doom, Or offer aught like thee? He in the thickest battle died, Where Death is Pride; And Thou his widow -- not his bride, Wer't not more free -- Here where all love, till Love is made bondage or a trade, Here -- thou so redolent of Beauty, In whom Caprice had seemed a duty, Thou, who could'st trample and despise The holiest chain of human ties For him, the dear One in thine eyes, Broke it no more. Thy heart was withered to it's Core, It's hopes, it's fears, it's feelings o'er: Thy Blood grew Ice when his was shed, And Thou the Vestal of the Dead.
    </CONTENT>
  </SAMPLE>

  <SAMPLE>
    <AUTHOR>Byron</AUTHOR>
    <CONTENT>
Then he addressed himself to Satan: "Why -- My good old friend, for such I deem you, though Our different parties make us fight so shy, ne'er mistake you for a personal foe; Our difference political, and I Trust that, whatever may occur below, You know my great respect for you: and this Makes me regret whate'er you do amiss --
    </CONTENT>
  </SAMPLE>

  <SAMPLE>
    <AUTHOR>Shakespeare</AUTHOR>
    <CONTENT>
He will not fight with me, Domitius? No. Why should he not? He thinks, being twenty times of better fortune, He is twenty men to one. To-morrow, soldier, By sea and land I'll fight. Or I will live, Or bathe my dying honour in the blood Shall make it live again. Woo't thou fight well? I'll strike, and cry 'Take all.' Well said; come on. Call forth my household servants; let's to-night Be bounteous at our meal.
    </CONTENT>
  </SAMPLE>

  <SAMPLE>
    <AUTHOR>Byron</AUTHOR>
    <CONTENT>
She was not old, nor young, nor at the years Which certain people call a "certain age," Which yet the most uncertain age appears, Because I never heard, nor could engage person yet by prayers, or bribes, or tears, To name, define by speech, or write on page, The period meant precisely by that word, -- Which surely is exceedingly absurd.
    </CONTENT>
  </SAMPLE>

  <SAMPLE>
    <AUTHOR>Shakespeare</AUTHOR>
    <CONTENT>
Fairies, black, grey, green, and white, You moonshine revellers, and shades of night, You orphan heirs of fixed destiny, Attend your office and your quality. Crier Hobgoblin, make the fairy oyes. Elves, list your names; silence, you airy toys. Cricket, to Windsor chimneys shalt thou leap; Where fires thou find'st unrak'd, and hearths unswept, There pinch the maids as blue as bilberry; Our radiant Queen hates sluts and sluttery. They are fairies; he that speaks to them shall die. I'll wink and couch; no man their works must eye.  Oh, oh, oh! Corrupt, corrupt, and tainted in desire! About him, fairies; sing a scornful rhyme; And, as you trip, still pinch him to your time. Fie on sinful fantasy! Fie on lust and luxury! Lust is but a bloody fire, Kindled with unchaste desire, Fed in heart, whose flames aspire, As thoughts do blow them, higher and higher. Pinch him, fairies, mutually; Pinch him for his villainy; Pinch him and burn him and turn him about, Till candles and star-light and moonshine be out.
    </CONTENT>
  </SAMPLE>

  <SAMPLE>
    <AUTHOR>Byron</AUTHOR>
    <CONTENT>
Upon the way let your cry be of War And of the Genoese Fleet, by the first dawn Discerned before the port; form round the palace, Within whose court will be drawn out in arms My nephew and the clients of our house, Many and martial; while the bell tolls on, Shout ye, "Saint Mark! -- the foe is on our waters!"
    </CONTENT>
  </SAMPLE>

  <SAMPLE>
    <AUTHOR>Shakespeare</AUTHOR>
    <CONTENT>
I prithee, Harry, withdraw thyself; thou bleedest too much. Lord John of Lancaster, go you unto him. John. Not I, my lord, unless I did bleed too. Prince. I do beseech your Majesty make up, Lest Your retirement do amaze your friends. King. I will do so. My Lord of Westmoreland, lead him to his tent. West. Come, my lord, I'll lead you to your tent. Prince. Lead me, my lord, I do not need your help; And God forbid a shallow scratch should drive The Prince of Wales from such a field as this, Where stain'd nobility lies trodden on, And rebels' arms triumph in massacres! John. We breathe too long. Come, cousin Westmoreland, Our duty this way lies. For God's sake, come.  Prince. By God, thou hast deceiv'd me, Lancaster! did not think thee lord of such a spirit. Before, I lov'd thee as a brother, John; But now, I do respect thee as my soul. King. I saw him hold Lord Percy at the point With lustier maintenance than I did look for Of such an ungrown warrior. Prince. O, this boy Lends mettle to us all! Exit.
    </CONTENT>
  </SAMPLE>

  <SAMPLE>
    <AUTHOR>Byron</AUTHOR>
    <CONTENT>
How many things! I loved thee -- thou Loved'st me not: another was The Idol of thy virgin vow, And I was, what I am, Alas! And what he is, and what thou art, And what we were, is like the rest: We must endure it as a test, And old Ordeal of the Heart.
    </CONTENT>
  </SAMPLE>

  <SAMPLE>
    <AUTHOR>Byron</AUTHOR>
    <CONTENT>
And by the way about the giants dead Orlando with Morgante reasoned: "Be, For their decease, I pray you, comforted, And, since it is God's pleasure, pardon me; thousand wrongs unto the monks they bred; And our true Scripture soundeth openly, Good is rewarded, and chastised the ill, Which the Lord never faileth to fulfil:
    </CONTENT>
  </SAMPLE>

  <SAMPLE>
    <AUTHOR>Shakespeare</AUTHOR>
    <CONTENT>
Sister, have comfort. All of us have cause To wail the dimming of our shining star; But none can help our harms by wailing them. Madam, my mother, I do cry you mercy; did not see your Grace. Humbly on my knee crave your blessing. God bless thee; and put meekness in thy breast, Love, charity, obedience, and true duty! Amen!  And make me die a good old
    </CONTENT>
  </SAMPLE>

  <SAMPLE>
    <AUTHOR>Shakespeare</AUTHOR>
    <CONTENT>
Came you from Padua, from Bellario? From both, my lord. Bellario greets your Grace.  'Your Grace shall understand that at the receipt of your letter I am very sick; but in the instant that your messenger came, in loving visitation was with me a young doctor of Rome- his name is Balthazar. I acquainted him with the cause in controversy between the Jew and Antonio the merchant; we turn'd o'er many books together; he is furnished with my opinion which, bettered with his own learning-the greatness whereof I cannot enough commend- comes with him at my importunity to fill up your Grace's request in my stead. I beseech you let his lack of years be no impediment to let him lack a reverend estimation, for I never knew so young a body with so old a head. I leave him to your gracious acceptance, whose trial shall better publish his
    </CONTENT>
  </SAMPLE>

  <SAMPLE>
    <AUTHOR>Shakespeare</AUTHOR>
    <CONTENT>
Well met, Corporal Nym. Good morrow, Lieutenant Bardolph. What, are Ancient Pistol and you friends yet? For my part, I care not; I say little, but when time shall serve, there shall be smiles- but that shall be as it may. I dare not fight; but I will wink and hold out mine iron. It is a simple one; but what though? It will toast cheese, and it will endure cold as another man's sword will; and there's an end. will bestow a breakfast to make you friends; and we'll be all three sworn brothers to France. Let't be so, good Corporal
    </CONTENT>
  </SAMPLE>

  <SAMPLE>
    <AUTHOR>Byron</AUTHOR>
    <CONTENT>
No Chemistry for them unfolds her gases, No Metaphysics are let loose in lectures, No Circulating Library amasses Religious novels, moral tales, and strictures Upon the living manners, as they pass us; No Exhibition glares with annual pictures; They stare not on the stars from out their attics, Nor deal (thank God for that!) in Mathematics.
    </CONTENT>
  </SAMPLE>

  <SAMPLE>
    <AUTHOR>Byron</AUTHOR>
    <CONTENT>
My Lord, I looked but to my father's wishes, Hallowed by his last words, and to my heart For doing all its duties, and replying With faith to him with whom I was affianced. Ambitious hopes ne'er crossed my dreams; and should The hour you speak of come, it will be seen so.
    </CONTENT>
  </SAMPLE>

  <SAMPLE>
    <AUTHOR>Byron</AUTHOR>
    <CONTENT>
noble Lady of the Italian shore Lovely and young, herself a happy bride, Commands a verse, and will not be denied, From me a wandering Englishman; I tore One sonnet, but invoke the muse once more To hail these gentle hearts which Love has tied, In Youth, Birth, Beauty, genially allied And blest with Virtue's soul, and Fortune's store. sweeter language, and a luckier bard Were worthier of your hopes, Auspicious Pair! And of the sanctity of Hymen's shrine, But, -- since I cannot but obey the Fair, To render your new state your true reward, May your Fate be like Hers, and unlike mine.
    </CONTENT>
  </SAMPLE>

  <SAMPLE>
    <AUTHOR>Byron</AUTHOR>
    <CONTENT>
Formed a sepulchral melodrame. Of all The fools who flocked to swell or see the show, Who cared about the corpse? The funeral Made the attraction, and the black the woe, There throbbed not there a thought which pierced the pall; And when the gorgeous coffin was laid low, It seemed the mockery of hell to fold The rottenness of eighty years in gold.
    </CONTENT>
  </SAMPLE>

  <SAMPLE>
    <AUTHOR>Shakespeare</AUTHOR>
    <CONTENT>
Come now, a roundel and a fairy song; Then, for the third part of a minute, hence: Some to kill cankers in the musk-rose buds; Some war with rere-mice for their leathern wings, To make my small elves coats; and some keep back The clamorous owl that nightly hoots and wonders At our quaint spirits. Sing me now asleep; Then to your offices, and let me rest.
    </CONTENT>
  </SAMPLE>

  <SAMPLE>
    <AUTHOR>Byron</AUTHOR>
    <CONTENT>
Orlando answered, "Baron just and pious, If this good wish your heart can really move To the true God, who will not then deny us Eternal honour, you will go above, And, if you please, as friends we will ally us, And I will love you with a perfect love. Your idols are vain liars, full of fraud: The only true God is the Christian's God.
    </CONTENT>
  </SAMPLE>

  <SAMPLE>
    <AUTHOR>Byron</AUTHOR>
    <CONTENT>
Once more in Man's frail world! which I had left So long that 'twas forgotten; and I feel The weight of clay again, -- too soon bereft Of the Immortal Vision which could heal My earthly sorrows, and to God's own skies Lift me from that deep Gulf without repeal, Where late my ears rung with the damned cries Of Souls in hopeless bale; and from that place Of lesser torment, whence men may arise Pure from the fire to join the Angelic race; Midst whom my own bright Beatric Their mother, the cold partner who hath brought Destruction for a dowry -- this to see And feel, and know without repair, hath taught bitter lesson; but it leaves me free: have not vilely found, nor basely sought, They made an Exile -- not a Slave of me.
    </CONTENT>
  </SAMPLE>

  <SAMPLE>
    <AUTHOR>Shakespeare</AUTHOR>
    <CONTENT>
The devil damn thee black, thou cream-faced loon! Where got'st thou that goose look? There is ten thousand- Geese, villain? Soldiers, sir. Go prick thy face and over-red thy fear, Thou lily-liver'd boy. What soldiers, patch? Death of thy soul! Those linen cheeks of thine Are counselors to fear. What soldiers, whey-face? The English force, so please you. Take thy face hence. Exit Servant. Seyton-I am sick at heart, When I behold- Seyton, I say!- This push Will cheer me ever or disseat me now. have lived long enough. My way of life Is fall'n into the sear, the yellow leaf, And that which should accompany old age, As honor, love, obedience, troops of friends, must not look to have; but in their stead, Curses, not loud but deep, mouth-honor, breath, Which the poor heart would fain deny and dare not.
    </CONTENT>
  </SAMPLE>

  <SAMPLE>
    <AUTHOR>Byron</AUTHOR>
    <CONTENT>
From thy false tears I did distil An essence which hath strength to kill; From thy own heart I then did wring The black blood in its blackest spring; From thy own smile I snatched the snake, For there it coiled as in a brake; From thy own lip I drew the charm Which gave all these their chiefest harm; In proving every poison known, found the strongest was thine own.
    </CONTENT>
  </SAMPLE>

  <SAMPLE>
    <AUTHOR>Shakespeare</AUTHOR>
    <CONTENT>
See, Reignier, see, thy daughter prisoner! To whom? To me. Suffolk, what remedy? am a soldier and unapt to weep Or to exclaim on fortune's fickleness. Yes, there is remedy enough, my lord. Consent, and for thy honour give consent, Thy daughter shall be wedded to my king, Whom I with pain have woo'd and won thereto; And this her easy-held imprisonment Hath gain'd thy daughter princely liberty. Speaks Suffolk as he thinks? Fair Margaret knows That Suffolk doth not flatter, face, or feign. Upon thy princely warrant I descend To give thee answer of thy just demand.
    </CONTENT>
  </SAMPLE>

  <SAMPLE>
    <AUTHOR>Shakespeare</AUTHOR>
    <CONTENT>
What's the noise? have done my work ill, friends. O, make an end Of what I have begun. The star is fall'n. And time is at his period. Alas, and woe! Let him that loves me, strike me dead. Not I. Nor I. Nor any one. Exeunt guard Thy death and fortunes bid thy followers fly. This sword but shown to Caesar, with this tidings, Shall enter me with him.
    </CONTENT>
  </SAMPLE>

  <SAMPLE>
    <AUTHOR>Byron</AUTHOR>
    <CONTENT>
But one such day occurs within an age; My life is little less than one, and 'tis Enough for Fortune to have granted once, That which scarce one more favoured citizen May win in many states and years. But why Thus speak I? Venice has forgot that day -- Then why should I remember it? -- Farewell, Sweet Angiolina! I must to my cabinet; There's much for me to do -- and the hour hastens.
    </CONTENT>
  </SAMPLE>

  <SAMPLE>
    <AUTHOR>Shakespeare</AUTHOR>
    <CONTENT>
Peace, good Doll! Do not speak like a death's-head; do not bid me remember mine end. Sirrah, what humour's the Prince of? good shallow young fellow. 'A would have made a good pantler; 'a would ha' chipp'd bread well. They say Poins has a good wit. He a good wit! hang him, baboon! His wit's as thick as Tewksbury mustard; there's no more conceit in him than is in a
    </CONTENT>
  </SAMPLE>

  <SAMPLE>
    <AUTHOR>Shakespeare</AUTHOR>
    <CONTENT>
How now, Thersites! What, lost in the labyrinth of thy fury? Shall the elephant Ajax carry it thus? He beats me, and I rail at him. O worthy satisfaction! Would it were otherwise: that could beat him, whilst he rail'd at me! 'Sfoot, I'll learn to conjure and raise devils, but I'll see some issue of my spiteful execrations. Then there's Achilles, a rare engineer! If Troy be not taken till these two undermine it, the walls will stand till they fall of themselves. O thou great thunder-darter of Olympus, forget that thou art Jove, the king of gods, and, Mercury, lose all the serpentine craft of thy caduceus, if ye take not that little little less-than-little wit from them that they have! which short-arm'd ignorance itself knows is so abundant scarce, it will not in circumvention deliver a fly from a spider without drawing their massy irons and cutting the web. After this, the vengeance on the whole camp! or, rather, the Neapolitan bone-ache! for that, methinks, is the curse depending on those that war for a placket. I have said my prayers; and devil Envy say 'Amen.' What ho! my Lord Achilles!
    </CONTENT>
  </SAMPLE>

  <SAMPLE>
    <AUTHOR>Shakespeare</AUTHOR>
    <CONTENT>
Say, Somerville, what says my loving son? And by thy guess how nigh is Clarence now? At Southam I did leave him with his forces, And do expect him here some two hours hence.  Then Clarence is at hand; I hear his drum. It is not his, my lord; here Southam lies. The drum your Honour hears marcheth from Warwick. Who should that be? Belike unlook'd for friends. They are at hand, and you shall quickly know.
    </CONTENT>
  </SAMPLE>

  <SAMPLE>
    <AUTHOR>Shakespeare</AUTHOR>
    <CONTENT>
Why strew'st thou sugar on that bottled spider Whose deadly web ensnareth thee about? Fool, fool! thou whet'st a knife to kill thyself. The day will come that thou shalt wish for me To help thee curse this poisonous bunch-back'd toad. False-boding woman, end thy frantic curse, Lest to thy harm thou move our patience. Foul shame upon you! you have all mov'd mine. Were you well serv'd, you would be taught your
    </CONTENT>
  </SAMPLE>

  <SAMPLE>
    <AUTHOR>Byron</AUTHOR>
    <CONTENT>
He died! his death made no great stir on earth: His burial made some pomp; there was profusion Of velvet -- gilding -- brass -- and no great dearth Of aught but tears -- save those shed by collusion: For these things may be bought at their true worth; Of elegy there was the due infusion -- Bought also; and the torches, cloaks and banners, Heralds, and relics of old Gothic manners,
    </CONTENT>
  </SAMPLE>

  <SAMPLE>
    <AUTHOR>Byron</AUTHOR>
    <CONTENT>
loved all Solitude -- but little thought To spend I know not what of life, remote From all communion with existence, save The maniac and his tyrant; -- had I been Their fellow, many years ere this had seen My mind like theirs corrupted to its grave. But who hath seen me writhe, or heard me rave? Perchance in such a cell we suffer more Than the wrecked sailor on his desert shore; The world is all before him -- mine is here, Scarce twice the space they must accord my bier. What though he perish, he may lift his eye, And with a dying glance upbraid the sky; will not raise my own in such reproof, Although 'tis clouded by my dungeon roof.
    </CONTENT>
  </SAMPLE>

  <SAMPLE>
    <AUTHOR>Byron</AUTHOR>
    <CONTENT>
Long years ago -- so long, they are a doubt Passion shall tear thee when all passions cease In other men, or mellow into virtues; And Majesty which decks all other heads, Shall crown to leave thee headless; honours shall But prove to thee the heralds of Destruction, And hoary hairs of Shame, and both of Death, But not such death as fits an agd man."40 Thus saying, he passed on. -- That Hour is come.
    </CONTENT>
  </SAMPLE>

  <SAMPLE>
    <AUTHOR>Shakespeare</AUTHOR>
    <CONTENT>
What is become of Marcius? Slain, sir, doubtless. Following the fliers at the very heels, With them he enters; who, upon the sudden, Clapp'd to their gates. He is himself alone, To answer all the city. noble fellow! Who sensibly outdares his senseless sword, And when it bows stand'st up. Thou art left, Marcius; carbuncle entire, as big as thou art, Were not so rich a jewel. Thou wast a soldier Even to Cato's wish, not fierce and terrible Only in strokes; but with thy grim looks and The thunder-like percussion of thy sounds Thou mad'st thine enemies shake, as if the world Were feverous and did tremble.
    </CONTENT>
  </SAMPLE>

  <SAMPLE>
    <AUTHOR>Shakespeare</AUTHOR>
    <CONTENT>
God, seest Thou this, and bearest so long? It made me laugh to see the villain run. Follow the knave, and take this drab away. Alas, sir, we did it for pure need! Let them be whipp'd through every market town till they come to Berwick, from whence they came. Exeunt MAYOR, BEADLE, WIFE, c. Duke Humphrey has done a miracle to-day. True; made the lame to leap and fly away. But you have done more miracles than I: You made in a day, my lord, whole towns to fly.
    </CONTENT>
  </SAMPLE>

  <SAMPLE>
    <AUTHOR>Byron</AUTHOR>
    <CONTENT>
I need them not, But can endure thy pity. I depart -- 'Tis time -- farewell! -- Here's gold, and thanks for thee -- No words -- it is thy due. -- Follow me not -- know my path -- the mountain peril's past: And once again I charge thee, follow not!
    </CONTENT>
  </SAMPLE>

  <SAMPLE>
    <AUTHOR>Shakespeare</AUTHOR>
    <CONTENT>
The ditty does remember my drown'd father. This is no mortal business, nor no sound That the earth owes. I hear it now above me. The fringed curtains of thine eye advance, And say what thou seest yond. What is't? a spirit? Lord, how it looks about! Believe me, sir, It carries a brave form. But 'tis a spirit. No, wench; it eats and sleeps and hath such senses As we have, such. This gallant which thou seest Was in the wreck; and but he's something stain'd With grief, that's beauty's canker, thou mightst call him goodly person. He hath lost his fellows, And strays about to find 'em. might call him thing divine; for nothing natural ever saw so noble.  A word, good
    </CONTENT>
  </SAMPLE>

  <SAMPLE>
    <AUTHOR>Shakespeare</AUTHOR>
    <CONTENT>
Here come two of Sir John Falstaffs men, as I think. Good morrow, honest gentlemen. beseech you, which is Justice Shallow? am Robert Shallow, sir, a poor esquire of this county, and one of the King's justices of the peace. What is your good pleasure with me? My captain, sir, commends him to you; my captain, Sir John Falstaff- a tall gentleman, by heaven, and a most gallant
    </CONTENT>
  </SAMPLE>

  <SAMPLE>
    <AUTHOR>Byron</AUTHOR>
    <CONTENT>
change came o'er the spirit of my dream. The Lady of his love was wed with One Who did not love her better: -- in her home, thousand leagues from his, -- her native home, She dwelt, begirt with growing Infancy, Daughters and sons of Beauty, -- but behold! Upon her face there was the tint of grief, The settled shadow of an inward strife, And an unquiet drooping of the eye, As if its lid were charged with unshed tears. What could her grief be? -- she had all she loved, And he who had so loved her was not there To trouble with bad hopes, or evil wish, Or ill-repressed affliction, her pure thoughts. What could her grief be? -- she had loved him not, Nor given him cause to deem himself beloved, Nor could he be a part of that which preyed Upon her mind -- a spectre of the past.
    </CONTENT>
  </SAMPLE>

  <SAMPLE>
    <AUTHOR>Byron</AUTHOR>
    <CONTENT>
Love in full life and length, not love ideal, No, nor ideal beauty, that fine name, But something better still, so very real, That the sweet Model must have been the same; thing that you would purchase, beg, or steal, Wer't not impossible, besides a shame: The face recalls some face, as 'twere with pain, You once have seen, but ne'er will see again;
    </CONTENT>
  </SAMPLE>

  <SAMPLE>
    <AUTHOR>Byron</AUTHOR>
    <CONTENT>
I do believe you; and I know you true: For Love -- romantic Love -- which in my youth knew to be illusion, and ne'er saw Lasting, but often fatal, it had been No lure for me, in my most passionate days, And could not be so now, did such exist. But such respect, and mildly paid regard As a true feeling for your welfare, and free compliance with all honest wishes, -- kindness to your virtues, watchfulness Not shown, but shadowing o'er such little failings As Youth is apt in, so as not to check Rashly, but win you from them ere you knew You had been won, but thought the change your choice; pride not in your beauty, but your conduct; trust in you; a patriarchal love, And not a doting homage; friendship, faith, -- Such estimation in your eyes as these Might claim, I hoped for.
    </CONTENT>
  </SAMPLE>

  <SAMPLE>
    <AUTHOR>Shakespeare</AUTHOR>
    <CONTENT>
Beseech you, sir, be merry; you have cause, So have we all, of joy; for our escape Is much beyond our loss. Our hint of woe Is common; every day, some sailor's wife, The masters of some merchant, and the merchant, Have just our theme of woe; but for the miracle, mean our preservation, few in millions Can speak like us. Then wisely, good sir, weigh Our sorrow with our comfort. Prithee, peace. He receives comfort like cold porridge. The visitor will not give him o'er so. Look, he's winding up the watch of his wit; by and by it will strike. Sir- One-Tell. When every grief is entertain'd that's offer'd, Comes to th' entertainer- dollar. Dolour comes to him, indeed; you have spoken truer than you purpos'd. You have taken it wiselier than I meant you
    </CONTENT>
  </SAMPLE>

  <SAMPLE>
    <AUTHOR>Byron</AUTHOR>
    <CONTENT>
No; let him be reserved unto the last, Nor turn aside to strike at such a prey, Till nobler game is quarried: his offence Was a mere ebullition of the vice, The general corruption generated By the foul Aristocracy: he could not -- He dared not in more honourable days Have risked it. I have merged all private wrath Against him in the thought of our great purpose. slave insults me -- I require his punishment From his proud master's hands; if he refuse it, The offence grows his, and let him answer it.
    </CONTENT>
  </SAMPLE>

  <SAMPLE>
    <AUTHOR>Shakespeare</AUTHOR>
    <CONTENT>
At difference in thee. Out of that I'll work Myself a former fortune.  Ay, by and by; But we will drink together; and you shall bear better witness back than words, which we, On like conditions, will have counter-seal'd. Come, enter with us. Ladies, you deserve To have a temple built you. All the swords In Italy, and her confederate arms, Could not have made this peace. Exeunt
    </CONTENT>
  </SAMPLE>

  <SAMPLE>
    <AUTHOR>Shakespeare</AUTHOR>
    <CONTENT>
Beshrew that heart that makes my heart to groan For that deep wound it gives my friend and me; Is't not enough to torture me alone, But slave to slavery my sweet'st friend must be? Me from my self thy cruel eye hath taken, And my next self thou harder hast engrossed, Of him, my self, and thee I am forsaken, torment thrice three-fold thus to be crossed: Prison my heart in thy steel bosom's ward, But then my friend's heart let my poor heart bail, Whoe'er keeps me, let my heart be his guard, Thou canst not then use rigour in my gaol. And yet thou wilt, for I being pent in thee, Perforce am thine and all that is in me.
    </CONTENT>
  </SAMPLE>

  <SAMPLE>
    <AUTHOR>Shakespeare</AUTHOR>
    <CONTENT>
To cavil in the course of this contract. If once it be neglected, ten to one We shall not find like opportunity.  To say the truth, it is your policy To save your subjects from such massacre And ruthless slaughters as are daily seen By our proceeding in hostility; And therefore take this compact of a truce, Although you break it when your pleasure serves. How say'st thou, Charles? Shall our condition
    </CONTENT>
  </SAMPLE>

  <SAMPLE>
    <AUTHOR>Shakespeare</AUTHOR>
    <CONTENT>
This man, lady, hath robb'd many beasts of their particular additions: he is as valiant as a lion, churlish as the bear, slow as the elephant-a man into whom nature hath so crowded humours that his valour is crush'd into folly, his folly sauced with discretion. There is no man hath a virtue that he hath not a glimpse of, nor any man an attaint but he carries some stain of it; he is melancholy without cause and merry against the hair; he hath the joints of every thing; but everything so out of joint that he is a gouty Briareus, many hands and no use, or purblind Argus, all eyes and no sight. But how should this man, that makes me smile, make Hector
    </CONTENT>
  </SAMPLE>

  <SAMPLE>
    <AUTHOR>Byron</AUTHOR>
    <CONTENT>
Laura, when dressed, was (as I sang before) pretty woman as was ever seen, Fresh as the Angel o'er a new inn door, Or frontispiece of a new Magazine, With all the fashions which the last month wore, Coloured, and silver paper leaved between That and the title-page, for fear the Press Should soil with parts of speech the parts of dress.
    </CONTENT>
  </SAMPLE>

  <SAMPLE>
    <AUTHOR>Shakespeare</AUTHOR>
    <CONTENT>
Hail, King, for so thou art. Behold where stands The usurper's cursed head. The time is free. see thee compass'd with thy kingdom's pearl That speak my salutation in their minds, Whose voices I desire aloud with mine- Hail, King of Scotland! Hail, King of Scotland! Flourish. We shall not spend a large expense of time Before we reckon with your several loves And make us even with you. My Thanes and kinsmen, Henceforth be Earls, the first that ever Scotland In such an honor named. What's more to do, Which would be planted newly with the time, As calling home our exiled friends abroad That fled the snares of watchful tyranny, Producing forth the cruel ministers Of this dead butcher and his fiend-like queen, Who, as 'tis thought, by self and violent hands Took off her life; this, and what needful else That calls upon us, by the grace of Grace We will perform in measure, time, and place. So thanks to all at once and to each one, Whom we invite to see us crown'd at Scone. Flourish. Exeunt.
    </CONTENT>
  </SAMPLE>

  <SAMPLE>
    <AUTHOR>Byron</AUTHOR>
    <CONTENT>
It might be months, or years, or days -- kept no count, I took no note -- had no hope my eyes to raise, And clear them of their dreary mote; At last men came to set me free; asked not why, and recked not where; It was at length the same to me, Fettered or fetterless to be, learned to love despair. And thus when they appeared at last, And all my bonds aside were cast, These heavy walls to me had grown hermitage -- and all my own! My very chains and I grew friends, So much a long communion tends To make us what we are: -- even I Regained my freedom with a sigh.
    </CONTENT>
  </SAMPLE>

  <SAMPLE>
    <AUTHOR>Byron</AUTHOR>
    <CONTENT>
True, separations Ask more than patience; What desperations From such have risen! But yet remaining, What is't but chaining Hearts which, once waning, Beat 'gainst their prison? Time can but cloy love, And use destroy love: The wingd boy, Love, Is but for boys -- You'll find it torture Though sharper, shorter, To wean, and not wear out your joys.
    </CONTENT>
  </SAMPLE>

  <SAMPLE>
    <AUTHOR>Shakespeare</AUTHOR>
    <CONTENT>
What wouldst thou have, boor? What, thick-skin? Speak, breathe, discuss; brief, short, quick, snap. Marry, sir, I come to speak with Sir John Falstaff from Master Slender. There's his chamber, his house, his castle, his standing-bed and truckle-bed; 'tis painted about with the story of the Prodigal, fresh and new. Go, knock and can; he'll speak like an Anthropophaginian unto thee. Knock, I say. There's an old woman, a fat woman, gone up into his chamber; I'll be so bold as stay, sir, till she come down; come to speak with her, indeed. Ha! a fat woman? The knight may be robb'd. I'll call. Bully knight! Bully Sir John! Speak from thy lungs military. Art thou there? It is thine host, thine Ephesian, calls.  How now, mine host? Here's a Bohemian-Tartar tarries the coming down of thy fat woman. Let her descend, bully, let her descend; my chambers are honourible. Fie, privacy, fie!
    </CONTENT>
  </SAMPLE>

  <SAMPLE>
    <AUTHOR>Byron</AUTHOR>
    <CONTENT>
Doge (interrupting him). There is no such thing -- It is a word -- nay, worse -- a worthless by-word: The most despised, wronged, outraged, helpless wretch, Who begs his bread, if 'tis refused by one, May win it from another kinder heart; But he, who is denied his right by those Whose place it is to do no wrong, is poorer Than the rejected beggar -- he's a slave -- And that am I -- and thou -- and all our house, Even from this hour; the meanest artisan Will point the finger, and the haughty noble May spit upon us: -- where is our redress?
    </CONTENT>
  </SAMPLE>

  <SAMPLE>
    <AUTHOR>Shakespeare</AUTHOR>
    <CONTENT>
the Moor, general of the Venetian forces his wife ensign to Othello his wife, lady-in-waiting to Desdemona lieutenant to Othello Venetian Senator, father of Desdemona nobleman of Venice, brother of Brabantio nobleman of Venice, kinsman of Brabantio rejected suitor of Desdemona mistress of Cassio a Cypriot official Clown in service to Othello Senators, Sailors, Messengers, Officers, Gentlemen, Musicians, and
    </CONTENT>
  </SAMPLE>

  <SAMPLE>
    <AUTHOR>Shakespeare</AUTHOR>
    <CONTENT>
Good King, that must approve the common saw, Thou out of heaven's benediction com'st To the warm sun! Approach, thou beacon to this under globe, That by thy comfortable beams I may Peruse this letter. Nothing almost sees miracles But misery. I know 'tis from Cordelia, Who hath most fortunately been inform'd Of my obscured course- and  'shall find time From this enormous state, seeking to give Losses their remedies'- All weary and o'erwatch'd, Take vantage, heavy eyes, not to behold This shameful lodging. Fortune, good night; smile once more, turn thy wheel.
    </CONTENT>
  </SAMPLE>

  <SAMPLE>
    <AUTHOR>Shakespeare</AUTHOR>
    <CONTENT>
What noise? The town is empty; on the brow o' the sea Stand ranks of people, and they cry, "A sail!" My hopes do shape him for the governor. Guns heard. They do discharge their shot of courtesy- Our friends at least. pray you, sir, go forth, And give us truth who 'tis that is arrived. shall. Exit. But, good lieutenant, is your general wived? Most fortunately: he hath achieved a maid That paragons description and wild fame, One that excels the quirks of blazoning pens, And in the essential vesture of creation Does tire the ingener.
    </CONTENT>
  </SAMPLE>

  <SAMPLE>
    <AUTHOR>Byron</AUTHOR>
    <CONTENT>
My good Lord! crave a second grace for this approach; But yet let not my humble zeal offend By its abruptness -- all it hath of ill Recoils on me; its good in the effect May light upon your head -- could I say heart -- Could I touch that, with words or prayers, I should Recall a noble spirit which hath wandered, But is not yet all lost.
    </CONTENT>
  </SAMPLE>

  <SAMPLE>
    <AUTHOR>Byron</AUTHOR>
    <CONTENT>
"And here our doctors are of one accord, Coming on this point to the same conclusion, -- That in their thoughts, who praise in Heaven the Lord, If Pity e'er was guilty of intrusion For their unfortunate relations stored In Hell below, and damned in great confusion, Their happiness would be reduced to nought, -- And thus unjust the Almighty's self be thought.
    </CONTENT>
  </SAMPLE>

  <SAMPLE>
    <AUTHOR>Byron</AUTHOR>
    <CONTENT>
"He was -- if I remember -- King of France; That head of his, which could not keep a crown On earth, yet ventured in my face to advance claim to those of martyrs -- like my own: If I had had my sword, as I had once When I cut ears off, I had cut him down; But having but my keys, and not my brand, only knocked his head from out his hand.
    </CONTENT>
  </SAMPLE>

  <SAMPLE>
    <AUTHOR>Shakespeare</AUTHOR>
    <CONTENT>
Thy news? The citizens of Corioli have issued And given to Lartius and to Marcius battle; saw our party to their trenches driven, And then I came away. Though thou speak'st truth, Methinks thou speak'st not well. How long is't since? Above an hour, my lord. 'Tis not a mile; briefly we heard their drums. How couldst thou in a mile confound an hour, And bring thy news so late? Spies of the Volsces Held me in chase, that I was forc'd to wheel Three or four miles about; else had I, sir, Half an hour since brought my report.
    </CONTENT>
  </SAMPLE>

  <SAMPLE>
    <AUTHOR>Shakespeare</AUTHOR>
    <CONTENT>
I would your Grace would constrain me to tell. Pedro. I charge thee on thy allegiance. Bene. You hear, Count Claudio. I can be secret as a dumb man, I would have you think so; but, on my allegiance -- mark you this-on my allegiance! he is in love. With who? Now that is your Grace's part. Mark how short his answer is: With Hero, Leonato's short
    </CONTENT>
  </SAMPLE>

  <SAMPLE>
    <AUTHOR>Shakespeare</AUTHOR>
    <CONTENT>
Complain unto the Duke of this indignity. Come, go; I will fall prostrate at his feet, And never rise until my tears and prayers Have won his Grace to come in person hither And take perforce my husband from the Abbess. By this, I think, the dial points at five; Anon, I'm sure, the Duke himself in person Comes this way to the melancholy vale, The place of death and sorry execution, Behind the ditches of the abbey here. Upon what cause? To see a reverend Syracusian merchant, Who put unluckily into this bay Against the laws and statutes of this town, Beheaded publicly for his offence. See where they come; we will behold his death. Kneel to the Duke before he pass the abbey.
    </CONTENT>
  </SAMPLE>

  <SAMPLE>
    <AUTHOR>Byron</AUTHOR>
    <CONTENT>
And this is not a theologic tract, To prove with Hebrew and with Arabic, If Job be allegory or a fact, But a true narrative; and thus I pick From out the whole but such and such an act As sets aside the slightest thought of trick. 'Tis every tittle true, beyond suspicion, And accurate as any other vision.
    </CONTENT>
  </SAMPLE>

  <SAMPLE>
    <AUTHOR>Shakespeare</AUTHOR>
    <CONTENT>
Is't possible the spells of France should juggle Men into such strange mysteries? New customs, Though they be never so ridiculous, Nay, let 'em be unmanly, yet are follow'd. As far as I see, all the good our English Have got by the late voyage is but merely fit or two o' th' face; but they are shrewd ones; For when they hold 'em, you would swear directly Their very noses had been counsellors To Pepin or Clotharius, they keep state so. They have all new legs, and lame ones. One would take it, That never saw 'em pace before, the spavin Or springhalt reign'd among 'em. Death! my lord, Their clothes are after such a pagan cut to't, That sure th' have worn out Christendom.
    </CONTENT>
  </SAMPLE>

  <SAMPLE>
    <AUTHOR>Byron</AUTHOR>
    <CONTENT>
Strange rumours, but most true, if all I hear And see be sooth, have reached me, and I come To know the worst, even at the worst; forgive The abruptness of my entrance and my bearing. Is it -- I cannot speak -- I cannot shape The question -- but you answer it ere spoken, With eyes averted, and with gloomy brows -- Oh God! this is the silence of the grave!
    </CONTENT>
  </SAMPLE>

  <SAMPLE>
    <AUTHOR>Byron</AUTHOR>
    <CONTENT>
Titan! to whose immortal eyes The sufferings of mortality, Seen in their sad reality, Were not as things that gods despise; What was thy pity's recompense? silent suffering, and intense; The rock, the vulture, and the chain, All that the proud can feel of pain, The agony they do not show, The suffocating sense of woe, Which speaks but in its loneliness, And then is jealous lest the sky Should have a listener, nor will sigh Until its voice is echoless.
    </CONTENT>
  </SAMPLE>

  <SAMPLE>
    <AUTHOR>Byron</AUTHOR>
    <CONTENT>
And then he was a Count, and then he knew Music, and dancing, fiddling, French and Tuscan; The last not easy, be it known to you, For few Italians speak the right Etruscan. He was a critic upon operas, too, And knew all niceties of sock and buskin; And no Venetian audience could endure a Song, scene, or air, when he cried "seccatura!"
    </CONTENT>
  </SAMPLE>

  <SAMPLE>
    <AUTHOR>Shakespeare</AUTHOR>
    <CONTENT>
Are not the speedy scouts return'd again That dogg'd the mighty army of the Dauphin? They are return'd, my lord, and give it out That he is march'd to Bordeaux with his power To fight with Talbot; as he march'd along, By your espials were discovered Two mightier troops than that the Dauphin led, Which join'd with him and made their march for
    </CONTENT>
  </SAMPLE>

  <SAMPLE>
    <AUTHOR>Shakespeare</AUTHOR>
    <CONTENT>
Good boatswain, have care. Where's the master? Play the men. pray now, keep below. Where is the master, boson? Do you not hear him? You mar our labour; keep your cabins; you do assist the storm. Nay, good, be patient. When the sea is. Hence! What cares these roarers for the name of king? To cabin! silence! Trouble us not. Good, yet remember whom thou hast aboard. None that I more love than myself. You are counsellor; if you can command these elements to silence, and work the peace of the present, we will not hand a rope more. Use your authority; if you cannot, give thanks you have liv'd so long, and make yourself ready in your cabin for the mischance of the hour, if it so hap.-Cheerly, good hearts!-Out of our way, I say.
    </CONTENT>
  </SAMPLE>

  <SAMPLE>
    <AUTHOR>Shakespeare</AUTHOR>
    <CONTENT>
My lord, your nobles, jealous of your absence, Seek through your camp to find you. Good old knight, Collect them all together at my tent: I'll be before thee. shall do't, my lord. Exit God of battles, steel my soldiers' hearts, Possess them not with fear! Take from them now The sense of reck'ning, if th' opposed numbers Pluck their hearts from them! Not to-day, O Lord, not to-day, think not upon the fault My father made in compassing the crown! Richard's body have interred new, And on it have bestowed more contrite tears Than from it issued forced drops of blood; Five hundred poor I have in yearly pay, Who twice a day their wither'd hands hold up Toward heaven, to pardon blood; and I have built Two chantries, where the sad and solemn priests Sing still for Richard's soul. More will I do; Though all that I can do is nothing worth, Since that my penitence comes after all, Imploring pardon.
    </CONTENT>
  </SAMPLE>

  <SAMPLE>
    <AUTHOR>Shakespeare</AUTHOR>
    <CONTENT>
No, I'll come no more i' th' basket. May I not go out ere he come? Alas, three of Master Ford's brothers watch the door with pistols, that none shall issue out; otherwise you might slip away ere he came. But what make you here? What shall I do? I'll creep up into the chimney. There they always use to discharge their
    </CONTENT>
  </SAMPLE>

  <SAMPLE>
    <AUTHOR>Byron</AUTHOR>
    <CONTENT>
The Angel answered, "Peter! do not pout: The King who comes has head and all entire, And never knew much what it was about -- He did as doth the puppet -- by its wire, And will be judged like all the rest, no doubt: My business and your own is not to inquire Into such matters, but to mind our cue -- Which is to act as we are bid to do."
    </CONTENT>
  </SAMPLE>

  <SAMPLE>
    <AUTHOR>Shakespeare</AUTHOR>
    <CONTENT>
He is full of harmony. Truly, lady, no. sir- Rude, in sooth; in good sooth, very rude. Well said, my lord. Well, you say so in fits. have business to my lord, dear queen. My lord, will you vouchsafe me a word? Nay, this shall not hedge us out. We'll hear you sing,
    </CONTENT>
  </SAMPLE>

  <SAMPLE>
    <AUTHOR>Byron</AUTHOR>
    <CONTENT>
Our Laura's Turk still kept his eyes upon her, Less in the Mussulman than Christian way, Which seems to say, "Madam, I do you honour, And while I please to stare, you'll please to stay." Could staring win a woman, this had won her, But Laura could not thus be led astray; She had stood fire too long and well, to boggle Even at this Stranger's most outlandish ogle.
    </CONTENT>
  </SAMPLE>

  <SAMPLE>
    <AUTHOR>Byron</AUTHOR>
    <CONTENT>
I think so. For the difference in our years You knew it choosing me, and chose; I trusted Not to my qualities, nor would have faith In such, nor outward ornaments of nature, Were I still in my five and twentieth spring; trusted to the blood of Loredano Pure in your veins; I trusted to the soul God gave you -- to the truths your father taught you -- To your belief in Heaven -- to your mild virtues -- To your own faith and honour, for my own.
    </CONTENT>
  </SAMPLE>

  <SAMPLE>
    <AUTHOR>Shakespeare</AUTHOR>
    <CONTENT>
how I faint when I of you do write, Knowing a better spirit doth use your name, And in the praise thereof spends all his might, To make me tongue-tied speaking of your fame. But since your worth (wide as the ocean is) The humble as the proudest sail doth bear, My saucy bark (inferior far to his) On your broad main doth wilfully appear. Your shallowest help will hold me up afloat, Whilst he upon your soundless deep doth ride, Or (being wrecked) I am a worthless boat, He of tall building, and of goodly pride. Then if he thrive and I be cast away, The worst was this, my love was my decay.
    </CONTENT>
  </SAMPLE>

  <SAMPLE>
    <AUTHOR>Shakespeare</AUTHOR>
    <CONTENT>
Where's the Prince Dauphin? I have news for him. Bastard of Orleans, thrice welcome to us. Methinks your looks are sad, your cheer appall'd. Hath the late overthrow wrought this offence? Be not dismay'd, for succour is at hand. holy maid hither with me I bring, Which, by a vision sent to her from heaven, Ordained is to raise this tedious siege And drive the English forth the bounds of France. The spirit of deep prophecy she hath, Exceeding the nine sibyls of old Rome: What's past and what's to come she can descry. Speak, shall I call her in? Believe my words, For they are certain and unfallible. Go, call her in.  But first, to try her skill, Reignier, stand thou as Dauphin in my place; Question her proudly; let thy looks be stern; By this means shall we sound what skill she hath.
    </CONTENT>
  </SAMPLE>

  <SAMPLE>
    <AUTHOR>Shakespeare</AUTHOR>
    <CONTENT>
shall drive you then to confess the wilful abuse, and then I know how to handle you. No abuse, Hal, o' mine honour; no abuse. Not- to dispraise me, and call me pander, and bread-chipper, and I know not what! No abuse, Hal. No abuse! No abuse, Ned, i' th' world; honest Ned, none. I disprais'd him before the wicked- that the wicked might not fall in love with thee; in which doing, I have done the part of a careful friend and a true subject; and thy father is to give me thanks for it. No abuse, Hal; none, Ned, none; no, faith, boys,
    </CONTENT>
  </SAMPLE>

  <SAMPLE>
    <AUTHOR>Shakespeare</AUTHOR>
    <CONTENT>
Why dost thou use me thus? I know thee not. Kent. Fellow, I know thee. Osw. What dost thou know me for? Kent. A knave; a rascal; an eater of broken meats; a base, proud, shallow, beggarly, three-suited, hundred-pound, filthy, worsted-stocking knave; a lily-liver'd, action-taking, whoreson, glass-gazing, superserviceable, finical rogue; one-trunk-inheriting slave; one that wouldst be a bawd in way of good service, and art nothing but the composition of a knave, beggar, coward, pander, and the son and heir of a mongrel bitch; one whom I will beat into clamorous whining, if thou deny the least syllable of thy addition. Osw. Why, what a monstrous fellow art thou, thus to rail on one that's neither known of thee nor knows thee! Kent. What a brazen-fac'd varlet art thou, to deny thou knowest me! Is it two days ago since I beat thee and tripp'd up thy heels before the King?  Draw, you rogue! for, though it be night, yet the moon shines. I'll make a sop o' th' moonshine o' you. Draw, you whoreson cullionly barbermonger!
    </CONTENT>
  </SAMPLE>

  <SAMPLE>
    <AUTHOR>Shakespeare</AUTHOR>
    <CONTENT>
My lord, our army is dispers'd already. Like youthful steers unyok'd, they take their courses East, west, north, south; or like a school broke up, Each hurries toward his home and sporting-place. Good tidings, my Lord Hastings; for the which do arrest thee, traitor, of high treason; And you, Lord Archbishop, and you, Lord Mowbray, Of capital treason I attach you both. Is this proceeding just and honourable? Is your assembly so? Will you thus break your faith? pawn'd thee none: promis'd you redress of these same grievances Whereof you did complain; which, by mine honour, will perform with a most Christian care. But for you, rebels- look to taste the due Meet for rebellion and such acts as yours. Most shallowly did you these arms commence, Fondly brought here, and foolishly sent hence. Strike up our drums, pursue the scatt'red stray. God, and not we, hath safely fought to-day. Some guard these traitors to the block of death, Treason's true bed and yielder-up of breath. Exeunt
    </CONTENT>
  </SAMPLE>

  <SAMPLE>
    <AUTHOR>Byron</AUTHOR>
    <CONTENT>
I've a card, and shall go: but at present, as soon As friend Scamp shall be pleased to step down from the moon, (Where he seems to be soaring in search of his wits), And an interval grants from his lecturing fits, I'm engaged to the Lady Bluebottle's collation, To partake of a luncheon and learn'd conversation: 'Tis a sort of reunion for Scamp, on the days Of his lecture, to treat him with cold tongue and praise. And I own, for my own part, that 'tis not unpleasant. Will you go? There's Miss Lilac will also be present.
    </CONTENT>
  </SAMPLE>

  <SAMPLE>
    <AUTHOR>Shakespeare</AUTHOR>
    <CONTENT>
Another king? They grow like Hydra's heads. am the Douglas, fatal to all those That wear those colours on them. What art thou That counterfeit'st the person of a king? King. The King himself, who, Douglas, grieves at heart So many of his shadows thou hast met, And not the very King. I have two boys Seek Percy and thyself about the field; But, seeing thou fall'st on me so luckily, will assay thee. So defend thyself. Doug. I fear thou art another counterfeit; And yet, in faith, thou bearest thee like a king. But mine I am sure thou art, whoe'er thou be, And thus I win thee.
    </CONTENT>
  </SAMPLE>

  <SAMPLE>
    <AUTHOR>Byron</AUTHOR>
    <CONTENT>
did remind thee of our own dear Lake, By the old Hall which may be mine no more. Leman's is fair; but think not I forsake The sweet remembrance of a dearer shore: Sad havoc Time must with my memory make, Ere that or thou can fade these eyes before; Though, like all things which I have loved, they are Resigned for ever, or divided far.
    </CONTENT>
  </SAMPLE>

  <SAMPLE>
    <AUTHOR>Shakespeare</AUTHOR>
    <CONTENT>
Good time of day unto my gracious lord! As much unto my good Lord Chamberlain! Well are you welcome to the open air. How hath your lordship brook'd imprisonment? With patience, noble lord, as prisoners must; But I shall live, my lord, to give them thanks That were the cause of my imprisonment. No doubt, no doubt; and so shall Clarence too; For they that were your enemies are his, And have prevail'd as much on him as you. More pity that the eagles should be mew'd Whiles kites and buzzards prey at liberty. What news abroad? No news so bad abroad as this at home: The King is sickly, weak, and melancholy, And his physicians fear him mightily. Now, by Saint John, that news is bad indeed. he hath kept an evil diet long And overmuch consum'd his royal person! 'Tis very grievous to be thought upon. Where is he? In his bed? He is. Go you before, and I will follow you.
    </CONTENT>
  </SAMPLE>

  <SAMPLE>
    <AUTHOR>Byron</AUTHOR>
    <CONTENT>
She rules the present, past, and all to be yet, She gives us luck in lotteries, love, and marriage; cannot say that she's done much for me yet; Not that I mean her bounties to disparage, We've not yet closed accounts, and we shall see yet How much she'll make amends for past miscarriage; Meantime the Goddess I'll no more importune, Unless to thank her when she's made my fortune.
    </CONTENT>
  </SAMPLE>

  <SAMPLE>
    <AUTHOR>Byron</AUTHOR>
    <CONTENT>
"He came to his sceptre young; he leaves it old: Look to the state in which he found his realm, And left it; and his annals too behold, How to a minion first he gave the helm; How grew upon his heart a thirst for gold, The beggar's vice, which can but overwhelm The meanest hearts; and for the rest, but glance Thine eye along America and France.
    </CONTENT>
  </SAMPLE>

  <SAMPLE>
    <AUTHOR>Byron</AUTHOR>
    <CONTENT>
No solemn, antique gentleman of rhyme, Who having angled all his life for Fame, And getting but a nibble at a time, Still fussily keeps fishing on, the same Small "Triton of the minnows," the sublime Of Mediocrity, the furious tame, The Echo's echo, usher of the school Of female wits, boy bards -- in short, a fool!
    </CONTENT>
  </SAMPLE>

  <SAMPLE>
    <AUTHOR>Shakespeare</AUTHOR>
    <CONTENT>
'Inprimis: She can milk.' Ay, that she can. 'Item: She brews good ale.' And thereof comes the proverb: Blessing of your heart, you brew good ale. 'Item: She can sew.' That's as much as to say 'Can she so?' 'Item: She can knit.' What need a man care for a stock with a wench, when she can knit him a stock. 'Item: She can wash and scour.' special virtue; for then she need not be wash'd and
    </CONTENT>
  </SAMPLE>

  <SAMPLE>
    <AUTHOR>Shakespeare</AUTHOR>
    <CONTENT>
Come on, my lords, the better foot before; Straight will I bring you to the loathsome pit Where I espied the panther fast asleep. My sight is very dull, whate'er it bodes. And mine, I promise you; were it not for shame, Well could I leave our sport to sleep awhile.
    </CONTENT>
  </SAMPLE>

  <SAMPLE>
    <AUTHOR>Byron</AUTHOR>
    <CONTENT>
My hair is grey, but not with years, Nor grew it white In a single night, One in fire, and two in field, Their belief with blood have sealed, Dying as their father died, For the God their foes denied; -- Three were in a dungeon cast, Of whom this wreck is left the last.
    </CONTENT>
  </SAMPLE>

  <SAMPLE>
    <AUTHOR>Shakespeare</AUTHOR>
    <CONTENT>
An't please your lordship, I hear his Majesty is return'd with some discomfort from Wales. talk not of his Majesty. You would not come when I sent for you. And I hear, moreover, his Highness is fall'n into this same whoreson apoplexy. Well God mend him! I pray you let me speak with you. This apoplexy, as I take it, is a kind of lethargy, an't please your lordship, a kind of sleeping in the blood, a whoreson
    </CONTENT>
  </SAMPLE>

  <SAMPLE>
    <AUTHOR>Byron</AUTHOR>
    <CONTENT>
And hurled a fragment of a size so large That if it had in fact fulfilled its mission, And Roland not availed him of his targe, There would have been no need of a physician. Orlando set himself in turn to charge, And in his bulky bosom made incision With all his sword. The lout fell; but o'erthrown, he However by no means forgot Macone.
    </CONTENT>
  </SAMPLE>

  <SAMPLE>
    <AUTHOR>Byron</AUTHOR>
    <CONTENT>
Think'st thou existence doth depend on time? It doth; but actions are our epochs: mine Have made my days and nights imperishable, Endless, and all alike, as sands on the shore, Innumerable atoms; and one desert, Barren and cold, on which the wild waves break, But nothing rests, save carcasses and wrecks, Rocks, and the salt-surf weeds of bitterness.
    </CONTENT>
  </SAMPLE>

  <SAMPLE>
    <AUTHOR>Byron</AUTHOR>
    <CONTENT>
Strike! -- If I dreaded death, a death more fearful Than any your rash weapons can inflict, should not now be here: Oh, noble Courage! The eldest born of Fear, which makes you brave Against this solitary hoary head! See the bold chiefs, who would reform a state And shake down senates, mad with wrath and dread At sight of one patrician! Butcher me! You can, I care not. -- Israel, are these men The mighty hearts you spoke of? look upon them!
    </CONTENT>
  </SAMPLE>

  <SAMPLE>
    <AUTHOR>Shakespeare</AUTHOR>
    <CONTENT>
Do you hear, my lord? Do you hear? What now? Here's a letter come from yond poor girl. Let me read. whoreson tisick, a whoreson rascally tisick so troubles me, and the foolish fortune of this girl, and what one thing, what another, that I shall leave you one o' th's days; and I have a rheum in mine eyes too, and such an ache in my bones that unless a man were curs'd I cannot tell what to think on't. What says she there? Words, words, mere words, no matter from the heart; Th' effect doth operate another way.  Go, wind, to wind, there turn and change together. My love with words and errors still she feeds, But edifies another with her deeds. Exeunt severally
    </CONTENT>
  </SAMPLE>

  <SAMPLE>
    <AUTHOR>Shakespeare</AUTHOR>
    <CONTENT>
No! Time, thou shalt not boast that I do change, Thy pyramids built up with newer might To me are nothing novel, nothing strange, They are but dressings Of a former sight: Our dates are brief, and therefore we admire, What thou dost foist upon us that is old, And rather make them born to our desire, Than think that we before have heard them told: Thy registers and thee I both defy, Not wond'ring at the present, nor the past, For thy records, and what we see doth lie, Made more or less by thy continual haste: This I do vow and this shall ever be, will be true despite thy scythe and thee.
    </CONTENT>
  </SAMPLE>

  <SAMPLE>
    <AUTHOR>Byron</AUTHOR>
    <CONTENT>
The Angels all were singing out of tune, And hoarse with having little else to do, Excepting to wind up the sun and moon, Or curb a runaway young star or two, Or wild colt of a comet, which too soon Broke out of bounds o'er the ethereal blue, Splitting some planet with its playful tail, As boats are sometimes by a wanton whale.
    </CONTENT>
  </SAMPLE>

  <SAMPLE>
    <AUTHOR>Shakespeare</AUTHOR>
    <CONTENT>
Under this thick-grown brake we'll shroud ourselves, For through this laund anon the deer will come; And in this covert will we make our stand, Culling the principal of all the deer. I'll stay above the hill, so both may shoot. That cannot be; the noise of thy cross-bow Will scare the herd, and so my shoot is lost. Here stand we both, and aim we at the best; And, for the time shall not seem tedious, I'll tell thee what befell me on a day In this self-place where now we mean to stand. Here comes a man; let's stay till he be past.
    </CONTENT>
  </SAMPLE>

  <SAMPLE>
    <AUTHOR>Byron</AUTHOR>
    <CONTENT>
When Rome's sixth Emperor From senates once his slaves, a certain soldier, With show of loyal pity, would have stanched The gushing throat with his officious robe; The dying Roman thrust him back, and said -- Some empire still in his expiring glance -- "It is too late -- is this fidelity?"
    </CONTENT>
  </SAMPLE>

  <SAMPLE>
    <AUTHOR>Shakespeare</AUTHOR>
    <CONTENT>
know his gait; 'tis he. Villain, thou diest! Makes a pass at Cassio. That thrust had been mine enemy indeed, But that my coat is better than thou know'st; will make proof of thine. Draws, and wounds Roderigo. am slain! Iago from behind wounds Cassio in the leg, and exit. am maim'd forever. Help, ho! Murther! Murther!
    </CONTENT>
  </SAMPLE>

  <SAMPLE>
    <AUTHOR>Byron</AUTHOR>
    <CONTENT>
Such blows Must be struck suddenly or never. When had o'ermastered the weak false remorse Which yearned about my heart, too fondly yielding moment to the feelings of old days, was most fain to strike; and, firstly, that might not yield again to such emotions; And, secondly, because of all these men, Save Israel and Philip Calendaro, know not well the courage or the faith: To-day might find 'mongst them a traitor to us, As yesterday a thousand to the Senate; But once in, with their hilts hot in their hands, They must on for their own sakes; one stroke struck, And the mere instinct of the first-born Cain, Which ever lurks somewhere in human hearts, Though Circumstance may keep it in abeyance, Will urge the rest on like to wolves; the sight Of blood to crowds begets the thirst of more, As the first wine-cup leads to the long revel; And you will find a harder task to quell Than urge them when they have commenced, but till That moment, a mere voice, a straw, a shadow, Are capable of turning them aside. -- How goes the night?
    </CONTENT>
  </SAMPLE>

  <SAMPLE>
    <AUTHOR>Shakespeare</AUTHOR>
    <CONTENT>
Mistress! what, mistress! Juliet! Fast, I warrant her, she. Why, lamb! why, lady! Fie, you slug-abed! Why, love, I say! madam! sweetheart! Why, bride! What, not a word? You take your pennyworths now! Sleep for a week; for the next night, I warrant, The County Paris hath set up his rest That you shall rest but little. God forgive me! Marry, and amen. How sound is she asleep! needs must wake her. Madam, madam, madam! Ay, let the County take you in your bed! He'll fright you up, i' faith. Will it not be?  What, dress'd, and in your clothes, and down again? must needs wake you. Lady! lady! lady! Alas, alas! Help, help! My lady's dead! weraday that ever I was born! Some aqua-vitae, ho! My lord! my lady!
    </CONTENT>
  </SAMPLE>

  <SAMPLE>
    <AUTHOR>Shakespeare</AUTHOR>
    <CONTENT>
Tell me precisely of what complexion. Of the sea-water green, sir. Is that one of the four complexions? As I have read, sir; and the best of them too. Green, indeed, is the colour of lovers; but to have a love of that colour, methinks Samson had small reason for it. He surely affected her for her wit. It was so, sir; for she had a green wit. My love is most immaculate white and red. Most maculate thoughts, master, are mask'd under such
    </CONTENT>
  </SAMPLE>

  <SAMPLE>
    <AUTHOR>Byron</AUTHOR>
    <CONTENT>
You should know Who hear me, who and what I am; a man Roused like yourselves to overthrow oppression; kind man, I am apt to think, as some Of you have found me; and if brave or no, You, Calendaro, can pronounce, who have seen me Put to the proof; or, if you should have doubts, I'll clear them on your person!
    </CONTENT>
  </SAMPLE>

  <SAMPLE>
    <AUTHOR>Byron</AUTHOR>
    <CONTENT>
F. (taking up and placing the ducal bonnet on the table). Ere I depart, pray you to resume what you have spurned, Till you can change it -- haply, for a crown! And now I take my leave, imploring you In all things to rely upon my duty, As doth become your near and faithful kinsman, And not less loyal citizen and subject.
    </CONTENT>
  </SAMPLE>

  <SAMPLE>
    <AUTHOR>Byron</AUTHOR>
    <CONTENT>
Of these same we see several, and of others. Men of the world, who know the World like Men, Scott, Rogers, Moore, and all the better brothers, Who think of something else besides the pen; But for the children of the "Mighty Mother's," The would-be wits, and can't-be gentlemen, leave them to their daily "tea is ready," Smug coterie, and literary lady.
    </CONTENT>
  </SAMPLE>

  <SAMPLE>
    <AUTHOR>Byron</AUTHOR>
    <CONTENT>
With all its sinful doings, I must say, That Italy's a pleasant place to me, Who love to see the Sun shine every day, And vines (not nailed to walls) from tree to tree Festooned, much like the back scene of a play, Or melodrame, which people flock to see, When the first act is ended by a dance In vineyards copied from the South of France.
    </CONTENT>
  </SAMPLE>

  <SAMPLE>
    <AUTHOR>Byron</AUTHOR>
    <CONTENT>
I have risked no man's life except my own -- Of that be certain: he is one who may Make our assurance doubly sure, according His aid; and if reluctant, he no less Is in our power: he comes alone with me, And cannot 'scape us; but he will not swerve.
    </CONTENT>
  </SAMPLE>

  <SAMPLE>
    <AUTHOR>Byron</AUTHOR>
    <CONTENT>
In the blue depth of the waters, Where the wave hath no strife, Where the Wind is a stranger, And the Sea-snake hath life, Where the Mermaid is decking Her green hair with shells, Like the storm on the surface Came the sound of thy spells; O'er my calm Hall of Coral The deep Echo rolled -- To the Spirit of Ocean Thy wishes unfold!
    </CONTENT>
  </SAMPLE>

  <SAMPLE>
    <AUTHOR>Shakespeare</AUTHOR>
    <CONTENT>
mean in singing; but in loving Leander the good swimmer, Troilus the first employer of panders, and a whole book full of these quondam carpet-mongers, whose names yet run smoothly in the even road of a blank verse -- why, they were never so truly turn'd over and over as my poor self in love. Marry, I cannot show it in rhyme. I have tried. I can find out no rhyme to 'lady' but 'baby' -- an innocent rhyme; for 'scorn,' 'horn' -- a hard rhyme; for 'school', 'fool' -- a babbling rhyme: very ominous endings! No, I was not born under a rhyming planet, nor cannot woo in festival
    </CONTENT>
  </SAMPLE>

  <SAMPLE>
    <AUTHOR>Byron</AUTHOR>
    <CONTENT>
His wife received, the Patriarch re-baptised him, (He made the Church a present, by the way;) He then threw off the garments which disguised him, And borrowed the Count's smallclothes for a day: His friends the more for his long absence prized him, Finding he'd wherewithal to make them gay, With dinners, where he oft became the laugh of them, For stories -- but I don't believe the half of them.
    </CONTENT>
  </SAMPLE>

  <SAMPLE>
    <AUTHOR>Shakespeare</AUTHOR>
    <CONTENT>
Your friends at Pomfret, they do need the priest: Your honour hath no shriving work in hand. Good faith, and when I met this holy man, The men you talk of came into my mind. What, go you toward the Tower? do, my lord, but long I cannot stay there; shall return before your lordship thence. Nay, like enough, for I stay dinner there.  And supper too, although thou knowest it not.- Come, will you go? I'll wait upon your lordship. Exeunt
    </CONTENT>
  </SAMPLE>

  <SAMPLE>
    <AUTHOR>Shakespeare</AUTHOR>
    <CONTENT>
What's your name, sir? Of what condition are you, and of what place, I pray? am a knight sir; and my name is Colville of the Dale. Well then, Colville is your name, a knight is your degree, and your place the Dale. Colville shall still be your name, a traitor your degree, and the dungeon your place- a place deep enough; so shall you be still Colville of the Dale. Are not you Sir John Falstaff? As good a man as he, sir, whoe'er I am. Do you yield, sir, or shall I sweat for you? If I do sweat, they are the drops of thy lovers, and they weep for thy death; therefore rouse up fear and trembling, and do observance to my mercy. think you are Sir John Falstaff, and in that thought yield me. have a whole school of tongues in this belly of mine; and not a tongue of them all speaks any other word but my name. An I had but a belly of any indifferency, I were simply the most active fellow in Europe. My womb, my womb, my womb undoes me. Here comes our general.
    </CONTENT>
  </SAMPLE>

  <SAMPLE>
    <AUTHOR>Byron</AUTHOR>
    <CONTENT>
Now when the Abbot Count Orlando heard, His heart grew soft with inner tenderness, Such fervour in his bosom bred each word; And, "Cavalier," he said, "if I have less Courteous and kind to your great worth appeared, Than fits me for such gentle blood to express, know I have done too little in this case; But blame our ignorance, and this poor place.
    </CONTENT>
  </SAMPLE>

  <SAMPLE>
    <AUTHOR>Byron</AUTHOR>
    <CONTENT>
But there are in Death. tell thee, man, there is a spirit in Such things that acts and sees, unseen, though felt; And, if there be a spell to stir the dead, 'Tis in such deeds as we are now upon. Deem'st thou the souls of such a race as mine Can rest, when he, their last descendant Chief, Stands plotting on the brink of their pure graves With stung plebeians?
    </CONTENT>
  </SAMPLE>

  <SAMPLE>
    <AUTHOR>Byron</AUTHOR>
    <CONTENT>
"Our ancient fathers, living the desert in, For just and holy works were duly fed; Think not they lived on locusts sole, 'tis certain That manna was rained down from heaven instead; But here 'tis fit we keep on the alert in Our bounds, or taste the stones showered down for bread, From off yon mountain daily raining faster, And flung by Passamont and Alabaster.
    </CONTENT>
  </SAMPLE>

  <SAMPLE>
    <AUTHOR>Byron</AUTHOR>
    <CONTENT>
We have them in the toil -- it cannot fail! Now thou'rt indeed a Sovereign, and wilt make name immortal greater than the greatest: Free citizens have struck at Kings ere now; Csars have fallen, and even patrician hands Have crushed dictators, as the popular steel Has reached patricians: but, until this hour, What Prince has plotted for his people's freedom? Or risked a life to liberate his subjects? For ever, and for ever, they conspire Against the people, to abuse their hands To chains, but laid aside to carry weapons Against the fellow nations, so that yoke On yoke, and slavery and death may whet, Not glut, the never-gorged Leviathan! Now, my Lord, to our enterprise; -- 'tis great, And greater the reward; why stand you rapt? moment back, and you were all impatience!
    </CONTENT>
  </SAMPLE>

  <SAMPLE>
    <AUTHOR>Byron</AUTHOR>
    <CONTENT>
Even so. My object is to make your cause end well, And not to push myself to power. Experience, Some skill, and your own choice, had marked me out To act in trust as your commander, till Some worthier should appear: if I have found such As you yourselves shall own more worthy, think you That I would hesitate from selfishness, And, covetous of brief authority, Stake our deep interest on my single thoughts, Rather than yield to one above me in All leading qualities? No, Calendaro, Know your friend better; but you all shall judge. Away! and let us meet at the fixed hour. Be vigilant, and all will yet go well.
    </CONTENT>
  </SAMPLE>

  <SAMPLE>
    <AUTHOR>Shakespeare</AUTHOR>
    <CONTENT>
Knock off his manacles; bring your prisoner to the King. Thou bring'st good news: I am call'd to be made free. I'll be hang'd then. Thou shalt be then freer than a gaoler; no bolts for the dead. Exeunt POSTHUMUS and MESSENGER Unless a man would marry a gallows and beget young gibbets, never saw one so prone. Yet, on my conscience, there are verier knaves desire to live, for all he be a Roman; and there be some of them too that die against their wills; so should I, if I were one. I would we were all of one mind, and one mind good. O, there were desolation of gaolers and gallowses! I speak against my present profit, but my wish hath a preferment in't. Exit
    </CONTENT>
  </SAMPLE>

  <SAMPLE>
    <AUTHOR>Shakespeare</AUTHOR>
    <CONTENT>
My lord, there are certain nobles of the Senate newly alighted and come to visit you. They are fairly welcome. Exit SERVANT beseech your honour, vouchsafe me a word; it does concern you near. Near! Why then, another time I'll hear thee. I prithee let's be provided to show them entertainment.  I scarce know how.
    </CONTENT>
  </SAMPLE>

  <SAMPLE>
    <AUTHOR>Shakespeare</AUTHOR>
    <CONTENT>
Can you inquire him out and be edified by report? will catechize the world for him; that is, make questions and by them answer. Seek him, bid him come hither. Tell him I have moved my lord on his behalf and hope all will be well. To do this is within the compass of man's wit, and therefore will attempt the doing it. Exit. Where should I lose that handkerchief, Emilia? know not, madam. Believe me, I had rather have lost my purse Full of crusadoes; and, but my noble Moor Is true of mind and made of no such baseness As jealous creatures are, it were enough To put him to ill thinking. Is he not jealous? Who, he? I think the sun where he was born Drew all such humors from him. Look, where he comes. will not leave him now till Cassio Be call'd to him.
    </CONTENT>
  </SAMPLE>

  <SAMPLE>
    <AUTHOR>Shakespeare</AUTHOR>
    <CONTENT>
Sound drums and trumpets, and then enter MARTIUS and MUTIUS, two of TITUS' sons; and then two men bearing a coffin covered with black; then LUCIUS and QUINTUS, two other sons; then TITUS ANDRONICUS; and then TAMORA the Queen of Goths, with her three sons, ALARBUS, DEMETRIUS, and CHIRON, with AARON the Moor, and others, as many as can be. Then set down the coffin and TITUS speaks
    </CONTENT>
  </SAMPLE>

  <SAMPLE>
    <AUTHOR>Shakespeare</AUTHOR>
    <CONTENT>
This is the man. Avoid, and leave him. Exit GUARDSMAN Hast thou the pretty worm of Nilus there That kills and pains not? Truly, I have him. But I would not be the party that should desire you to touch him, for his biting is immortal; those that do die of it do seldom or never recover. Remember'st thou any that have died on't? Very many, men and women too. I heard of one of them no longer than yesterday: a very honest woman, but something given to lie, as a woman should not do but in the way of honesty; how she died of the biting of it, what pain she felt- truly she makes a very good report o' th' worm. But he that will believe all that they say shall never be saved by half that they do. But this is most falliable, the worm's an odd worm. Get thee hence; farewell. wish you all joy of the worm.  Farewell. You must think this, look you, that the worm will do his
    </CONTENT>
  </SAMPLE>

  <SAMPLE>
    <AUTHOR>Shakespeare</AUTHOR>
    <CONTENT>
Hang there, my verse, in witness of my love; And thou, thrice-crowned Queen of Night, survey With thy chaste eye, from thy pale sphere above, Thy huntress' name that my full life doth sway. Rosalind! these trees shall be my books, And in their barks my thoughts I'll character, That every eye which in this forest looks Shall see thy virtue witness'd every where. Run, run, Orlando; carve on every tree, The fair, the chaste, and unexpressive she. Exit
    </CONTENT>
  </SAMPLE>

  <SAMPLE>
    <AUTHOR>Byron</AUTHOR>
    <CONTENT>
"Take care he don't revenge himself, though dead, As Nessus did of old beyond all cure. don't know if the fact you've heard or read; But he will make you burst, you may be sure." "But help him on my back," Morgante said, "And you shall see what weight I can endure. In place, my gentle Roland, of this palfrey, With all the bells, I'd carry yonder belfry."
    </CONTENT>
  </SAMPLE>

  <SAMPLE>
    <AUTHOR>Shakespeare</AUTHOR>
    <CONTENT>
But soft! behold! Lo, where it comes again! I'll cross it, though it blast me.- Stay illusion! Spreads his arms. If thou hast any sound, or use of voice, Speak to me. If there be any good thing to be done, That may to thee do ease, and, race to me, Speak to me. If thou art privy to thy country's fate, Which happily foreknowing may avoid, speak! Or if thou hast uphoarded in thy life Extorted treasure in the womb of earth (For which, they say, you spirits oft walk in death), The cock crows. Speak of it! Stay, and speak!- Stop it, Marcellus! Mar. Shall I strike at it with my partisan? Hor. Do, if it will not stand. Ber. 'Tis here! Hor. 'Tis here! Mar. 'Tis gone!
    </CONTENT>
  </SAMPLE>

  <SAMPLE>
    <AUTHOR>Byron</AUTHOR>
    <CONTENT>
Nor now, nor ever; whatsoe'er betide, would have saved you: when to Manhood's growth We sprung, and you, devoted to the state, As suits your station, the more humble Bertram Was left unto the labours of the humble, Still you forsook me not; and if my fortunes Have not been towering, 'twas no fault of him Who ofttimes rescued and supported me, When struggling with the tides of Circumstance, Which bear away the weaker: noble blood Ne'er mantled in a nobler heart than thine Has proved to me, the poor plebeian Bertram. Would that thy fellow Senators were like thee!
    </CONTENT>
  </SAMPLE>

  <SAMPLE>
    <AUTHOR>Shakespeare</AUTHOR>
    <CONTENT>
Thou art as tyrannous, so as thou art, As those whose beauties proudly make them cruel; For well thou know'st to my dear doting heart Thou art the fairest and most precious jewel. Yet in good faith some say that thee behold, Thy face hath not the power to make love groan; To say they err, I dare not be so bold, Although I swear it to my self alone. And to be sure that is not false I swear, thousand groans but thinking on thy face, One on another's neck do witness bear Thy black is fairest in my judgment's place. In nothing art thou black save in thy deeds, And thence this slander as I think proceeds.
    </CONTENT>
  </SAMPLE>

  <SAMPLE>
    <AUTHOR>Byron</AUTHOR>
    <CONTENT>
come to preach to you, as to your brothers, -- Sent by the miserable monks -- repentance; For Providence divine, in you and others, Condemns the evil done, my new acquaintance! 'Tis writ on high -- your wrong must pay another's: From Heaven itself is issued out this sentence. Know then, that colder now than a pilaster left your Passamont and Alabaster."
    </CONTENT>
  </SAMPLE>

  <SAMPLE>
    <AUTHOR>Byron</AUTHOR>
    <CONTENT>
Yet this existed long before, and never Till in these late days did I see you thus. Forgive me; there is something at your heart More than the mere discharge of public duties, Which long use and a talent like to yours Have rendered light, nay, a necessity, To keep your mind from stagnating. 'Tis not In hostile states, nor perils, thus to shake you, -- You, who have stood all storms and never sunk, And climbed up to the pinnacle of power And never fainted by the way, and stand Upon it, and can look down steadily Along the depth beneath, and ne'er feel dizzy. Were Genoa's galleys riding in the port, Were civil fury raging in Saint Mark's, You are not to be wrought on, but would fall, As you have risen, with an unaltered brow: Your feelings now are of a different kind; Something has stung your pride, not patriotism.
    </CONTENT>
  </SAMPLE>

  <SAMPLE>
    <AUTHOR>Shakespeare</AUTHOR>
    <CONTENT>
I understand you not, my lord. Ham. I am glad of it. A knavish speech sleeps in a foolish ear. Ros. My lord, you must tell us where the body is and go with us to the King. Ham. The body is with the King, but the King is not with the body. The King is a thing- Guil. A thing, my lord? Ham. Of nothing. Bring me to him. Hide fox, and all after.
    </CONTENT>
  </SAMPLE>

  <SAMPLE>
    <AUTHOR>Byron</AUTHOR>
    <CONTENT>
I knew my heart would never treat you harshly: knew my days could not disturb you long; And then the daughter of my earliest friend, His worthy daughter, free to choose again. Wealthier and wiser, in the ripest bloom Of womanhood, more skilful to select By passing these probationary years, Inheriting a Prince's name and riches, Secured, by the short penance of enduring An old man for some summers, against all That law's chicane or envious kinsmen might Have urged against her right; my best friend's child Would choose more fitly in respect of years, And not less truly in a faithful heart.
    </CONTENT>
  </SAMPLE>

  <SAMPLE>
    <AUTHOR>Byron</AUTHOR>
    <CONTENT>
My son! I did not speak of punishment, But penitence and pardon; -- with thyself The choice of such remains -- and for the last, Our institutions and our strong belief Have given me power to smooth the path from sin To higher hope and better thoughts; the first leave to Heaven, -- "Vengeance is mine alone!" So saith the Lord, and with all humbleness His servant echoes back the awful word.
    </CONTENT>
  </SAMPLE>

  <SAMPLE>
    <AUTHOR>Shakespeare</AUTHOR>
    <CONTENT>
The taper burneth in your closet, sir. Searching the window for a flint I found This paper thus seal'd up, and I am sure It did not lie there when I went to bed. Gives him the letter. Get you to bed again, it is not day. Is not tomorrow, boy, the ides of March? know not, sir. Look in the calendar and bring me word. will, sir. Exit. The exhalations whizzing in the air Give so much light that I may read by them. Opens the letter and reads. "Brutus, thou sleep'st: awake and see thyself! Shall Rome, etc. Speak, strike, redress!"
    </CONTENT>
  </SAMPLE>

  <SAMPLE>
    <AUTHOR>Byron</AUTHOR>
    <CONTENT>
That which should shake me, -- but I fear it not: see a dusk and awful figure rise, Like an infernal god, from out the earth; His face wrapt in a mantle, and his form Robed as with angry clouds: he stands between Thyself and me -- but I do fear him not.
    </CONTENT>
  </SAMPLE>

  <SAMPLE>
    <AUTHOR>Byron</AUTHOR>
    <CONTENT>
So now the Doge is nothing, and at last am again Marino Faliero: 'Tis well to be so, though but for a moment, Here was I crowned, and here, bear witness, Heaven! With how much more contentment I resign That shining mockery, the ducal bauble, Than I received the fatal ornament.
    </CONTENT>
  </SAMPLE>

  <SAMPLE>
    <AUTHOR>Byron</AUTHOR>
    <CONTENT>
Peace, thou thing! Thou hast done a worthy deed, and earned the price Of blood, and they who use thee will reward thee. But thou wert sent to watch, and not to prate, As thou said'st even now -- then do thine office, But let it be in silence, as behoves thee, Since, though thy prisoner, I am thy Prince.
    </CONTENT>
  </SAMPLE>

  <SAMPLE>
    <AUTHOR>Shakespeare</AUTHOR>
    <CONTENT>
And soothe the devil that I warn thee from? but remember this another day, When he shall split thy very heart with sorrow, And say poor Margaret was a prophetess! Live each of you the subjects to his hate, And he to yours, and all of you to God's! Exit My hair doth stand an end to hear her curses. And so doth mine. I muse why she's at liberty. cannot blame her; by God's holy Mother, She hath had too much wrong; and I repent My part thereof that I have done to her. never did her any to my knowledge. Yet you have all the vantage of her wrong. was too hot to do somebody good That is too cold in thinking of it now. Marry, as for Clarence, he is well repaid; He is frank'd up to fatting for his pains; God pardon them that are the cause thereof! virtuous and a Christian-like conclusion, To pray for them that have done scathe to us! So do I ever-  being well advis'd; For had I curs'd now, I had curs'd myself.
    </CONTENT>
  </SAMPLE>

  <SAMPLE>
    <AUTHOR>Byron</AUTHOR>
    <CONTENT>
Excuse me: I meant no offence To the Nine; though the number who make some pretence To their favours is such --  -- but the subject to drop, am just piping hot from a publisher's shop, (Next door to the pastry-cook's; so that when I Cannot find the new volume I wanted to buy On the bibliopole's shelves, it is only two paces, As one finds every author in one of those places:) Where I just had been skimming a charming critique, So studded with wit, and so sprinkled with Greek! Where your friend -- you know who -- has just got such a threshing, That it is, as the phrase goes, extremely "refreshing." What a beautiful word!
    </CONTENT>
  </SAMPLE>

  <SAMPLE>
    <AUTHOR>Shakespeare</AUTHOR>
    <CONTENT>
You have made shift to run into 't, boots and spurs and all, like him that leapt into the custard; and out of it you'll run again, rather than suffer question for your residence. It may be you have mistaken him, my lord. And shall do so ever, though I took him at's prayers. Fare you well, my lord; and believe this of me: there can be no kernal in this light nut; the soul of this man is his clothes; trust him not in matter of heavy consequence; I have kept of them tame, and know their natures. Farewell, monsieur; I have spoken better of you than you have or will to deserve at my hand; but we must do good against evil. Exit An idle lord, I swear. think so. Why, do you not know him? Yes, I do know him well; and common speech Gives him a worthy pass. Here comes my clog.
    </CONTENT>
  </SAMPLE>

  <SAMPLE>
    <AUTHOR>Shakespeare</AUTHOR>
    <CONTENT>
No company's abroad. None in the world; you did mistake him, sure. cannot tell; long is it since I saw him, But time hath nothing blurr'd those lines of favour Which then he wore; the snatches in his voice, And burst of speaking, were as his. I am absolute 'Twas very Cloten. In this place we left them. wish my brother make good time with him, You say he is so fell. Being scarce made up, mean to man, he had not apprehension Or roaring terrors; for defect of judgment Is oft the cease of fear.
    </CONTENT>
  </SAMPLE>

  <SAMPLE>
    <AUTHOR>Shakespeare</AUTHOR>
    <CONTENT>
Then hate me when thou wilt, if ever, now, Now while the world is bent my deeds to cross, join with the spite of fortune, make me bow, And do not drop in for an after-loss: Ah do not, when my heart hath 'scaped this sorrow, Come in the rearward of a conquered woe, Give not a windy night a rainy morrow, To linger out a purposed overthrow. If thou wilt leave me, do not leave me last, When other petty griefs have done their spite, But in the onset come, so shall I taste At first the very worst of fortune's might. And other strains of woe, which now seem woe, Compared with loss of thee, will not seem so.
    </CONTENT>
  </SAMPLE>

  <SAMPLE>
    <AUTHOR>Byron</AUTHOR>
    <CONTENT>
For a "mixed company" implies that, save Yourself and friends, and half a hundred more, Whom you may bow to without looking grave, The rest are but a vulgar set, the Bore Of public places, where they basely brave The fashionable stare of twenty score Of well-bred persons, called "The World;" but I, Although I know them, really don't know why.
    </CONTENT>
  </SAMPLE>

  <SAMPLE>
    <AUTHOR>Byron</AUTHOR>
    <CONTENT>
Hail to our Master! -- Prince of Earth and Air! Who walks the clouds and waters -- in his hand The sceptre of the Elements, which tear Themselves to chaos at his high command! He breatheth -- and a tempest shakes the sea; He speaketh -- and the clouds reply in thunder; He gazeth -- from his glance the sunbeams flee; He moveth -- Earthquakes rend the world asunder. Beneath his footsteps the Volcanoes rise; His shadow is the Pestilence: his path The comets herald through the crackling skies; And Planets turn to ashes at his wrath. To him War offers daily sacrifice; To him Death pays his tribute; Life is his, With all its Infinite of agonies -- And his the Spirit of whatever is!
    </CONTENT>
  </SAMPLE>

  <SAMPLE>
    <AUTHOR>Byron</AUTHOR>
    <CONTENT>
Orlando bade them take care of Rondello, And also made a breakfast of his own; "Abbot," he said, "I want to find that fellow Who flung at my good horse yon corner-stone." Said the abbot, "Let not my advice seem shallow; As to a brother dear I speak alone; would dissuade you, Baron, from this strife, As knowing sure that you will lose your life.
    </CONTENT>
  </SAMPLE>

  <SAMPLE>
    <AUTHOR>Shakespeare</AUTHOR>
    <CONTENT>
Peel'd priest, dost thou command me to be shut out? do, thou most usurping proditor, And not Protector of the King or realm. Stand back, thou manifest conspirator, Thou that contrived'st to murder our dead lord; Thou that giv'st whores indulgences to sin. I'll canvass thee in thy broad cardinal's hat, If thou proceed in this thy insolence. Nay, stand thou back; I will not budge a foot. This be Damascus; be thou cursed Cain, To slay thy brother Abel, if thou wilt. will not slay thee, but I'll drive thee back. Thy scarlet robes as a child's bearing-cloth I'll use to carry thee out of this place. Do what thou dar'st; I beard thee to thy face. What! am I dar'd and bearded to my face? Draw, men, for all this privileged place Blue-coats to tawny-coats. Priest, beware your beard; mean to tug it, and to cuff you soundly; Under my feet I stamp thy cardinal's hat; In spite of Pope or dignities of church, Here by the cheeks I'll drag thee up and down. Gloucester, thou wilt answer this before the
    </CONTENT>
  </SAMPLE>

  <SAMPLE>
    <AUTHOR>Shakespeare</AUTHOR>
    <CONTENT>
Thou comest to use thy tongue; thy story quickly. Gracious my lord, should report that which I say I saw, But know not how to do it. Well, say, sir. As I did stand my watch upon the hill, look'd toward Birnam, and anon, methought, The Wood began to move. Liar and slave! Let me endure your wrath, if't be not so. Within this three mile may you see it coming; say, a moving grove. If thou speak'st false, Upon the next tree shalt thou hang alive, Till famine cling thee; if thy speech be sooth, care not if thou dost for me as much. pull in resolution and begin To doubt the equivocation of the fiend That lies like truth. "Fear not, till Birnam Wood Do come to Dunsinane," and now a wood Comes toward Dunsinane. Arm, arm, and out! If this which he avouches does appear, There is nor flying hence nor tarrying here. 'gin to be aweary of the sun And wish the estate o' the world were now undone. Ring the alarum bell! Blow, wind! Come, wrack! At least we'll die with harness on our back. Exeunt.
    </CONTENT>
  </SAMPLE>

  <SAMPLE>
    <AUTHOR>Byron</AUTHOR>
    <CONTENT>
I am at peace: the peace of certainty That a sure Hour will come, when their sons' sons, And this proud city, and these azure waters, And all which makes them eminent and bright, Shall be a desolation and a curse, hissing and a scoff unto the nations, Carthage, and a Tyre, an Ocean Babel.
    </CONTENT>
  </SAMPLE>

  <SAMPLE>
    <AUTHOR>Shakespeare</AUTHOR>
    <CONTENT>
One, Kate, that you must kiss and be acquainted with. Where are my slippers? Shall I have some water? Come, Kate, and wash, and welcome heartily. You whoreson villain! will you let it fall?  You heedless joltheads and unmanner'd slaves! What, do you grumble? I'll be with you straight. Exeunt SERVANTS pray you, husband, be not so disquiet; The meat was well, if you were so contented. tell thee, Kate, 'twas burnt and dried away, And I expressly am forbid to touch it; For it engenders choler, planteth anger; And better 'twere that both of us did fast, Since, of ourselves, ourselves are choleric, Than feed it with such over-roasted flesh. Be patient; to-morrow 't shall be mended. And for this night we'll fast for company. Come, I will bring thee to thy bridal chamber. Exeunt
    </CONTENT>
  </SAMPLE>

  <SAMPLE>
    <AUTHOR>Shakespeare</AUTHOR>
    <CONTENT>
Did I, Bardolph? Bard. Indeed, Sir John, you said so. Fal. Yea. if he said my ring was copper. Prince. I say, 'tis copper. Darest thou be as good as thy word now? Fal. Why, Hal, thou knowest, as thou art but man, I dare; but as thou art Prince, I fear thee as I fear the roaring of the lion's
    </CONTENT>
  </SAMPLE>

  <SAMPLE>
    <AUTHOR>Byron</AUTHOR>
    <CONTENT>
'Tis known, at least it should be, that throughout All countries of the Catholic persuasion, Some weeks before Shrove Tuesday comes about, The People take their fill of recreation, And buy repentance, ere they grow devout, However high their rank, or low their station, With fiddling, feasting, dancing, drinking, masquing, And other things which may be had for asking.
    </CONTENT>
  </SAMPLE>

  <SAMPLE>
    <AUTHOR>Byron</AUTHOR>
    <CONTENT>
Said the Abbot, "You are welcome; what is mine We give you freely, since that you believe With us in Mary Mother's Son divine; And that you may not, Cavalier, conceive The cause of our delay to let you in To be rusticity, you shall receive The reason why our gate was barred to you: Thus those who in suspicion live must do.
    </CONTENT>
  </SAMPLE>

  <SAMPLE>
    <AUTHOR>Shakespeare</AUTHOR>
    <CONTENT>
Yonder comes the troop. Hail, all the state of Greece! What shall be done To him that victory commands? Or do you purpose victor shall be known? Will you the knights Shall to the edge of all extremity Pursue each other, or shall they be divided By any voice or order of the field? Hector bade ask. Which way would Hector have it? He cares not; he'll obey conditions. 'Tis done like Hector; but securely done, little proudly, and great deal misprizing The knight oppos'd. If not Achilles, sir, What is your name? If not Achilles, nothing. Therefore Achilles. But whate'er, know this: In the extremity of great and little Valour and pride excel themselves in Hector; The one almost as infinite as all, The other blank as nothing. Weigh him well, And that which looks like pride is courtesy. This Ajax is half made of Hector's blood; In love whereof half Hector stays at home; Half heart, half hand, half Hector comes to seek This blended knight, half Troyan and half Greek. maiden battle then? O, I perceive you!
    </CONTENT>
  </SAMPLE>

  <SAMPLE>
    <AUTHOR>Byron</AUTHOR>
    <CONTENT>
No -- but I feel, and shall do to the last. cannot quench a glorious life at once, Nor dwindle to the thing I now must be, So wronged as I, so fall'n, so loudly called To his redress: the very means I am forced By these fell tyrants to adopt is such, That I abhor them doubly for the deeds Which I must do to pay them back for theirs.
    </CONTENT>
  </SAMPLE>

  <SAMPLE>
    <AUTHOR>Byron</AUTHOR>
    <CONTENT>
But watchful Fortune, lurking, takes good heed Ever some bar 'gainst our intents to bring. While Charles reposed him thus, in word and deed, Orlando ruled court, Charles, and every thing; Curst Gan, with envy bursting, had such need To vent his spite, that thus with Charles the king One day he openly began to say, "Orlando must we always then obey?
    </CONTENT>
  </SAMPLE>

  <SAMPLE>
    <AUTHOR>Byron</AUTHOR>
    <CONTENT>
Unhappy men! prepare for instant death. The nature of your crime -- our law -- and peril The State now stands in, leave not an hour's respite. Guards! lead them forth, and upon the balcony Of the red columns, where, on festal Thursday, The Doge stands to behold the chase of bulls, Let them be justified: and leave exposed Their wavering relics, in the place of judgment, To the full view of the assembled people! And Heaven have mercy on their souls!
    </CONTENT>
  </SAMPLE>

  <SAMPLE>
    <AUTHOR>Shakespeare</AUTHOR>
    <CONTENT>
Prepare you, generals. The enemy comes on in gallant show; Their bloody sign of battle is hung out, And something to be done immediately. Octavius, lead your battle softly on, Upon the left hand of the even field. Upon the right hand I, keep thou the left. Why do you cross me in this exigent? do not cross you, but I will do so.
    </CONTENT>
  </SAMPLE>

  <SAMPLE>
    <AUTHOR>Shakespeare</AUTHOR>
    <CONTENT>
Who were those went by? Queen Hecuba and Helen. And whither go they? Up to the eastern tower, Whose height commands as subject all the vale, To see the battle. Hector, whose patience Is as a virtue fix'd, to-day was mov'd. He chid Andromache, and struck his armourer; And, like as there were husbandry in war, Before the sun rose he was harness'd light, And to the field goes he; where every flower Did as a prophet weep what it foresaw In Hector's wrath. What was his cause of anger? The noise goes, this: there is among the Greeks lord of Troyan blood, nephew to Hector; They call him Ajax. Good; and what of him? They say he is a very man per se, And stands alone. So do all men, unless they are drunk, sick, or have no
    </CONTENT>
  </SAMPLE>

  <SAMPLE>
    <AUTHOR>Byron</AUTHOR>
    <CONTENT>
Man. No, none: yet stay -- one moment, ere we part, would behold ye face to face. I hear Your voices, sweet and melancholy sounds, As Music on the waters; and I see The steady aspect of a clear large Star; But nothing more. Approach me as ye are, Or one -- or all -- in your accustomed forms.
    </CONTENT>
  </SAMPLE>

  <SAMPLE>
    <AUTHOR>Shakespeare</AUTHOR>
    <CONTENT>
I pray thee, good Mercutio, let's retire. The day is hot, the Capulets abroad. And if we meet, we shall not scape a brawl, For now, these hot days, is the mad blood stirring. Mer. Thou art like one of these fellows that, when he enters the confines of a tavern, claps me his sword upon the table and says 'God send me no need of thee!' and by the operation of the second cup draws him on the drawer, when indeed there is no need. Ben. Am I like such a fellow? Mer. Come, come, thou art as hot a jack in thy mood as any in Italy; and as soon moved to be moody, and as soon moody to be
    </CONTENT>
  </SAMPLE>

  <SAMPLE>
    <AUTHOR>Byron</AUTHOR>
    <CONTENT>
'Tis strange enough! night after night, for years, He hath pursued long vigils in this tower, Without a witness. I have been within it, -- So have we all been oft-times; but from it, Or its contents, it were impossible To draw conclusions absolute, of aught His studies tend to. To be sure, there is One chamber where none enter: I would give The fee of what I have to come these three years, To pore upon its mysteries.
    </CONTENT>
  </SAMPLE>

  <SAMPLE>
    <AUTHOR>Shakespeare</AUTHOR>
    <CONTENT>
It is well said, in faith, sir; and it is well said indeed too. 'Better accommodated!' It is good; yea, indeed, is it. Good phrases are surely, and ever were, very commendable. 'Accommodated!' It comes of accommodo. Very good; a good phrase. Pardon, sir; I have heard the word. 'Phrase' call you it? By this day, I know not the phrase; but I will maintain the word with my sword to be a soldier-like word, and a word of exceeding good command, by heaven. Accommodated: that is, when a man is, as they say, accommodated; or, when a man is being-whereby 'a may be thought to be accommodated; which is an excellent thing.
    </CONTENT>
  </SAMPLE>

  <SAMPLE>
    <AUTHOR>Byron</AUTHOR>
    <CONTENT>
It shall be broken soon. You say that all things are in readiness; To-day I have not been the usual round, And why thou knowest; but thy vigilance Will better have supplied my care: these orders In recent council to redouble now Our efforts to repair the galleys, have Lent a fair colour to the introduction Of many of our cause into the arsenal, As new artificers for their equipment, Or fresh recruits obtained in haste to man The hoped-for fleet. -- Are all supplied with arms?
    </CONTENT>
  </SAMPLE>

  <SAMPLE>
    <AUTHOR>Shakespeare</AUTHOR>
    <CONTENT>
Here comes his body, mourned by Mark Antony, who, though he had no hand in his death, shall receive the benefit of his dying, a place in the commonwealth, as which of you shall not? With this I depart- that, as I slew my best lover for the good of Rome, I have the same dagger for myself, when it shall please my country to need my death. Live, Brutus, live, live! Bring him with triumph home unto his house. Give him a statue with his ancestors. Let him be Caesar. Caesar's better parts Shall be crown'd in Brutus. We'll bring him to his house with shouts and
    </CONTENT>
  </SAMPLE>

  <SAMPLE>
    <AUTHOR>Shakespeare</AUTHOR>
    <CONTENT>
We have beat him to his camp. Run one before And let the Queen know of our gests. To-morrow, Before the sun shall see's, we'll spill the blood That has to-day escap'd. I thank you all; For doughty-handed are you, and have fought Not as you serv'd the cause, but as't had been Each man's like mine; you have shown all Hectors.
    </CONTENT>
  </SAMPLE>

  <SAMPLE>
    <AUTHOR>Byron</AUTHOR>
    <CONTENT>
To me the Lands of him who slew Came through a line of yore renowned; For I can boast a race as true To Monarchs crowned, and some discrowned, As ever Britain's Annals knew: For the first Conqueror gave us Ground, And the last Conquered owned the line Which was my mother's, and is mine.
    </CONTENT>
  </SAMPLE>

  <SAMPLE>
    <AUTHOR>Byron</AUTHOR>
    <CONTENT>
The other was as pure of mind, But formed to combat with his kind; Strong in his frame, and of a mood Which 'gainst the world in war had stood, And perished in the foremost rank With joy: -- but not in chains to pine: His spirit withered with their clank, saw it silently decline -- And so perchance in sooth did mine: But yet I forced it on to cheer Those relics of a home so dear. He was a hunter of the hills, Had followed there the deer and wolf; To him this dungeon was a gulf, And fettered feet the worst of ills.
    </CONTENT>
  </SAMPLE>

  <SAMPLE>
    <AUTHOR>Shakespeare</AUTHOR>
    <CONTENT>
What's o'clock, Francis? Fran. Anon, anon, sir.  Prince. That ever this fellow should have fewer words than a parrot, and yet the son of a woman! His industry is upstairs and downstairs, his eloquence the parcel of a reckoning. I am not yet of Percy's mind, the Hotspur of the North; he that kills me some six or seven dozen of Scots at a breakfast, washes his hands, and says to his wife, 'Fie upon this quiet life! I want work.' 'O my sweet Harry,' says she, 'how many hast thou kill'd to-day?' 'Give my roan horse a drench,' says he, and answers 'Some fourteen,' an hour after, 'a trifle, a trifle.' I prithee call in Falstaff. I'll play Percy, and that damn'd brawn shall play Dame Mortimer his wife. 'Rivo!' says the drunkard. Call in ribs, call in tallow.
    </CONTENT>
  </SAMPLE>

  <SAMPLE>
    <AUTHOR>Shakespeare</AUTHOR>
    <CONTENT>
Bless you, sir! Now, Master Brook, you come to know what hath pass'd between me and Ford's wife? That, indeed, Sir John, is my business. Master Brook, I will not lie to you; I was at her house the hour she appointed me. And sped you, sir? Very ill-favouredly, Master Brook. How so, sir; did she change her determination? No. Master Brook; but the peaking cornuto her husband, Master Brook, dwelling in a continual 'larum of jealousy, comes me in the instant of our, encounter, after we had embrac'd, kiss'd, protested, and, as it were, spoke the prologue of our comedy; and at his heels a rabble of his companions, thither provoked and instigated by his distemper, and, forsooth, to search his house for his wife's
    </CONTENT>
  </SAMPLE>

  <SAMPLE>
    <AUTHOR>Shakespeare</AUTHOR>
    <CONTENT>
If it do, you shall have a dozen of cushions again; you have but eleven now. Come, I charge you both go with me; for the man is dead that you and Pistol beat amongst you. I'll tell you what, you thin man in a censer, I will have you as soundly swing'd for this- you blue-bottle rogue, you filthy famish'd correctioner, if you be not swing'd, I'll forswear
    </CONTENT>
  </SAMPLE>

  <SAMPLE>
    <AUTHOR>Shakespeare</AUTHOR>
    <CONTENT>
Captain of our fairy band, Helena is here at hand, And the youth mistook by me Pleading for a lover's fee; Shall we their fond pageant see? Lord, what fools these mortals be! Stand aside. The noise they make Will cause Demetrius to awake. Then will two at once woo one. That must needs be sport alone; And those things do best please me That befall prepost'rously.
    </CONTENT>
  </SAMPLE>

  <SAMPLE>
    <AUTHOR>Shakespeare</AUTHOR>
    <CONTENT>
Good morrow, lord, good morrow. Who's there? My lord Aeneas? By my troth, knew you not. What news with you so early? Is not Prince Troilus here? Here! What should he do here? Come, he is here, my lord; do not deny him. It doth import him much to speak with me. Is he here, say you? It's more than I know, I'll be sworn. For my own part, I came in late. What should he do here? Who!-nay, then. Come, come, you'll do him wrong ere you are ware; you'll be so true to him to be false to him. Do not you know of him, but yet go fetch him hither; go.
    </CONTENT>
  </SAMPLE>

  <SAMPLE>
    <AUTHOR>Byron</AUTHOR>
    <CONTENT>
"Since God has granted your illumination, Accepting you in mercy for his own, Humility should be your first oblation." Morgante said, "For goodness' sake, make known, -- Since that your God is to be mine -- your station, And let your name in verity be shown; Then will I everything at your command do." On which the other said, he was Orlando.
    </CONTENT>
  </SAMPLE>

  <SAMPLE>
    <AUTHOR>Byron</AUTHOR>
    <CONTENT>
The name of this Aurora I'll not mention, Although I might, for she was nought to me More than that patent work of God's invention, charming woman, whom we like to see; But writing names would merit reprehension, Yet if you like to find out this fair She, At the next London or Parisian ball You still may mark her cheek, out-blooming all.
    </CONTENT>
  </SAMPLE>

  <SAMPLE>
    <AUTHOR>Shakespeare</AUTHOR>
    <CONTENT>
What's the news? Good news, good news! The ladies have prevail'd, The Volscians are dislodg'd, and Marcius gone. merrier day did never yet greet Rome, No, not th' expulsion of the Tarquins. Friend, Art thou certain this is true? Is't most certain? As certain as I know the sun is fire. Where have you lurk'd, that you make doubt of it? Ne'er through an arch so hurried the blown tide As the recomforted through th' gates. Why, hark you!  First, the gods bless you for your tidings; next, Accept my thankfulness. Sir, we have all Great cause to give great thanks. They are near the city? Almost at point to enter. We'll meet them, And help the joy. Exeunt
    </CONTENT>
  </SAMPLE>

  <SAMPLE>
    <AUTHOR>Byron</AUTHOR>
    <CONTENT>
Could Love for ever Run like a river, And Time's endeavour Be tried in vain -- No other pleasure With this could measure; And like a treasure We'd hug the chain. But since our sighing Ends not in dying, And, formed for flying, Love plumes his wing; Then for this reason Let's love a season; But let that season be only Spring.
    </CONTENT>
  </SAMPLE>

  <SAMPLE>
    <AUTHOR>Shakespeare</AUTHOR>
    <CONTENT>
It hath not appeared. grant indeed it hath not appeared, and your suspicion is not without wit and judgement. But, Roderigo, if thou hast that in thee indeed, which I have greater reason to believe now than ever, I mean purpose, courage, and valor, this night show it; if thou the next night following enjoy not Desdemona, take me from this world with treachery and devise engines for my life. Well, what is it? Is it within reason and compass? Sir, there is especial commission come from Venice to depute Cassio in Othello's place. Is that true? Why then Othello and Desdemona return again to Venice. no; he goes into Mauritania, and takes away with him the fair Desdemona, unless his abode be lingered here by some accident; wherein none can be so determinate as the removing of
    </CONTENT>
  </SAMPLE>

  <SAMPLE>
    <AUTHOR>Byron</AUTHOR>
    <CONTENT>
Oh that thou wert but with me! -- but I grow The fool of my own wishes, and forget The solitude which I have vaunted so Has lost its praise in this but one regret; There may be others which I less may show; -- am not of the plaintive mood, and yet feel an ebb in my philosophy, And the tide rising in my altered eye.
    </CONTENT>
  </SAMPLE>

  <SAMPLE>
    <AUTHOR>Byron</AUTHOR>
    <CONTENT>
"When there shall be occasion, you will see How I approve my courage in the fight." Orlando said, "I really think you'll be, If it should prove God's will, a goodly knight; Nor will you napping there discover me. But never mind your horse, though out of sight 'Twere best to carry him into some wood, If but the means or way I understood."
    </CONTENT>
  </SAMPLE>

  <SAMPLE>
    <AUTHOR>Byron</AUTHOR>
    <CONTENT>
But here they were in neutral space: we know From Job, that Satan hath the power to pay heavenly visit thrice a-year or so; And that the "Sons of God," like those of clay, Must keep him company; and we might show From the same book, in how polite a way The dialogue is held between the Powers Of Good and Evil -- but 'twould take up hours.
    </CONTENT>
  </SAMPLE>

  <SAMPLE>
    <AUTHOR>Shakespeare</AUTHOR>
    <CONTENT>
When forty winters shall besiege thy brow, And dig deep trenches in thy beauty's field, Thy youth's proud livery so gazed on now, Will be a tattered weed of small worth held: Then being asked, where all thy beauty lies, Where all the treasure of thy lusty days; To say within thine own deep sunken eyes, Were an all-eating shame, and thriftless praise. How much more praise deserved thy beauty's use, If thou couldst answer 'This fair child of mine Shall sum my count, and make my old excuse' Proving his beauty by succession thine. This were to be new made when thou art old, And see thy blood warm when thou feel'st it cold.
    </CONTENT>
  </SAMPLE>

  <SAMPLE>
    <AUTHOR>Shakespeare</AUTHOR>
    <CONTENT>
Yet they are not join'd. Where yond pine does stand shall discover all. I'll bring thee word Straight how 'tis like to go. Exit Swallows have built In Cleopatra's sails their nests. The augurers Say they know not, they cannot tell; look grimly, And dare not speak their knowledge. Antony Is valiant and dejected; and by starts His fretted fortunes give him hope and fear Of what he has and has not.
    </CONTENT>
  </SAMPLE>

  <SAMPLE>
    <AUTHOR>Byron</AUTHOR>
    <CONTENT>
The Count and Laura found their boat at last, And homeward floated o'er the silent tide, Discussing all the dances gone and past; The dancers and their dresses, too, beside; Some little scandals eke; but all aghast (As to their palace-stairs the rowers glide) Sate Laura by the side of her adorer, When lo! the Mussulman was there before her!
    </CONTENT>
  </SAMPLE>

  <SAMPLE>
    <AUTHOR>Shakespeare</AUTHOR>
    <CONTENT>
Who, my master? Nay, it's no matter for that. Worth six on him. Nay, not so neither; but I take him to be the greater soldier. Faith, look you, one cannot tell how to say that; for the defence of a town our general is excellent. Ay, and for an assault too.
    </CONTENT>
  </SAMPLE>

  <SAMPLE>
    <AUTHOR>Byron</AUTHOR>
    <CONTENT>
Where is Honour, Innate and precept-strengthened, 'tis the rock Of faith connubial: where it is not -- where Light thoughts are lurking, or the vanities Of worldly pleasure rankle in the heart, Or sensual throbs convulse it, well I know 'Twere hopeless for humanity to dream Of honesty in such infected blood, Although 'twere wed to him it covets most: An incarnation of the poet's God In all his marble-chiselled beauty, or The demi-deity, Alcides, in His majesty of superhuman Manhood, Would not suffice to bind where virtue is not; It is consistency which forms and proves it: Vice cannot fix, and Virtue cannot change. The once fall'n woman must for ever fall; For Vice must have variety, while Virtue Stands like the Sun, and all which rolls around Drinks life, and light, and glory from her aspect.
    </CONTENT>
  </SAMPLE>

  <SAMPLE>
    <AUTHOR>Byron</AUTHOR>
    <CONTENT>
F. Methinks, my Lord,'tis better as it is: sudden swelling of our retinue Had waked suspicion; and, though fierce and trusty, The vassals of that district are too rude And quick in quarrel to have long maintained The secret discipline we need for such service, till our foes are dealt upon.
    </CONTENT>
  </SAMPLE>

  <SAMPLE>
    <AUTHOR>Shakespeare</AUTHOR>
    <CONTENT>
uncle to the King, and Protector uncle to the King, and Regent of France great-uncle to the king great-uncle to the King, BISHOP OF WINCHESTER, and afterwards CARDINAL afterwards Duke son of Richard late Earl of Cambridge, afterwards DUKE OF YORK afterwards EARL OF SHREWSBURY his son of LONDON Lieutenant of the Tower of the White Rose or York faction of the Red Rose or Lancaster faction to Mortimer Dauphin, and afterwards King of France and titular King of Naples and his SON in Bordeaux father to Joan la Pucelle daughter to Reignier, afterwards married to King Henry Commonly called JOAN OF ARC
    </CONTENT>
  </SAMPLE>

  <SAMPLE>
    <AUTHOR>Shakespeare</AUTHOR>
    <CONTENT>
Out, ye rogue! Shall I be your ostler? Fal. Go hang thyself in thine own heir-apparent garters! If I be ta'en, I'll peach for this. An I have not ballads made on you all, and sung to filthy tunes, let a cup of sack be my poison. When a jest is so forward- and afoot too- I hate it.
    </CONTENT>
  </SAMPLE>

  <SAMPLE>
    <AUTHOR>Byron</AUTHOR>
    <CONTENT>
Aye -- father! I have had those early visions, And noble aspirations in my youth, To make my own the mind of other men, The enlightener of nations; and to rise knew not whither -- it might be to fall; But fall, even as the mountain-cataract, Which having leapt from its more dazzling height, Even in the foaming strength of its abyss, (Which casts up misty columns that become Clouds raining from the re-ascended skies,) Lies low but mighty still. -- But this is past, My thoughts mistook themselves.
    </CONTENT>
  </SAMPLE>

  <SAMPLE>
    <AUTHOR>Byron</AUTHOR>
    <CONTENT>
Your crimes Are fully proved by your accomplices, And all which Circumstance can add to aid them; Yet we would hear from your own lips complete Avowal of your treason: on the verge Of that dread gulf which none repass, the truth Alone can profit you on earth or Heaven -- Say, then, what was your motive?
    </CONTENT>
  </SAMPLE>

  <SAMPLE>
    <AUTHOR>Byron</AUTHOR>
    <CONTENT>
"His crimes!"500 But let it be so: -- it will be in vain. The veil which blackens o'er this blighted name, And hides, or seems to hide, these lineaments, Shall draw more gazers than the thousand portraits Which glitter round it in their pictured trappings -- Your delegated slaves -- the people's tyrants! "Decapitated for his crimes!" -- What crimes? Were it not better to record the facts, So that the contemplator might approve, Or at the least learn whence the crimes arose? When the beholder knows a Doge conspired, Let him be told the cause -- it is your history.
    </CONTENT>
  </SAMPLE>

  <SAMPLE>
    <AUTHOR>Byron</AUTHOR>
    <CONTENT>
Didst ever see a Gondola? For fear You should not, I'll describe it you exactly: 'Tis a long covered boat that's common here, Carved at the prow, built lightly, but compactly, Rowed by two rowers, each call'd "Gondolier," It glides along the water looking blackly, Just like a coffin clapt in a canoe, Where none can make out what you say or do.
    </CONTENT>
  </SAMPLE>

  <SAMPLE>
    <AUTHOR>Byron</AUTHOR>
    <CONTENT>
Shadow! or Spirit! Whatever thou art, Which still doth inherit The whole or a part Of the form of thy birth, Of the mould of thy clay, Which returned to the earth, Re-appear to the day! Bear what thou borest, The heart and the form, And the aspect thou worest Redeem from the worm.
    </CONTENT>
  </SAMPLE>

  <SAMPLE>
    <AUTHOR>Shakespeare</AUTHOR>
    <CONTENT>
What! Is my Lord of Winchester install'd And call'd unto a cardinal's degree? Then I perceive that will be verified Henry the Fifth did sometime prophesy: 'If once he come to be a cardinal, He'll make his cap co-equal with the crown.' My Lords Ambassadors, your several suits Have been consider'd and debated on. Your purpose is both good and reasonable, And therefore are we certainly resolv'd To draw conditions of a friendly peace, Which by my Lord of Winchester we mean Shall be transported presently to France. And for the proffer of my lord your master, have inform'd his Highness so at large, As, liking of the lady's virtuous gifts, Her beauty, and the value of her dower, He doth intend she shall be England's Queen.  In argument and proof of which contract, Bear her this jewel, pledge of my affection. And so, my Lord Protector, see them guarded And safely brought to Dover; where inshipp'd, Commit them to the fortune of the sea.
    </CONTENT>
  </SAMPLE>

  <SAMPLE>
    <AUTHOR>Shakespeare</AUTHOR>
    <CONTENT>
prithee, good Grumio, tell me how goes the world? cold world, Curtis, in every office but thine; and therefore fire. Do thy duty, and have thy duty, for my master and mistress are almost frozen to death. There's fire ready; and therefore, good Grumio, the news? Why, 'Jack boy! ho, boy!' and as much news as thou wilt. Come, you are so full of cony-catching! Why, therefore, fire; for I have caught extreme cold. Where's the cook? Is supper ready, the house trimm'd, rushes strew'd, cobwebs swept, the serving-men in their new fustian, their white stockings, and every officer his wedding-garment on? Be the jacks fair within, the jills fair without, the carpets laid, and everything in order? All ready; and therefore, I pray thee, news. First know my horse is tired; my master and mistress fall'n
    </CONTENT>
  </SAMPLE>

  <SAMPLE>
    <AUTHOR>Byron</AUTHOR>
    <CONTENT>
"The sun was sinking -- still I lay Chained to the chill and stiffening steed! thought to mingle there our clay; He flew, and perched, then flew once more, And each time nearer than before; saw his wing through twilight flit, And once so near me he alit could have smote, but lacked the strength; But the slight motion of my hand, And feeble scratching of the sand, The exerted throat's faint struggling noise, Which scarcely could be called a voice, Together scared him off at length. know no more -- my latest dream Is something of a lovely star Which fixed my dull eyes from afar, And went and came with wandering beam, And of the cold -- dull -- swimming -- dense Sensation of recurring sense, And then subsiding back to death, And then again a little breath, little thrill -- a short suspense, An icy sickness curdling o'er My heart, and sparks that crossed my brain -- gasp -- a throb -- a start of pain, sigh -- and nothing more.
    </CONTENT>
  </SAMPLE>

  <SAMPLE>
    <AUTHOR>Shakespeare</AUTHOR>
    <CONTENT>
He wants advice. He will hear none. He hath evermore had the liberty of the prison; give him leave to escape hence, he would not; drunk many times a day, if not many days entirely drunk. We have very oft awak'd him, as if to carry him to execution, and show'd him a seeming warrant for it; it hath not moved him at all. More of him anon. There is written in your brow, Provost, honesty and constancy. If I read it not truly, my ancient skill beguiles me; but in the boldness of my cunning I will lay myself in hazard. Claudio, whom here you have warrant to execute, is no greater forfeit to the law than Angelo who hath sentenc'd him. To make you understand this in a manifested effect, I crave but four days' respite; for the which you are to do me both a present and a dangerous courtesy. Pray, sir, in what? In the delaying death. Alack! How may I do it, having the hour limited, and an express command, under penalty, to deliver his head in the view of Angelo? I may make my case as Claudio's, to cross this in the
    </CONTENT>
  </SAMPLE>

  <SAMPLE>
    <AUTHOR>Byron</AUTHOR>
    <CONTENT>
The Saracen rejoined in humble tone, have had an extraordinary vision; savage serpent fell on me alone, And Macon would not pity my condition; Hence to thy God, who for ye did atone Upon the cross, preferred I my petition; His timely succour set me safe and free, And I a Christian am disposed to be."
    </CONTENT>
  </SAMPLE>

  <SAMPLE>
    <AUTHOR>Shakespeare</AUTHOR>
    <CONTENT>
Fare you well, my dove! Laer. Hadst thou thy wits, and didst persuade revenge, It could not move thus. Oph. You must sing 'A-down a-down, and you call him a-down-a.' O, how the wheel becomes it! It is the false steward, that stole his master's daughter. Laer. This nothing's more than matter. Oph. There's rosemary, that's for remembrance. Pray you, love, remember. And there is pansies, that's for thoughts. Laer. A document in madness! Thoughts and remembrance fitted. Oph. There's fennel for you, and columbines. There's rue for you, and here's some for me. We may call it herb of grace o' Sundays. you must wear your rue with a difference! There's a daisy. I would give you some violets, but they wither'd all when my father died. They say he made a good end.
    </CONTENT>
  </SAMPLE>

  <SAMPLE>
    <AUTHOR>Shakespeare</AUTHOR>
    <CONTENT>
Forbear me till anon- This wine for Lepidus! What manner o' thing is your crocodile? It is shap'd, sir, like itself, and it is as broad as it hath breadth; it is just so high as it is, and moves with it own organs. It lives by that which nourisheth it, and the elements once out of it, it transmigrates. What colour is it of? Of it own colour too. 'Tis a strange serpent. 'Tis so. And the tears of it are wet. Will this description satisfy him? With the health that Pompey gives him, else he is a very
    </CONTENT>
  </SAMPLE>

  <SAMPLE>
    <AUTHOR>Shakespeare</AUTHOR>
    <CONTENT>
think there is not in the world either malice or matter to alter it. You have an unspeakable comfort of your young Prince Mamillius; it is a gentleman of the greatest promise that ever came into my note. very well agree with you in the hopes of him. It is a gallant child; one that indeed physics the subject, makes old hearts fresh; they that went on crutches ere he was born desire yet their life to see him a man. Would they else be content to die? Yes; if there were no other excuse why they should desire to live. If the King had no son, they would desire to live on crutches till he had one.
    </CONTENT>
  </SAMPLE>

  <SAMPLE>
    <AUTHOR>Shakespeare</AUTHOR>
    <CONTENT>
Heat me these irons hot; and look thou stand Within the arras. When I strike my foot Upon the bosom of the ground, rush forth And bind the boy which you shall find with me Fast to the chair. Be heedful; hence, and watch. hope your warrant will bear out the deed. Uncleanly scruples! Fear not you. Look to't. Exeunt EXECUTIONERS Young lad, come forth; I have to say with you.
    </CONTENT>
  </SAMPLE>

  <SAMPLE>
    <AUTHOR>Byron</AUTHOR>
    <CONTENT>
For his faults -- he has but one; 'Tis but Envy, when all's done: He but pays the pain he suffers, Clipping, like a pair of Snuffers, Light that ought to burn the brighter For this temporary blighter. He's the Cancer of his Species, And will eat himself to pieces, -- Plague personified and Famine, -- Devil, whose delight is damning. Once he wrote a pretty Poem.
    </CONTENT>
  </SAMPLE>

  <SAMPLE>
    <AUTHOR>Shakespeare</AUTHOR>
    <CONTENT>
Mine eye and heart are at a mortal war, How to divide the conquest of thy sight, Mine eye, my heart thy picture's sight would bar, My heart, mine eye the freedom of that right, My heart doth plead that thou in him dost lie, closet never pierced with crystal eyes) But the defendant doth that plea deny, And says in him thy fair appearance lies. To side this title is impanelled quest of thoughts, all tenants to the heart, And by their verdict is determined The clear eye's moiety, and the dear heart's part. As thus, mine eye's due is thy outward part, And my heart's right, thy inward love of heart.
    </CONTENT>
  </SAMPLE>

  <SAMPLE>
    <AUTHOR>Byron</AUTHOR>
    <CONTENT>
This is the case in England; at least was During the dynasty of Dandies, now Perchance succeeded by some other class Of imitated Imitators: -- how Irreparably soon decline, alas! The Demagogues of fashion: all below Is frail; how easily the world is lost By Love, or War, and, now and then, -- by Frost!
    </CONTENT>
  </SAMPLE>

  <SAMPLE>
    <AUTHOR>Byron</AUTHOR>
    <CONTENT>
The Abbot was called Clermont, and by blood Descended from Angrante: under cover Of a great mountain's brow the abbey stood, But certain savage giants looked him over; One Passamont was foremost of the brood, And Alabaster and Morgante hover Second and third, with certain slings, and throw In daily jeopardy the place below.
    </CONTENT>
  </SAMPLE>

  <SAMPLE>
    <AUTHOR>Byron</AUTHOR>
    <CONTENT>
Disperse then to your posts: be firm and vigilant; Think on the wrongs we bear, the rights we claim. This day and night shall be the last of peril! Watch for the signal, and then march. I go To join my band; let each be prompt to marshal His separate charge: the Doge will now return To the palace to prepare all for the blow. We part to meet in Freedom and in Glory!
    </CONTENT>
  </SAMPLE>

  <SAMPLE>
    <AUTHOR>Byron</AUTHOR>
    <CONTENT>
Such was the hazard of the die; The wounded Charles was taught to fly In outworn Nature's agony; His wounds were stiff, his limbs were stark; The heavy hour was chill and dark; The fever in his blood forbade transient slumber's fitful aid: And thus it was; but yet through all, Kinglike the monarch bore his fall, And made, in this extreme of ill, His pangs the vassals of his will: All silent and subdued were they. As once the nations round him lay.
    </CONTENT>
  </SAMPLE>

  <SAMPLE>
    <AUTHOR>Shakespeare</AUTHOR>
    <CONTENT>
Fear me not, man; I will not break away. I'll give thee, ere I leave thee, so much money, To warrant thee, as I am 'rested for. My wife is in a wayward mood to-day, And will not lightly trust the messenger. That I should be attach'd in Ephesus, tell you 'twill sound harshly in her cars.
    </CONTENT>
  </SAMPLE>

  <SAMPLE>
    <AUTHOR>Shakespeare</AUTHOR>
    <CONTENT>
Love is too young to know what conscience is, Yet who knows not conscience is born of love? Then gentle cheater urge not my amiss, Lest guilty of my faults thy sweet self prove. For thou betraying me, I do betray My nobler part to my gross body's treason, My soul doth tell my body that he may, Triumph in love, flesh stays no farther reason, But rising at thy name doth point out thee, As his triumphant prize, proud of this pride, He is contented thy poor drudge to be, To stand in thy affairs, fall by thy side. No want of conscience hold it that I call, Her love, for whose dear love I rise and fall.
    </CONTENT>
  </SAMPLE>

  <SAMPLE>
    <AUTHOR>Shakespeare</AUTHOR>
    <CONTENT>
I heard myself proclaim'd, And by the happy hollow of a tree Escap'd the hunt. No port is free, no place That guard and most unusual vigilance Does not attend my taking. Whiles I may scape, will preserve myself; and am bethought To take the basest and most poorest shape That ever penury, in contempt of man, Brought near to beast. My face I'll grime with filth, Blanket my loins, elf all my hair in knots, And with presented nakedness outface The winds and persecutions of the sky. The country gives me proof and precedent Of Bedlam beggars, who, with roaring voices, Strike in their numb'd and mortified bare arms Pins, wooden pricks, nails, sprigs of rosemary; And with this horrible object, from low farms, Poor pelting villages, sheepcotes, and mills, Sometime with lunatic bans, sometime with prayers, Enforce their charity. 'Poor Turlygod! poor Tom!' That's something yet! Edgar I nothing am. Exit.
    </CONTENT>
  </SAMPLE>

  <SAMPLE>
    <AUTHOR>Byron</AUTHOR>
    <CONTENT>
It may be so: apprehend less treachery than weakness; Yet as he has no mistress, and no wife To work upon his milkiness of spirit, He may go through the ordeal; it is well He is an orphan, friendless save in us: woman or a child had made him less Than either in resolve.
    </CONTENT>
  </SAMPLE>

  <SAMPLE>
    <AUTHOR>Shakespeare</AUTHOR>
    <CONTENT>
Sir, my lord would instantly speak with you. Where? At your own house; there he unarms him. Good boy, tell him I come. Exit Boy doubt he be hurt. Fare ye well, good niece. Adieu, uncle. will be with you, niece, by and by. To bring, uncle. Ay, a token from Troilus. By the same token, you are a bawd.
    </CONTENT>
  </SAMPLE>

  <SAMPLE>
    <AUTHOR>Shakespeare</AUTHOR>
    <CONTENT>
Who's there? the traitor? Reg. Ingrateful fox! 'tis he. Corn. Bind fast his corky arms. Glou. What mean, your Graces? Good my friends, consider You are my guests. Do me no foul play, friends. Corn. Bind him, I say.  Glou. By the kind gods, 'tis most ignobly done To pluck me by the beard. Reg. So white, and such a traitor! Glou. Naughty lady, These hairs which thou dost ravish from my chin Will quicken, and accuse thee. I am your host. With robber's hands my hospitable favours You should not ruffle thus. What will you do? Corn. Come, sir, what letters had you late from France? Reg. Be simple-answer'd, for we know the truth. Corn. And what confederacy have you with the traitors Late footed in the kingdom? Reg. To whose hands have you sent the lunatic King?
    </CONTENT>
  </SAMPLE>

  <SAMPLE>
    <AUTHOR>Shakespeare</AUTHOR>
    <CONTENT>
how thy worth with manners may I sing, When thou art all the better part of me? What can mine own praise to mine own self bring: And what is't but mine own when I praise thee? Even for this, let us divided live, And our dear love lose name of single one, That by this separation I may give: That due to thee which thou deserv'st alone: absence what a torment wouldst thou prove, Were it not thy sour leisure gave sweet leave, To entertain the time with thoughts of love, Which time and thoughts so sweetly doth deceive. And that thou teachest how to make one twain, By praising him here who doth hence remain.
    </CONTENT>
  </SAMPLE>

  <SAMPLE>
    <AUTHOR>Byron</AUTHOR>
    <CONTENT>
So mix his body with the dust! It might Return to what it must far sooner, were The natural compound left alone to fight Its way back into earth, and fire, and air; But the unnatural balsams merely blight What Nature made him at his birth, as bare As the mere million's base unmummied clay -- Yet all his spices but prolong decay.
    </CONTENT>
  </SAMPLE>

  <SAMPLE>
    <AUTHOR>Shakespeare</AUTHOR>
    <CONTENT>
English John Talbot, Captains, calls you forth, Servant in arms to Harry King of England; And thus he would open your city gates, Be humble to us, call my sovereignvours And do him homage as obedient subjects, And I'll withdraw me and my bloody power; But if you frown upon this proffer'd peace, You tempt the fury of my three attendants, Lean famine, quartering steel, and climbing fire; Who in a moment even with the earth Shall lay your stately and air braving towers, If you forsake the offer of their love. Thou ominous and fearful owl of
    </CONTENT>
  </SAMPLE>

  <SAMPLE>
    <AUTHOR>Shakespeare</AUTHOR>
    <CONTENT>
Now will I write letters to Angelo- The Provost, he shall bear them- whose contents Shall witness to him I am near at home, And that, by great injunctions, I am bound To enter publicly. Him I'll desire To meet me at the consecrated fount, league below the city; and from thence, By cold gradation and well-balanc'd form. We shall proceed with Angelo.
    </CONTENT>
  </SAMPLE>

  <SAMPLE>
    <AUTHOR>Byron</AUTHOR>
    <CONTENT>
Ah no! -- As I have ever shared your kindness In all things else, let me not be shut out From your distress: were it of public import, You know I never sought, would never seek To win a word from you; but feeling now Your grief is private, it belongs to me To lighten or divide it. Since the day When foolish Steno's ribaldry detected Unfixed your quiet, you are greatly changed, And I would soothe you back to what you were.
    </CONTENT>
  </SAMPLE>

  <SAMPLE>
    <AUTHOR>Byron</AUTHOR>
    <CONTENT>
For my part, now, I ne'er could understand Why naughty women -- but I won't discuss thing which is a scandal to the land, only don't see why it should be thus; And if I were but in a gown and band, Just to entitle me to make a fuss, I'd preach on this till Wilberforce and Romilly Should quote in their next speeches from my homily.
    </CONTENT>
  </SAMPLE>

  <SAMPLE>
    <AUTHOR>Shakespeare</AUTHOR>
    <CONTENT>
Those lines that I before have writ do lie, Even those that said I could not love you dearer, Yet then my judgment knew no reason why, My most full flame should afterwards burn clearer, But reckoning time, whose millioned accidents Creep in 'twixt vows, and change decrees of kings, Tan sacred beauty, blunt the sharp'st intents, Divert strong minds to the course of alt'ring things: Alas why fearing of time's tyranny, Might I not then say 'Now I love you best,' When I was certain o'er incertainty, Crowning the present, doubting of the rest? Love is a babe, then might I not say so To give full growth to that which still doth grow.
    </CONTENT>
  </SAMPLE>

  <SAMPLE>
    <AUTHOR>Shakespeare</AUTHOR>
    <CONTENT>
There is no composition in these news That gives them credit. Indeed they are disproportion'd; My letters say a hundred and seven galleys. And mine, a hundred and forty. And mine, two hundred. But though they jump not on a just account- As in these cases, where the aim reports, 'Tis oft with difference- yet do they all confirm Turkish fleet, and bearing up to Cyprus. Nay, it is possible enough to judgement. do not so secure me in the error, But the main article I do approve In fearful sense.  What, ho! What, ho! What, ho! messenger from the galleys.
    </CONTENT>
  </SAMPLE>

  <SAMPLE>
    <AUTHOR>Byron</AUTHOR>
    <CONTENT>
No; I affirm. I have betrayed myself; But there's no torture in the mystic wells Which undermine your palace, nor in those Not less appalling cells, the "leaden roofs," To force a single name from me of others. The Pozzi and the Piombi were in vain; They might wring blood from me, but treachery never. And I would pass the fearful "Bridge of Sighs," Joyous that mine must be the last that e'er Would echo o'er the Stygian wave which flows Between the murderers and the murdered, washing The prison and the palace walls: there are Those who would live to think on't, and avenge me.
    </CONTENT>
  </SAMPLE>

  <SAMPLE>
    <AUTHOR>Byron</AUTHOR>
    <CONTENT>
Whate'er his youth had suffered, his old age With wealth and talking made him some amends; Though Laura sometimes put him in a rage, I've heard the Count and he were always friends. My pen is at the bottom of a page, Which being finished, here the story ends: 'Tis to be wished it had been sooner done, But stories somehow lengthen when begun.
    </CONTENT>
  </SAMPLE>

  <SAMPLE>
    <AUTHOR>Shakespeare</AUTHOR>
    <CONTENT>
Hold up thy head, vile Scot, or thou art like Never to hold it up again! The spirits Of valiant Shirley, Stafford, Blunt are in my arms. It is the Prince of Wales that threatens thee, Who never promiseth but he means to pay. They fight. Douglas flieth. Cheerly, my lord. How fares your Grace? Sir Nicholas Gawsey hath for succour sent, And so hath Clifton. I'll to Clifton straight. King. Stay and breathe awhile. Thou hast redeem'd thy lost opinion, And show'd thou mak'st some tender of my life, In this fair rescue thou hast brought to me. Prince. O God! they did me too much injury That ever said I heark'ned for your death. If it were so, I might have let alone The insulting hand of Douglas over you, Which would have been as speedy in your end As all the poisonous potions in the world, And sav'd the treacherous labour of your son. King. Make up to Clifton; I'll to Sir Nicholas Gawsey.
    </CONTENT>
  </SAMPLE>

  <SAMPLE>
    <AUTHOR>Byron</AUTHOR>
    <CONTENT>
And for the remnant which may be to come am content; and for the past I feel Not thankless, -- for within the crowded sum Of struggles, Happiness at times would steal, And for the present, I would not benumb My feelings farther. -- Nor shall I conceal That with all this I still can look around, And worship Nature with a thought profound.
    </CONTENT>
  </SAMPLE>

  <SAMPLE>
    <AUTHOR>Shakespeare</AUTHOR>
    <CONTENT>
Your steward puts me off, my lord; and am sent expressly to your lordship. Give me breath. do beseech you, good my lords, keep on; I'll wait upon you instantly. Exeunt ALCIBIADES and LORDS  Come hither. Pray you, How goes the world that I am thus encount'red With clamorous demands of date-broke bonds And the detention of long-since-due debts, Against my honour? Please you, gentlemen, The time is unagreeable to this business. Your importunacy cease till after dinner, That I may make his lordship understand Wherefore you are not paid. Do so, my friends. See them well entertain'd. Exit Pray draw near. Exit
    </CONTENT>
  </SAMPLE>

  <SAMPLE>
    <AUTHOR>Byron</AUTHOR>
    <CONTENT>
"What I have written, I have written: let The rest be on his head or mine!" So spoke Old "Nominis Umbra;" and while speaking yet, Away he melted in celestial smoke. Then Satan said to Michael, "Don't forget To call George Washington, and John Horne Tooke, And Franklin;" -- but at this time there was heard cry for room, though not a phantom stirred.
    </CONTENT>
  </SAMPLE>

  <SAMPLE>
    <AUTHOR>Byron</AUTHOR>
    <CONTENT>
He was a man as dusky as a Spaniard, Sunburnt with travel, yet a portly figure; Though coloured, as it were, within a tanyard, He was a person both of sense and vigour -- better seaman never yet did man yard; And she, although her manners showed no rigour, Was deemed a woman of the strictest principle, So much as to be thought almost invincible.
    </CONTENT>
  </SAMPLE>

  <SAMPLE>
    <AUTHOR>Byron</AUTHOR>
    <CONTENT>
Loss! -- such a palaver! I'd inoculate sooner my wife with the slaver Of a dog when gone rabid, than listen two hours To the torrent of trash which around him he pours, Pumped up with such effort, disgorged with such labour, That --  -- come -- do not make me speak ill of one's neighbour.
    </CONTENT>
  </SAMPLE>

  <SAMPLE>
    <AUTHOR>Shakespeare</AUTHOR>
    <CONTENT>
that you were your self, but love you are No longer yours, than you your self here live, Against this coming end you should prepare, And your sweet semblance to some other give. So should that beauty which you hold in lease Find no determination, then you were Your self again after your self's decease, When your sweet issue your sweet form should bear. Who lets so fair a house fall to decay, Which husbandry in honour might uphold, Against the stormy gusts of winter's day And barren rage of death's eternal cold? none but unthrifts, dear my love you know, You had a father, let your son say so.
    </CONTENT>
  </SAMPLE>

  <SAMPLE>
    <AUTHOR>Shakespeare</AUTHOR>
    <CONTENT>
good knave, i' faith, and well fed. Madam, my lord will go away to-night: very serious business calls on him. The great prerogative and rite of love, Which, as your due, time claims, he does acknowledge; But puts it off to a compell'd restraint; Whose want, and whose delay, is strew'd with sweets, Which they distil now in the curbed time, To make the coming hour o'erflow with joy And pleasure drown the brim. What's his else? That you will take your instant leave o' th' King, And make this haste as your own good proceeding, Strength'ned with what apology you think May make it probable need. What more commands he? That, having this obtain'd, you presently Attend his further pleasure. In everything I wait upon his will. shall report it so. pray you. Exit PAROLLES Come, sirrah. Exeunt
    </CONTENT>
  </SAMPLE>

  <SAMPLE>
    <AUTHOR>Shakespeare</AUTHOR>
    <CONTENT>
Captain Fluellen, you must come presently to the mines; the Duke of Gloucester would speak with you. To the mines! Tell you the Duke it is not so good to come to the mines; for, look you, the mines is not according to the disciplines of the war; the concavities of it is not sufficient. For, look you, th' athversary- you may discuss unto the Duke, look you- is digt himself four yard under the countermines; by Cheshu, I think 'a will plow up all, if there is not better
    </CONTENT>
  </SAMPLE>

  <SAMPLE>
    <AUTHOR>Byron</AUTHOR>
    <CONTENT>
I do defy ye, -- though I feel my soul Is ebbing from me, yet I do defy ye; Nor will I hence, while I have earthly breath To breathe my scorn upon ye -- earthly strength To wrestle, though with spirits; what ye take Shall be ta'en limb by limb.
    </CONTENT>
  </SAMPLE>

  <SAMPLE>
    <AUTHOR>Shakespeare</AUTHOR>
    <CONTENT>
Who are you? Tell me, for more certainty, Albeit I'll swear that I do know your tongue. Lorenzo, and thy love. Lorenzo, certain; and my love indeed; For who love I so much? And now who knows But you, Lorenzo, whether I am yours? Heaven and thy thoughts are witness that thou art. Here, catch this casket; it is worth the pains. am glad 'tis night, you do not look on me, For I am much asham'd of my exchange; But love is blind, and lovers cannot see The pretty follies that themselves commit, For, if they could, Cupid himself would blush To see me thus transformed to a boy. Descend, for you must be my torch-bearer. What! must I hold a candle to my shames? They in themselves, good sooth, are too too light. Why, 'tis an office of discovery, love, And I should be obscur'd. So are you, sweet, Even in the lovely garnish of a boy. But come at once, For the close night doth play the runaway, And we are stay'd for at Bassanio's feast. will make fast the doors, and gild myself With some moe ducats, and be with you straight.
    </CONTENT>
  </SAMPLE>

  <SAMPLE>
    <AUTHOR>Shakespeare</AUTHOR>
    <CONTENT>
Now, good sir, You know me, do you not? For a worthy lady, And one who much I honour. Pray you, then, Conduct me to the Queen. may not, madam; To the contrary I have express commandment. Here's ado, to lock up honesty and honour from Th' access of gentle visitors! Is't lawful, pray you, To see her women- any of them? Emilia? So please you, madam, To put apart these your attendants, Shall bring Emilia forth. pray now, call her. Withdraw yourselves. Exeunt ATTENDANTS And, madam, must be present at your conference. Well, be't so, prithee. Exit GAOLER Here's such ado to make no stain a stain As passes colouring.
    </CONTENT>
  </SAMPLE>

  <SAMPLE>
    <AUTHOR>Shakespeare</AUTHOR>
    <CONTENT>
Advance our waving colours on the walls; Rescu'd is Orleans from the English. Thus Joan la Pucelle hath perform'd her word. Divinest creature, Astraea's daughter, How shall I honour thee for this success? Thy promises are like Adonis' gardens, That one day bloom'd and fruitful were the next. France, triumph in thy glorious prophetess. Recover'd is the town of Orleans. More blessed hap did ne'er befall our state. Why ring not out the bells aloud throughout the
    </CONTENT>
  </SAMPLE>

  <SAMPLE>
    <AUTHOR>Byron</AUTHOR>
    <CONTENT>
said my nearer brother pined, said his mighty heart declined, He loathed and put away his food; It was not that 'twas coarse and rude, For we were used to hunter's fare, And for the like had little care: The milk drawn from the mountain goat Was changed for water from the moat, Our bread was such as captives' tears Have moistened many a thousand years, Since man first pent his fellow men Like brutes within an iron den; But what were these to us or him? These wasted not his heart or limb; My brother's soul was of that mould Which in a palace had grown cold, Had his free breathing been denied The range of the steep mountain's side; That even in death his freeborn breast In such a dungeon could not rest. might have spared my idle prayer -- They coldly laughed -- and laid him there: The flat and turfless earth above The being we so much did love; His empty chain above it leant, Such Murder's fitting monument!
    </CONTENT>
  </SAMPLE>

  <SAMPLE>
    <AUTHOR>Byron</AUTHOR>
    <CONTENT>
"For God-sake, Cavalier, come in with speed; The manna's falling now," the Abbot cried. "This fellow does not wish my horse should feed, Dear Abbot," Roland unto him replied, "Of restiveness he'd cure him had he need; That stone seems with good will and aim applied." The holy father said, "I don't deceive; They'll one day fling the mountain, I believe."
    </CONTENT>
  </SAMPLE>

  <SAMPLE>
    <AUTHOR>Byron</AUTHOR>
    <CONTENT>
And thus they bid farewell to carnal dishes, And solid meats, and highly spiced ragouts, To live for forty days on ill-dressed fishes, Because they have no sauces to their stews; thing which causes many "poohs" and "pishes," And several oaths (which would not suit the Muse), From travellers accustomed from a boy To eat their salmon, at the least, with soy;
    </CONTENT>
  </SAMPLE>

  <SAMPLE>
    <AUTHOR>Shakespeare</AUTHOR>
    <CONTENT>
Thou art as wise as thou art beautiful. Not so, neither; but if I had wit enough to get out of this wood, I have enough to serve mine own turn. Out of this wood do not desire to go; Thou shalt remain here whether thou wilt or no. am a spirit of no common rate; The summer still doth tend upon my state; And I do love thee; therefore, go with me. I'll give thee fairies to attend on thee; And they shall fetch thee jewels from the deep, And sing, while thou on pressed flowers dost sleep; And I will purge thy mortal grossness so That thou shalt like an airy spirit go. Peaseblossom! Cobweb! Moth! and Mustardseed!
    </CONTENT>
  </SAMPLE>

  <SAMPLE>
    <AUTHOR>Byron</AUTHOR>
    <CONTENT>
Dolfino's father was my friend, and Lando Fought by my side, and Marc Cornaro shared Of Veniero -- shall I save it twice? Would that I could save them and Venice also! All these men, or their fathers, were my friends Till they became my subjects; then fell from me As faithless leaves drop from the o'erblown flower, And left me a lone blighted thorny stalk, Which, in its solitude, can shelter nothing; So, as they let me wither, let them perish!
    </CONTENT>
  </SAMPLE>

  <SAMPLE>
    <AUTHOR>Byron</AUTHOR>
    <CONTENT>
We -- We! -- no matter -- you have earned the right To talk of us. -- But to the point. -- If this Attempt succeeds, and Venice, rendered free And flourishing, when we are in our graves, Conducts her generations to our tombs, And makes her children with their little hands Strew flowers o'er her deliverers' ashes, then The consequence will sanctify the deed, And we shall be like the two Bruti in The annals of hereafter; but if not, If we should fail, employing bloody means And secret plot, although to a good end, Still we are traitors, honest Israel; -- thou No less than he who was thy Sovereign Six hours ago, and now thy brother rebel.
    </CONTENT>
  </SAMPLE>

  <SAMPLE>
    <AUTHOR>Byron</AUTHOR>
    <CONTENT>
change came o'er the spirit of my dream. The Boy was sprung to manhood: in the wilds Of fiery climes he made himself a home, And his Soul drank their sunbeams: he was girt With strange and dusky aspects; he was not Himself like what he had been; on the sea And on the shore he was a wanderer; There was a mass of many images Crowded like waves upon me, but he was part of all; and in the last he lay Reposing from the noontide sultriness, Couched among fallen columns, in the shade Of ruined walls that had survived the names Of those who reared them; by his sleeping side Stood camels grazing, and some goodly steeds Were fastened near a fountain; and a man Clad in a flowing garb did watch the while, While many of his tribe slumbered around: And they were canopied by the blue sky, So cloudless, clear, and purely beautiful, That God alone was to be seen in Heaven.
    </CONTENT>
  </SAMPLE>

  <SAMPLE>
    <AUTHOR>Shakespeare</AUTHOR>
    <CONTENT>
'Tis strange, my Theseus, that these lovers speak of. More strange than true. I never may believe These antique fables, nor these fairy toys. Lovers and madmen have such seething brains, Such shaping fantasies, that apprehend More than cool reason ever comprehends. The lunatic, the lover, and the poet, Are of imagination all compact. One sees more devils than vast hell can hold; That is the madman. The lover, all as frantic, Sees Helen's beauty in a brow of Egypt. The poet's eye, in a fine frenzy rolling, Doth glance from heaven to earth, from earth to heaven; And as imagination bodies forth The forms of things unknown, the poet's pen Turns them to shapes, and gives to airy nothing local habitation and a name. Such tricks hath strong imagination That, if it would but apprehend some joy, It comprehends some bringer of that joy; Or in the night, imagining some fear, How easy is a bush suppos'd a bear? But all the story of the night told over, And all their minds transfigur'd so together, More witnesseth than fancy's images, And grows to something of great constancy, But howsoever strange and admirable.
    </CONTENT>
  </SAMPLE>

  <SAMPLE>
    <AUTHOR>Shakespeare</AUTHOR>
    <CONTENT>
Drink, servant-monster, when I bid thee; thy eyes are almost set in thy head. Where should they be set else? He were a brave monster indeed, if they were set in his tail. My man-monster hath drown'd his tongue in sack. For my part, the sea cannot drown me; I swam, ere could recover the shore, five and thirty leagues, off and on. By this light, thou shalt be my lieutenant, monster, or my standard. Your lieutenant, if you list; he's no standard. We'll not run, Monsieur Monster. Nor go neither; but you'll lie like dogs, and yet say nothing neither. Moon-calf, speak once in thy life, if thou beest a good moon-calf. How does thy honour? Let me lick thy shoe. I'll not serve him; he is not valiant. Thou liest, most ignorant monster: I am in case to justle a constable. Why, thou debosh'd fish, thou, was there ever man a coward that hath drunk so much sack as I to-day? Wilt thou tell a monstrous lie, being but half fish and half a monster? Lo, how he mocks me! Wilt thou let him, my
    </CONTENT>
  </SAMPLE>

  <SAMPLE>
    <AUTHOR>Byron</AUTHOR>
    <CONTENT>
"England! with all thy faults I love thee still," said at Calais, and have not forgot it; like to speak and lucubrate my fill; like the government (but that is not it); like the freedom of the press and quill; like the Habeas Corpus (when we've got it); like a Parliamentary debate, Particularly when 'tis not too late;
    </CONTENT>
  </SAMPLE>

  <SAMPLE>
    <AUTHOR>Byron</AUTHOR>
    <CONTENT>
Of all the places where the Carnival Was most facetious in the days of yore, For dance, and song, and serenade, and ball, And Masque, and Mime, and Mystery, and more Than I have time to tell now, or at all, Venice the bell from every city bore, -- And at the moment when I fix my story, That sea-born city was in all her glory.
    </CONTENT>
  </SAMPLE>

  <SAMPLE>
    <AUTHOR>Shakespeare</AUTHOR>
    <CONTENT>
Come here about me, you my Myrmidons; Mark what I say. Attend me where I wheel; Strike not a stroke, but keep yourselves in breath; And when I have the bloody Hector found, Empale him with your weapons round about; In fellest manner execute your arms. Follow me, sirs, and my proceedings eye. It is decreed Hector the great must die. Exeunt
    </CONTENT>
  </SAMPLE>

  <SAMPLE>
    <AUTHOR>Shakespeare</AUTHOR>
    <CONTENT>
Madam, you must come to your uncle. Yonder's old coil at home. It is proved my Lady Hero hath been falsely accus'd, the Prince and Claudio mightily abus'd, and Don John is the author of all, who is fled and gone. Will you come presently? Beat. Will you go hear this news, signior? Bene. I will live in thy heart, die in thy lap, and be buried thy eyes; and moreover, I will go with thee to thy uncle's.
    </CONTENT>
  </SAMPLE>

  <SAMPLE>
    <AUTHOR>Byron</AUTHOR>
    <CONTENT>
But he grew rich, and with his riches grew so Keen the desire to see his home again, He thought himself in duty bound to do so, And not be always thieving on the main; Lonely he felt, at times, as Robin Crusoe, And so he hired a vessel come from Spain, Bound for Corfu: she was a fine polacca, Manned with twelve hands, and laden with tobacco.
    </CONTENT>
  </SAMPLE>

  <SAMPLE>
    <AUTHOR>Shakespeare</AUTHOR>
    <CONTENT>
How ill this taper burns! Ha, who comes here? think it is the weakness of mine eyes That shapes this monstrous apparition. It comes upon me. Art thou anything? Art thou some god, some angel, or some devil That makest my blood cold and my hair to stare? Speak to me what thou art. Thy evil spirit, Brutus. Why comest thou? To tell thee thou shalt see me at Philippi. Well, then I shall see thee again? Ay, at Philippi. Why, I will see thee at Philippi then. Exit Ghost. Now I have taken heart thou vanishest. Ill spirit, I would hold more talk with thee. Boy! Lucius! Varro! Claudio! Sirs, awake!
    </CONTENT>
  </SAMPLE>

  <SAMPLE>
    <AUTHOR>Shakespeare</AUTHOR>
    <CONTENT>
God bless the King! What present hast thou there? Some certain treason. What makes treason here? Nay, it makes nothing, sir. If it mar nothing neither, The treason and you go in peace away together. beseech your Grace, let this letter be read; Our person misdoubts it: 'twas treason, he said. Berowne, read it over.  How now! What is in you? Why dost thou tear it? toy, my liege, a toy! Your Grace needs not fear it. It did move him to passion, and therefore let's hear
    </CONTENT>
  </SAMPLE>

  <SAMPLE>
    <AUTHOR>Byron</AUTHOR>
    <CONTENT>
The Cherubs and the Saints bowed down before That arch-angelic Hierarch, the first Of Essences angelical who wore The aspect of a god; but this ne'er nursed Pride in his heavenly bosom, in whose core No thought, save for his Maker's service, durst Intrude, however glorified and high; He knew him but the Viceroy of the sky.
    </CONTENT>
  </SAMPLE>

  <SAMPLE>
    <AUTHOR>Shakespeare</AUTHOR>
    <CONTENT>
Rule in this realm, and the gor'd state sustain. Kent. I have a journey, sir, shortly to go. My master calls me; I must not say no. Alb. The weight of this sad time we must obey, Speak what we feel, not what we ought to say. The oldest have borne most; we that are young Shall never see so much, nor live so long. Exeunt with a dead march.
    </CONTENT>
  </SAMPLE>

  <SAMPLE>
    <AUTHOR>Byron</AUTHOR>
    <CONTENT>
Man.I could not tame my nature down; for he Must serve who fain would sway; and soothe, and sue, And watch all time, and pry into all place, And be a living Lie, who would become mighty thing amongst the mean -- and such The mass are; I disdained to mingle with herd, though to be leader -- and of wolves, The lion is alone, and so am I.
    </CONTENT>
  </SAMPLE>

  <SAMPLE>
    <AUTHOR>Shakespeare</AUTHOR>
    <CONTENT>
Do, do. We steal by line and level, an't like your Grace. thank thee for that jest; here's a garment for't. Wit shall not go unrewarded while I am king of this country. 'Steal by line and level' is an excellent pass of pate; there's another garmet for't. Monster, come, put some lime upon your fingers, and away with the rest. will have none on't. We shall lose our time, And all be turn'd to barnacles, or to apes With foreheads villainous low. Monster, lay-to your fingers; help to bear this away where my hogshead of wine is, or I'll turn you out of my kingdom. Go to, carry this. And this. Ay, and this.
    </CONTENT>
  </SAMPLE>

  <SAMPLE>
    <AUTHOR>Shakespeare</AUTHOR>
    <CONTENT>
Why, cousin! why, Rosalind! Cupid have mercy! Not a word? Not one to throw at a dog. No, thy words are too precious to be cast away upon curs; throw some of them at me; come, lame me with reasons. Then there were two cousins laid up, when the one should be lam'd with reasons and the other mad without any. But is all this for your father? No, some of it is for my child's father. O, how full of briers is this working-day world! They are but burs, cousin, thrown upon thee in holiday foolery; if we walk not in the trodden paths, our very petticoats will catch them. could shake them off my coat: these burs are in my
    </CONTENT>
  </SAMPLE>

  <SAMPLE>
    <AUTHOR>Byron</AUTHOR>
    <CONTENT>
When I prepared my bark first to obey, As it should still obey, the helm, my mind, And carry prose or rhyme, and this my lay Of Charles the Emperor, whom you will find By several pens already praised; but they Who to diffuse his glory were inclined, For all that I can see in prose or verse, Have understood Charles badly, and wrote worse.
    </CONTENT>
  </SAMPLE>

  <SAMPLE>
    <AUTHOR>Shakespeare</AUTHOR>
    <CONTENT>
'"Lo, this device was sent me from a nun, Or sister sanctified, of holiest note, Which late her noble suit in court did shun, Whose rarest havings made the blossoms dote; For she was sought by spirits of richest coat, But kept cold distance, and did thence remove To spend her living in eternal love.
    </CONTENT>
  </SAMPLE>

  <SAMPLE>
    <AUTHOR>Byron</AUTHOR>
    <CONTENT>
(alone). There is a calm upon me -- Inexplicable stillness! which till now Did not belong to what I knew of life. If that I did not know Philosophy To be of all our vanities the motliest, The merest word that ever fooled the ear From out the schoolman's jargon, I should deem The golden secret, the sought "Kalon," found, And seated in my soul. It will not last, But it is well to have known it, though but once: It hath enlarged my thoughts with a new sense, And I within my tablets would note down That there is such a feeling. Who is there?
    </CONTENT>
  </SAMPLE>

  <SAMPLE>
    <AUTHOR>Byron</AUTHOR>
    <CONTENT>
Like Chiefs of Faction, His life is action -- formal paction That curbs his reign, Obscures his glory, Despot no more, he Such territory Quits with disdain. Still, still advancing, With banners glancing, His power enhancing, He must move on -- Repose but cloys him, Retreat destroys him, Love brooks not a degraded throne.
    </CONTENT>
  </SAMPLE>

  <SAMPLE>
    <AUTHOR>Shakespeare</AUTHOR>
    <CONTENT>
'Tis well that I get it so. But, Launce, how say'st thou that my master is become a notable lover? never knew him otherwise. Than how? notable lubber, as thou reportest him to be. Why, thou whoreson ass, thou mistak'st me. Why, fool, I meant not thee, I meant thy master. tell thee my master is become a hot lover. Why, I tell thee I care not though he burn himself in love. If thou wilt, go with me to the alehouse; if not, thou art an Hebrew, a Jew, and not worth the name of a Christian. Why? Because thou hast not so much charity in thee as to go to the ale with a Christian. Wilt thou go? At thy service. Exeunt
    </CONTENT>
  </SAMPLE>

  <SAMPLE>
    <AUTHOR>Byron</AUTHOR>
    <CONTENT>
"Sir," said the Count, with brow exceeding grave, "Your unexpected presence here will make It necessary for myself to crave Its import? But perhaps 'tis a mistake; hope it is so; and, at once to waive All compliment, I hope so for your sake; You understand my meaning, or you shall." "Sir," (quoth the Turk) "'tis no mistake at all:
    </CONTENT>
  </SAMPLE>

  <SAMPLE>
    <AUTHOR>Shakespeare</AUTHOR>
    <CONTENT>
What is the matter? Mess. Save Yourself, my lord: The ocean, overpeering of his list, Eats not the flats with more impetuous haste Than Young Laertes, in a riotous head, O'erbears Your offices. The rabble call him lord; And, as the world were now but to begin, Antiquity forgot, custom not known, The ratifiers and props of every word, They cry 'Choose we! Laertes shall be king!' Caps, hands, and tongues applaud it to the clouds, 'Laertes shall be king! Laertes king!' noise within. Queen. How cheerfully on the false trail they cry! this is counter, you false Danish dogs! King. The doors are broke.
    </CONTENT>
  </SAMPLE>

  <SAMPLE>
    <AUTHOR>Shakespeare</AUTHOR>
    <CONTENT>
give thee thy liberty, set thee from durance; and, in lieu thereof, impose on thee nothing but this: bear this significant  to the country maid Jaquenetta; there is remuneration, for the best ward of mine honour is rewarding my dependents. Moth, follow. Exit Like the sequel, I. Signior Costard, adieu. My sweet ounce of man's flesh, my incony Jew!
    </CONTENT>
  </SAMPLE>

  <SAMPLE>
    <AUTHOR>Byron</AUTHOR>
    <CONTENT>
That moment would have changed the face of ages; This gives us to Eternity -- We'll meet it As men whose triumph is not in success, But who can make their own minds all in all, Equal to every fortune. Droop not,'tis But a brief passage -- I would go alone, Yet if they send us, as 'tis like, together, Let us go worthy of our sires and selves.
    </CONTENT>
  </SAMPLE>

  <SAMPLE>
    <AUTHOR>Byron</AUTHOR>
    <CONTENT>
F. I cannot but agree with you The sentence is too slight for the offence; It is not honourable in the Forty To affix so slight a penalty to that Which was a foul affront to you, and even To them, as being your subjects; but 'tis not Yet without remedy: you can appeal To them once more, or to the Avogadori, Who, seeing that true justice is withheld, Will now take up the cause they once declined, And do you right upon the bold delinquent. Think you not thus, good Uncle? why do you stand So fixed? You heed me not: -- I pray you, hear me!
    </CONTENT>
  </SAMPLE>

  <SAMPLE>
    <AUTHOR>Byron</AUTHOR>
    <CONTENT>
"But had it come up here upon its shoulders, There would have been a different tale to tell: The fellow-feeling in the Saint's beholders Seems to have acted on them like a spell; And so this very foolish head Heaven solders Back on its trunk: it may be very well, And seems the custom here to overthrow Whatever has been wisely done below."
    </CONTENT>
  </SAMPLE>

  <SAMPLE>
    <AUTHOR>Byron</AUTHOR>
    <CONTENT>
said that like a picture by Giorgione Venetian women were, and so they are, Particularly seen from a balcony, (For beauty's sometimes best set off afar) And there, just like a heroine of Goldoni, They peep from out the blind, or o'er the bar; And truth to say, they're mostly very pretty, And rather like to show it, more's the pity!
    </CONTENT>
  </SAMPLE>

  <SAMPLE>
    <AUTHOR>Byron</AUTHOR>
    <CONTENT>
When the last sunshine of expiring Day In Summer's twilight weeps itself away, Who hath not felt the softness of the hour Sink on the heart, as dew along the flower? With a pure feeling which absorbs and awes While Nature makes that melancholy pause -- Her breathing moment on the bridge where Time Of light and darkness forms an arch sublime -- Who hath not shared that calm, so still and deep, The voiceless thought which would not speak but weep, holy concord, and a bright regret, glorious sympathy with suns that set?
    </CONTENT>
  </SAMPLE>

  <SAMPLE>
    <AUTHOR>Shakespeare</AUTHOR>
    <CONTENT>
It is great morning; and the hour prefix'd For her delivery to this valiant Greek Comes fast upon. Good my brother Troilus, Tell you the lady what she is to do And haste her to the purpose. Walk into her house. I'll bring her to the Grecian presently; And to his hand when I deliver her, Think it an altar, and thy brother Troilus priest, there off'ring to it his own heart. Exit know what 'tis to love, And would, as I shall pity, I could help! Please you walk in, my lords. Exeunt
    </CONTENT>
  </SAMPLE>

  <SAMPLE>
    <AUTHOR>Byron</AUTHOR>
    <CONTENT>
But this is o'er -- my pleasant task is done: -- was indeed delirious in my heart To lift my love so lofty as thou art; But still my frenzy was not of the mind: knew my fault, and feel my punishment Not less because I suffer it unbent. That thou wert beautiful, and I not blind, Hath been the sin which shuts me from mankind; But let them go, or torture as they will, My heart can multiply thine image still; Successful Love may sate itself away; The wretched are the faithful; 't is their fate To have all feeling, save the one, decay, And every passion into one dilate, As rapid rivers into Ocean pour; But ours is fathomless, and hath no shore.
    </CONTENT>
  </SAMPLE>

  <SAMPLE>
    <AUTHOR>Byron</AUTHOR>
    <CONTENT>
Morgante said, "Oh gentle Cavalier! Now by thy God say me no villany; The favour of your name I fain would hear, And if a Christian, speak for courtesy." Replied Orlando, "So much to your ear by my faith disclose contentedly; Christ I adore, who is the genuine Lord, And, if you please, by you may be adored."
    </CONTENT>
  </SAMPLE>

  <SAMPLE>
    <AUTHOR>Byron</AUTHOR>
    <CONTENT>
"And then he set up such a headless howl, That all the Saints came out and took him in; And there he sits by Saint Paul, cheek by jowl; Of Saint Bartholomew, which makes his cowl In heaven, and upon earth redeemed his sin, So as to make a martyr, never sped Better than did this weak and wooden head.
    </CONTENT>
  </SAMPLE>

  <SAMPLE>
    <AUTHOR>Byron</AUTHOR>
    <CONTENT>
Yet do I feel at times my mind decline, who is vexing me With pilfering pranks and petty pains, below The feeling of the healthful and the free; But much to One, who long hath suffered so, Sickness of heart, and narrowness of place, And all that may be borne, or can debase. thought mine enemies had been but Man, But Spirits may be leagued with them -- all Earth Abandons -- Heaven forgets me; -- in the dearth Of such defence the Powers of Evil can -- It may be -- tempt me further, -- and prevail Against the outworn creature they assail. Why in this furnace is my spirit proved, Like steel in tempering fire? because I loved? Because I loved what not to love, and see, Was more or less than mortal, and than me.
    </CONTENT>
  </SAMPLE>

  <SAMPLE>
    <AUTHOR>Shakespeare</AUTHOR>
    <CONTENT>
Those hours that with gentle work did frame The lovely gaze where every eye doth dwell Will play the tyrants to the very same, And that unfair which fairly doth excel: For never-resting time leads summer on To hideous winter and confounds him there, Sap checked with frost and lusty leaves quite gone, Beauty o'er-snowed and bareness every where: Then were not summer's distillation left liquid prisoner pent in walls of glass, Beauty's effect with beauty were bereft, Nor it nor no remembrance what it was. But flowers distilled though they with winter meet, Leese but their show, their substance still lives sweet.
    </CONTENT>
  </SAMPLE>

  <SAMPLE>
    <AUTHOR>Byron</AUTHOR>
    <CONTENT>
'Twas in the season when sad Philomel Weeps with her sister, who remembers and Deplores the ancient woes which both befel, And makes the nymphs enamoured, to the hand Of Phaton, by Phoebus loved so well, His car (but tempered by his sire's command) Was given, and on the horizon's verge just now Appeared, so that Tithonus scratched his brow:
    </CONTENT>
  </SAMPLE>

  <SAMPLE>
    <AUTHOR>Shakespeare</AUTHOR>
    <CONTENT>
Here is the sister of the man condemn'd Desires access to you. Hath he a sister? Ay, my good lord; a very virtuous maid, And to be shortly of a sisterhood, If not already. Well, let her be admitted. Exit SERVANT See you the fornicatress be remov'd; Let her have needful but not lavish means; There shall be order for't.
    </CONTENT>
  </SAMPLE>

  <SAMPLE>
    <AUTHOR>Shakespeare</AUTHOR>
    <CONTENT>
Why does the Prince love him so, then? Because their legs are both of a bigness, and 'a plays at quoits well, and eats conger and fennel, and drinks off candles' ends for flap-dragons, and rides the wild mare with the boys, and jumps upon join'd-stools, and swears with a good grace, and wears his boots very smooth, like unto the sign of the Leg, and breeds no bate with telling of discreet stories; and such other gambol faculties 'a has, that show a weak mind and an able body, for the which the Prince admits him. For the Prince himself is such another; the weight of a hair will turn the scales between their
    </CONTENT>
  </SAMPLE>

  <SAMPLE>
    <AUTHOR>Shakespeare</AUTHOR>
    <CONTENT>
Give me my fan. What, minion, can ye not?  cry your mercy, madam; was it you? Was't I? Yea, I it was, proud Frenchwoman. Could I come near your beauty with my nails, could set my ten commandments in your face. Sweet aunt, be quiet; 'twas against her will. Against her will, good King? Look to 't in time; She'll hamper thee and dandle thee like a baby. Though in this place most master wear no breeches, She shall not strike Dame Eleanor unreveng'd. Exit Lord Cardinal, I will follow Eleanor, And listen after Humphrey, how he proceeds. She's tickled now; her fume needs no spurs, She'll gallop far enough to her destruction. Exit
    </CONTENT>
  </SAMPLE>

  <SAMPLE>
    <AUTHOR>Shakespeare</AUTHOR>
    <CONTENT>
You are most welcome home. have not deserv'd it. But, worthy lords, have you with heed perused What I have written to you? We have. And grieve to hear't. What faults he made before the last, I think Might have found easy fines; but there to end Where he was to begin, and give away The benefit of our levies, answering us With our own charge, making a treaty where There was a yielding- this admits no excuse. He approaches; you shall hear him.
    </CONTENT>
  </SAMPLE>

  <SAMPLE>
    <AUTHOR>Byron</AUTHOR>
    <CONTENT>
But finally he thought fit to dismount, And said, "I am as light as any feather, And he has burst; -- to this what say you, Count?" Orlando answered, "Like a ship's mast rather You seem to me, and with the truck for front: Let him go! Fortune wills that we together Should march, but you on foot Morgante still." To which the Giant answered," So I will.
    </CONTENT>
  </SAMPLE>

  <SAMPLE>
    <AUTHOR>Byron</AUTHOR>
    <CONTENT>
Not I; could have wound my soul up to all things Save this. Thou must not die! and think how dear Thy life is, when I risk so many lives, Nay, more, the Life of lives, the liberty Of future generations, not to be The assassin thou miscall'st me: -- once, once more do adjure thee, pass not o'er thy threshold!
    </CONTENT>
  </SAMPLE>

  <SAMPLE>
    <AUTHOR>Byron</AUTHOR>
    <CONTENT>
"And who and what art thou?" the Archangel said. "For that you may consult my title-page," Replied this mighty shadow of a shade: "If I have kept my secret half an age, scarce shall tell it now." -- "Canst thou upbraid," Continued Michael, "George Rex, or allege Aught further?" Junius answered, "You had better First ask him for his answer to my letter:
    </CONTENT>
  </SAMPLE>

  <SAMPLE>
    <AUTHOR>Shakespeare</AUTHOR>
    <CONTENT>
What a long night is this! I will not change my horse with any that treads but on four pasterns. Ca, ha! he bounds from the earth as if his entrails were hairs; le cheval volant, the Pegasus, chez les narines de feu! When I bestride him I soar, I am a hawk. He trots the air; the earth sings when he touches it; the basest horn of his hoof is more musical than the pipe of
    </CONTENT>
  </SAMPLE>

  <SAMPLE>
    <AUTHOR>Shakespeare</AUTHOR>
    <CONTENT>
The exile of her minion is too new; She hath not yet forgot him; some more time Must wear the print of his remembrance out, And then she's yours. You are most bound to th' King, Who lets go by no vantages that may Prefer you to his daughter. Frame yourself To orderly soliciting, and be friended With aptness of the season; make denials Increase your services; so seem as if You were inspir'd to do those duties which You tender to her; that you in all obey her, Save when command to your dismission tends, And therein you are senseless. Senseless? Not so.
    </CONTENT>
  </SAMPLE>

  <SAMPLE>
    <AUTHOR>Byron</AUTHOR>
    <CONTENT>
In this they're like our coachmen, and the cause Is much the same -- the crowd, and pulling, hauling, With blasphemies enough to break their jaws, They make a never intermitted bawling. At home, our Bow-street gem'men keep the laws, And here a sentry stands within your calling; But for all that, there is a deal of swearing, And nauseous words past mentioning or bearing.
    </CONTENT>
  </SAMPLE>

  <SAMPLE>
    <AUTHOR>Byron</AUTHOR>
    <CONTENT>
Now Laura moves along the joyous crowd, Smiles in her eyes, and simpers on her lips; To some she whispers, others speaks aloud; To some she curtsies, and to some she dips, Complains of warmth, and this complaint avowed, Her lover brings the lemonade, she sips; She then surveys, condemns, but pities still Her dearest friends for being dressed so ill.
    </CONTENT>
  </SAMPLE>

  <SAMPLE>
    <AUTHOR>Byron</AUTHOR>
    <CONTENT>
Doge (musing). There is a certain Philip Calendaro Now in the Arsenal, who holds command Of eighty men, and has great influence Besides on all the spirits of his comrades: This man, I hear, is bold and popular, Sudden and daring, and yet secret; 'twould Be well that he were won: I needs must hope That Israel Bertuccio has secured him, But fain would be --  --
    </CONTENT>
  </SAMPLE>

  <SAMPLE>
    <AUTHOR>Shakespeare</AUTHOR>
    <CONTENT>
You are cock and capon too; and you crow, cock, with your comb on. Sayest thou? It is not fit your lordship should undertake every companion that you give offence to. No, I know that; but it is fit I should commit offence to my inferiors. Ay, it is fit for your lordship only. Why, so I say. Did you hear of a stranger that's come to court
    </CONTENT>
  </SAMPLE>

  <SAMPLE>
    <AUTHOR>Shakespeare</AUTHOR>
    <CONTENT>
Nan Page my daughter, and my little son, And three or four more of their growth, we'll dress Like urchins, ouphes, and fairies, green and white, With rounds of waxen tapers on their heads, And rattles in their hands; upon a sudden, As Falstaff, she, and I, are newly met, Let them from forth a sawpit rush at once With some diffused song; upon their sight We two in great amazedness will fly. Then let them all encircle him about, And fairy-like, to pinch the unclean knight; And ask him why, that hour of fairy revel, In their so sacred paths he dares to tread In shape profane. And till he tell the truth, Let the supposed fairies pinch him sound, And burn him with their tapers. The truth being known, We'll all present ourselves; dis-horn the spirit, And mock him home to Windsor. The children must Be practis'd well to this or they'll nev'r do 't. will teach the children their behaviours; and I will be like a jack-an-apes also, to burn the knight with my
    </CONTENT>
  </SAMPLE>

  <SAMPLE>
    <AUTHOR>Shakespeare</AUTHOR>
    <CONTENT>
He hath ta'en th' infection. Hold it up. Pedro. Hath she made her affection known to Benedick? Leon. No, and swears she never will. That's her torment. Claud. 'Tis true indeed. So your daughter says. 'Shall I,' says she, 'that have so oft encount'red him with scorn, write to him that I love him?'" Leon. This says she now when she is beginning to write to him; for she'll be up twenty times a night, and there will she sit in her smock till she have writ a sheet of paper. My daughter tells us
    </CONTENT>
  </SAMPLE>

  <SAMPLE>
    <AUTHOR>Shakespeare</AUTHOR>
    <CONTENT>
master, master, have watch'd so long That I am dog-weary; but at last I spied An ancient angel coming down the hill Will serve the turn. What is he, Biondello? Master, a mercatante or a pedant, know not what; but formal in apparel, In gait and countenance surely like a father. And what of him, Tranio? If he be credulous and trust my tale, I'll make him glad to seem Vincentio, And give assurance to Baptista Minola As if he were the right Vincentio. Take in your love, and then let me alone. Exeunt LUCENTIO and BIANCA
    </CONTENT>
  </SAMPLE>

  <SAMPLE>
    <AUTHOR>Shakespeare</AUTHOR>
    <CONTENT>
will, Sir. Exit Pless my soul, how full of chollors I am, and trempling of mind! I shall be glad if he have deceived me. How melancholies I am! I will knog his urinals about his knave's costard when I have goot opportunities for the ork. Pless my soul!  Melodious birds sing madrigals- Whenas I sat in Pabylon- And a thousand vagram posies. To shallow, etc.
    </CONTENT>
  </SAMPLE>

  <SAMPLE>
    <AUTHOR>Shakespeare</AUTHOR>
    <CONTENT>
The morn is fair. Good morrow, General. Good morrow, General. 'Tis well blown, lads. This morning, like the spirit of a youth That means to be of note, begins betimes. So, so. Come, give me that. This way. Well said. Fare thee well, dame, whate'er becomes of me. This is a soldier's kiss. Rebukeable, And worthy shameful check it were, to stand On more mechanic compliment; I'll leave thee Now like a man of steel. You that will fight, Follow me close; I'll bring you to't. Adieu. Exeunt ANTONY, EROS, CAPTAINS and soldiers Please you retire to your chamber? Lead me. He goes forth gallantly. That he and Caesar might Determine this great war in single fight! Then, Antony- but now. Well, on. Exeunt
    </CONTENT>
  </SAMPLE>

  <SAMPLE>
    <AUTHOR>Byron</AUTHOR>
    <CONTENT>
Though thy slumber may be deep, Yet thy Spirit shall not sleep; There are shades which will not vanish, There are thoughts thou canst not banish; By a Power to thee unknown, Thou canst never be alone; Thou art wrapt as with a shroud, Thou art gathered in a cloud; And for ever shalt thou dwell In the spirit of this spell.
    </CONTENT>
  </SAMPLE>

  <SAMPLE>
    <AUTHOR>Byron</AUTHOR>
    <CONTENT>
"'Tis true, he was a tool from first to last have the workmen safe); but as a tool So let him be consumed. From out the past Of ages, since mankind have known the rule Of monarchs -- from the bloody rolls amassed Of Sin and Slaughter -- from the Csars' school, Take the worst pupil; and produce a reign More drenched with gore, more cumbered with the slain.
    </CONTENT>
  </SAMPLE>

  <SAMPLE>
    <AUTHOR>Shakespeare</AUTHOR>
    <CONTENT>
Away! I have nothing to do with thee. Kent. Draw, you rascal! You come with letters against the King, and take Vanity the puppet's part against the royalty of her father. Draw, you rogue, or I'll so carbonado your shanks! Draw, you rascal! Come your ways! Osw. Help, ho! murther! help! Kent. Strike, you slave! Stand, rogue! Stand, you neat slave! Strike!  Osw. Help, ho! murther! murther!
    </CONTENT>
  </SAMPLE>

  <SAMPLE>
    <AUTHOR>Shakespeare</AUTHOR>
    <CONTENT>
Trouble yourselves no further. Pray you hasten Your generals after. Sir, Mark Antony Will e'en but kiss Octavia, and we'll follow. Till I shall see you in your soldier's dress, Which will become you both, farewell. We shall, As I conceive the journey, be at th' Mount Before you, Lepidus. Your way is shorter; My purposes do draw me much about. You'll win two days upon me. Sir, good success! Farewell. Exeunt
    </CONTENT>
  </SAMPLE>

  <SAMPLE>
    <AUTHOR>Shakespeare</AUTHOR>
    <CONTENT>
'Signior Martino and his wife and daughters; County Anselmo and his beauteous sisters; The lady widow of Vitruvio; Signior Placentio and His lovely nieces; Mercutio and his brother Valentine; Mine uncle Capulet, his wife, and daughters; My fair niece Rosaline and Livia; Signior Valentio and His cousin Tybalt; Lucio and the lively Helena.'
    </CONTENT>
  </SAMPLE>

  <SAMPLE>
    <AUTHOR>Shakespeare</AUTHOR>
    <CONTENT>
My hands are of your color, but I shame To wear a heart so white.  Hark, more knocking. Get on your nightgown, lest occasion call us And show us to be watchers. Be not lost So poorly in your thoughts. To know my deed, 'twere best not know myself. Knocking within. Wake Duncan with thy knocking! I would thou couldst!
    </CONTENT>
  </SAMPLE>

  <SAMPLE>
    <AUTHOR>Byron</AUTHOR>
    <CONTENT>
was the eldest of the three, And to uphold and cheer the rest ought to do -- and did my best -- And each did well in his degree. The youngest, whom my father loved, Because our mother's brow was given To him, with eyes as blue as heaven -- For him my soul was sorely moved: And truly might it be distressed To see such bird in such a nest; sunset till its summer's gone, Its sleepless summer of long light, The snow-clad offspring of the sun: And thus he was as pure and bright, And in his natural spirit gay, With tears for nought but others' ills, And then they flowed like mountain rills, Unless he could assuage the woe Which he abhorred to view below.
    </CONTENT>
  </SAMPLE>

  <SAMPLE>
    <AUTHOR>Shakespeare</AUTHOR>
    <CONTENT>
Nay, by God, soft! I know a trick worth two of that, i' faith. Gads. I pray thee lend me thine. Car. Ay, when? canst tell? Lend me thy lantern, quoth he? Marry, I'll see thee hang'd first! Gads. Sirrah carrier, what time do you mean to come to London? Car. Time enough to go to bed with a candle, I warrant thee. Come, neighbour Mugs, we'll call up the gentlemen. They will along with company, for they have great charge. Exeunt . Gads. What, ho! chamberlain!
    </CONTENT>
  </SAMPLE>

  <SAMPLE>
    <AUTHOR>Byron</AUTHOR>
    <CONTENT>
There being a want of water in the place, Orlando, like a worthy brother, said, "Morgante, I could wish you in this case To go for water." "You shall be obeyed In all commands," was the reply, "straight ways." Upon his shoulder a great tub he laid, And went out on his way unto a fountain, Where he was wont to drink, below the mountain.
    </CONTENT>
  </SAMPLE>

  <SAMPLE>
    <AUTHOR>Byron</AUTHOR>
    <CONTENT>
"But in my heart I bear through every clime The Abbot, abbey, and this solitude -- So much I love you in so short a time; For me, from Heaven reward you with all good The God so true, the eternal Lord sublime! Whose kingdom at the last hath open stood. Meantime we stand expectant of your blessing. And recommend us to your prayers with pressing."
    </CONTENT>
  </SAMPLE>

  <SAMPLE>
    <AUTHOR>Byron</AUTHOR>
    <CONTENT>
But several years elapsed since they had met; Some people thought the ship was lost, and some That he had somehow blundered into debt, And did not like the thought of steering home; And there were several offered any bet, Or that he would, or that he would not come; For most men (till by losing rendered sager) Will back their own opinions with a wager.
    </CONTENT>
  </SAMPLE>

  <SAMPLE>
    <AUTHOR>Shakespeare</AUTHOR>
    <CONTENT>
Fare you well, boy; you know my mind. I will leave you now to your gossiplike humour. You break jests as braggards do their blades, which God be thanked hurt not. My lord, for your many courtesies I thank you. I must discontinue your company. Your brother the bastard is fled from Messina. You have among you kill'd a sweet and innocent lady. For my Lord Lackbeard there, he and I shall meet; and till then peace be with him.
    </CONTENT>
  </SAMPLE>

  <SAMPLE>
    <AUTHOR>Byron</AUTHOR>
    <CONTENT>
don't see wherefore letters should not be Written without hands, since we daily view Them written without heads; and books, we see, Are filled as well without the latter too: And really till we fix on somebody For certain sure to claim them as his due, Their author, like the Niger's mouth, will bother The world to say if there be mouth or author.
    </CONTENT>
  </SAMPLE>

  <SAMPLE>
    <AUTHOR>Shakespeare</AUTHOR>
    <CONTENT>
Good Michael, look you to the guard tonight. Let's teach ourselves that honorable stop, Not to outsport discretion. Iago hath direction what to do; But notwithstanding with my personal eye Will I look to't. Iago is most honest. Michael, good night. Tomorrow with your earliest Let me have speech with you. Come, my dear love, The purchase made, the fruits are to ensue; That profit's yet to come 'tween me and you. Good night. Exeunt Othello, Desdemona, and Attendants.
    </CONTENT>
  </SAMPLE>

  <SAMPLE>
    <AUTHOR>Shakespeare</AUTHOR>
    <CONTENT>
She's making her ready, she'll come straight; you must be witty now. She does so blush, and fetches her wind so short, as if she were fray'd with a sprite. I'll fetch her. It is the prettiest villain; she fetches her breath as short as a new-ta'en sparrow. Exit Even such a passion doth embrace my bosom. My heart beats thicker than a feverous pulse, And all my powers do their bestowing lose, Like vassalage at unawares encount'ring The eye of majesty.
    </CONTENT>
  </SAMPLE>

  <SAMPLE>
    <AUTHOR>Byron</AUTHOR>
    <CONTENT>
He gazed; Morgante's height he calculated, And more than once contemplated his size; And then he said, "O Giant celebrated! Know, that no more my wonder will arise, How you could tear and fling the trees you late did, When I behold your form with my own eyes. You now a true and perfect friend will show Yourself to Christ, as once you were a foe.
    </CONTENT>
  </SAMPLE>

  <SAMPLE>
    <AUTHOR>Shakespeare</AUTHOR>
    <CONTENT>
See, see, our honor'd hostess! The love that follows us sometime is our trouble, Which still we thank as love. Herein I teach you How you shall bid God 'ield us for your pains, And thank us for your trouble. All our service In every point twice done, and then done double, Were poor and single business to contend Against those honors deep and broad wherewith Your Majesty loads our house. For those of old, And the late dignities heap'd up to them, We rest your hermits. Where's the Thane of Cawdor? We coursed him at the heels and had a purpose To be his purveyor; but he rides well, And his great love, sharp as his spur, hath holp him To his home before us. Fair and noble hostess, We are your guest tonight. Your servants ever Have theirs, themselves, and what is theirs, in compt, To make their audit at your Highness' pleasure, Still to return your own. Give me your hand; Conduct me to mine host. We love him highly, And shall continue our graces towards him. By your leave, hostess. Exeunt.
    </CONTENT>
  </SAMPLE>

  <SAMPLE>
    <AUTHOR>Shakespeare</AUTHOR>
    <CONTENT>
He shall have the skins of our enemies to make dog's leather of. And Dick the butcher- Then is sin struck down, like an ox, and iniquity's throat cut like a calf. And Smith the weaver- Argo, their thread of life is spun. Come, come, let's fall in with them.
    </CONTENT>
  </SAMPLE>

  <SAMPLE>
    <AUTHOR>Shakespeare</AUTHOR>
    <CONTENT>
Yes, truly; for, look you, the sins of the father are to be laid upon the children; therefore, I promise you, I fear you. was always plain with you, and so now I speak my agitation of the matter; therefore be o' good cheer, for truly I think you are damn'd. There is but one hope in it that can do you any good, and that is but a kind of bastard hope, neither. And what hope is that, I pray thee? Marry, you may partly hope that your father got you not- that you are not the Jew's daughter. That were a kind of bastard hope indeed; so the sins of my mother should be visited upon me. Truly then I fear you are damn'd both by father and mother; thus when I shun Scylla, your father, I fall into Charybdis, your mother; well, you are gone both ways. shall be sav'd by my husband; he hath made me a
    </CONTENT>
  </SAMPLE>

  <SAMPLE>
    <AUTHOR>Byron</AUTHOR>
    <CONTENT>
Perceiving that the pig was on him close, He gave him such a punch upon the head, As floored him so that he no more arose, Smashing the very bone; and he fell dead Next to the other. Having seen such blows, The other pigs along the valley fled; Morgante on his neck the bucket took, Full from the spring, which neither swerved nor shook.
    </CONTENT>
  </SAMPLE>

  <SAMPLE>
    <AUTHOR>Shakespeare</AUTHOR>
    <CONTENT>
Madam, there is at the gate a young gentleman much desires to speak with you. From the Count Orsino, is it? know not, madam; 'tis a fair young man, and well attended. Who of my people hold him in delay? Sir Toby, madam, your kinsman. Fetch him off, I pray you; he speaks nothing but madman. Fie on him!  Now you see, sir, how your fooling grows old, and people dislike it. Thou hast spoke for us, madonna, as if thy eldest son should be a fool; whose skull Jove cram with brains! For- here he comes- one of thy kin has a most weak pia mater.
    </CONTENT>
  </SAMPLE>

  <SAMPLE>
    <AUTHOR>Shakespeare</AUTHOR>
    <CONTENT>
Lady, will you walk a bout with your friend? Hero. So you walk softly and look sweetly and say nothing, am yours for the walk; and especially when I walk away. Pedro. With me in your company? Hero. I may say so when I please. Pedro. And when please you to say so? Hero. When I like your favour, for God defend the lute should be like the case! Pedro. My visor is Philemon's roof; within the house is Jove. Hero. Why then, your visor should be thatch'd. Pedro. Speak low if you speak love.  Balth. Well, I would you did like me. Marg. So would not I for your own sake, for I have many ill
    </CONTENT>
  </SAMPLE>

  <SAMPLE>
    <AUTHOR>Shakespeare</AUTHOR>
    <CONTENT>
Look where the youngest wren of nine comes. If you desire the spleen, and will laugh yourselves into stitches, follow me. Yond gull Malvolio is turned heathen, a very renegado; for there is no Christian that means to be saved by believing rightly can ever believe such impossible passages of grossness. He's in yellow stockings. And cross-garter'd? Most villainously; like a pedant that keeps a school i' th' church. I have dogg'd him like his murderer. He does obey every point of the letter that I dropp'd to betray him. He does smile his face into more lines than is in the new map with the augmentation of the Indies. You have not seen such a thing as 'tis; I can hardly forbear hurling things at him. I know my lady will strike him; if she do, he'll smile and take't for a great
    </CONTENT>
  </SAMPLE>

  <SAMPLE>
    <AUTHOR>Shakespeare</AUTHOR>
    <CONTENT>
They do me wrong, and I will not endure it. Who is it that complains unto the King That I, forsooth, am stern and love them not? By holy Paul, they love his Grace but lightly That fill his ears with such dissentious rumours. Because I cannot flatter and look fair, Smile in men's faces, smooth, deceive, and cog, Duck with French nods and apish courtesy, must be held a rancorous enemy. Cannot a plain man live and think no harm But thus his simple truth must be abus'd With silken, sly, insinuating Jacks? To who in all this presence speaks your Grace? To thee, that hast nor honesty nor grace. When have I injur'd thee? when done thee wrong, Or thee, or thee, or any of your faction? plague upon you all! His royal Grace- Whom God preserve better than you would wish!- Cannot be quiet searce a breathing while But you must trouble him with lewd complaints. Brother of Gloucester, you mistake the
    </CONTENT>
  </SAMPLE>

  <SAMPLE>
    <AUTHOR>Shakespeare</AUTHOR>
    <CONTENT>
Who is that calls so coldly? piece of ice. If thou doubt it, thou mayst slide from my shoulder to my heel with no greater a run but my head and my neck. A fire, good Curtis. Is my master and his wife coming, Grumio? ay, Curtis, ay; and therefore fire, fire; cast on no
    </CONTENT>
  </SAMPLE>

  <SAMPLE>
    <AUTHOR>Shakespeare</AUTHOR>
    <CONTENT>
If you be he, sir, I desire some confidence with you. Ben. She will endite him to some supper. Mer. A bawd, a bawd, a bawd! So ho! Rom. What hast thou found? Mer. No hare, sir; unless a hare, sir, in a lenten pie, that is something stale and hoar ere it be spent He walks by them and sings.
    </CONTENT>
  </SAMPLE>

  <SAMPLE>
    <AUTHOR>Shakespeare</AUTHOR>
    <CONTENT>
If I mistake not, thou art Harry Monmouth. Prince. Thou speak'st as if I would deny my name. Hot. My name is Harry Percy. Prince. Why, then I see very valiant rebel of the name. am the Prince of Wales; and think not, Percy, To share with me in glory any more. Two stars keep not their motion in one sphere, Nor can one England brook a double reign Of Harry Percy and the Prince of Wales. Hot. Nor shall it, Harry; for the hour is come To end the one of us and would to God Thy name in arms were now as great as mine! Prince. I'll make it greater ere I part from thee, And all the budding honours on thy crest I'll crop to make a garland for my head. Hot. I can no longer brook thy vanities. They fight.
    </CONTENT>
  </SAMPLE>

  <SAMPLE>
    <AUTHOR>Byron</AUTHOR>
    <CONTENT>
I had borne all -- it hurt me, but I bore it -- Till this last running over of the cup Of bitterness -- until this last loud insult, Not only unredressed, but sanctioned; then, And thus, I cast all further feelings from me -- The feelings which they crushed for me, long, long from that hour have seen but Senators In dark suspicious conflict with the Doge, Brooding with him in mutual hate and fear; They dreading he should snatch the tyranny From out their grasp, and he abhorring tyrants. To me, then, these men have no private life, Nor claim to ties they have cut off from others; As Senators for arbitrary acts Amenable, I look on them -- as such Let them be dealt upon.
    </CONTENT>
  </SAMPLE>

  <SAMPLE>
    <AUTHOR>Shakespeare</AUTHOR>
    <CONTENT>
You know I say nothing to him, for he understands not me, nor I him: he hath neither Latin, French, nor Italian, and you will come into the court and swear that I have a poor pennyworth in the English. He is a proper man's picture; but alas, who can converse with a dumb-show? How oddly he is suited! I think he bought his doublet in Italy, his round hose in France, his bonnet in Germany, and his behaviour everywhere. What think you of the Scottish lord, his neighbour? That he hath a neighbourly charity in him, for he borrowed a box of the ear of the Englishman, and swore he would pay him again when he was able; I think the Frenchman became his surety, and seal'd under for another. How like you the young German, the Duke of Saxony's
    </CONTENT>
  </SAMPLE>

  <SAMPLE>
    <AUTHOR>Shakespeare</AUTHOR>
    <CONTENT>
Who's there.? Fran. Nay, answer me. Stand and unfold yourself. Ber. Long live the King! Fran. Bernardo? Ber. He. Fran. You come most carefully upon your hour. Ber. 'Tis now struck twelve. Get thee to bed, Francisco. Fran. For this relief much thanks. 'Tis bitter cold, And I am sick at heart. Ber. Have you had quiet guard? Fran. Not a mouse stirring. Ber. Well, good night. If you do meet Horatio and Marcellus, The rivals of my watch, bid them make haste.
    </CONTENT>
  </SAMPLE>

  <SAMPLE>
    <AUTHOR>Byron</AUTHOR>
    <CONTENT>
The honours they continued to receive Perhaps exceeded what his merits claimed: He said, "I mean, and quickly, to retrieve The lost days of time past, which may be blamed; Some days ago I should have asked your leave, Kind father, but I really was ashamed, And know not how to show my sentiment, So much I see you with our stay content.
    </CONTENT>
  </SAMPLE>

  <SAMPLE>
    <AUTHOR>Byron</AUTHOR>
    <CONTENT>
"'Bring forth the horse!' -- the horse was brought! In truth, he was a noble steed, Tartar of the Ukraine breed, Who looked as though the speed of thought Were in his limbs; but he was wild, Wild as the wild deer, and untaught, With spur and bridle undefiled -- 'Twas but a day he had been caught; And snorting, with erected mane, And struggling fiercely, but in vain, In the full foam of wrath and dread To me the desert-born was led: They bound me on, that menial throng, Upon his back with many a thong; They loosed him with a sudden lash -- Away! -- away! -- and on we dash! -- Torrents less rapid and less rash.
    </CONTENT>
  </SAMPLE>

  <SAMPLE>
    <AUTHOR>Byron</AUTHOR>
    <CONTENT>
Himself, and much (heaven knows how gotten!) cash, He then embarked, with risk of life and limb, And got clear off, although the attempt was rash; He said that Providence protected him -- For my part, I say nothing -- lest we clash In our opinions: -- well -- the ship was trim, Set sail, and kept her reckoning fairly on, Except three days of calm when off Cape Bonn.
    </CONTENT>
  </SAMPLE>

  <SAMPLE>
    <AUTHOR>Byron</AUTHOR>
    <CONTENT>
Because my nature was averse from life; And yet not cruel; for I would not make, But find a desolation. Like the Wind, The red-hot breath of the most lone Simoom, Which dwells but in the desert, and sweeps o'er The barren sands which bear no shrubs to blast, And revels o'er their wild and arid waves, And seeketh not, so that it is not sought, But being met is deadly, -- such hath been The course of my existence; but there came Things in my path which are no more.
    </CONTENT>
  </SAMPLE>

  <SAMPLE>
    <AUTHOR>Byron</AUTHOR>
    <CONTENT>
"Sooner will I with Cerberus exchange My office (and his is no sinecure) Than see this royal Bedlam-bigot range The azure fields of Heaven, of that be sure!" "Saint!" replied Satan, "you do well to avenge The wrongs he made your satellites endure; And if to this exchange you should be given, I'll try to coax our Cerberus up to Heaven!"
    </CONTENT>
  </SAMPLE>

  <SAMPLE>
    <AUTHOR>Byron</AUTHOR>
    <CONTENT>
I disdain to speak. They might and must have known a heart like mine Incapable of treachery; and the power They gave me to adopt all fitting means To further their design was ne'er abused. They might be certain that who e'er was brought By me into this Council had been led To take his choice -- as brother, or as victim.
    </CONTENT>
  </SAMPLE>

  <SAMPLE>
    <AUTHOR>Byron</AUTHOR>
    <CONTENT>
I speak to Time and to Eternity, Of which I grow a portion, not to man. Ye Elements! in which to be resolved hasten, let my voice be as a Spirit Upon you! Ye blue waves! which bore my banner. Ye winds! which fluttered o'er as if you loved it, And filled my swelling sails as they were wafted To many a triumph! Thou, my native earth, Which I have bled for! and thou, foreign earth, Which drank this willing blood from many a wound! Ye stones, in which my gore will not sink, but Reek up to Heaven! Ye skies, which will receive it! Thou Sun! which shinest on these things, and Thou! Who kindlest and who quenchest suns! -- Attest! Thus I devote thee to the Infernal Gods! Thee and thy serpent seed!
    </CONTENT>
  </SAMPLE>

  <SAMPLE>
    <AUTHOR>Byron</AUTHOR>
    <CONTENT>
"Look to our earth, or rather mine; it was, Once, more thy master's: but I triumph not In this poor planet's conquest; nor, alas! Need he thou servest envy me my lot: With all the myriads of bright worlds which pass In worship round him, he may have forgot Yon weak creation of such paltry things: think few worth damnation save their kings,
    </CONTENT>
  </SAMPLE>

  <SAMPLE>
    <AUTHOR>Byron</AUTHOR>
    <CONTENT>
This was a handsome board -- at least for Heaven; And yet they had even then enough to do, So many Conquerors' cars were daily driven, So many kingdoms fitted up anew; Each day, too, slew its thousands six or seven, Till at the crowning carnage, Waterloo, They threw their pens down in divine disgust -- The page was so besmeared with blood and dust.
    </CONTENT>
  </SAMPLE>

  <SAMPLE>
    <AUTHOR>Shakespeare</AUTHOR>
    <CONTENT>
There's for you, Patroclus. will see you hang'd like clotpoles ere I come any more to your tents. I will keep where there is wit stirring, and leave the faction of fools. Exit good riddance. Marry, this, sir, is proclaim'd through all our host, That Hector, by the fifth hour of the sun, Will with a trumpet 'twixt our tents and Troy, To-morrow morning, call some knight to arms That hath a stomach; and such a one that dare Maintain I know not what; 'tis trash. Farewell. Farewell. Who shall answer him? know not; 'tis put to lott'ry. Otherwise. He knew his
    </CONTENT>
  </SAMPLE>

  <SAMPLE>
    <AUTHOR>Shakespeare</AUTHOR>
    <CONTENT>
Go you before to Gloucester with these letters. Acquaint my daughter no further with anything you know than comes from her demand out of the letter. If your diligence be not speedy, I shall be there afore you. Kent. I will not sleep, my lord, till I have delivered your letter.
    </CONTENT>
  </SAMPLE>

  <SAMPLE>
    <AUTHOR>Byron</AUTHOR>
    <CONTENT>
"True! he allowed them to pray God; but as consequence of prayer, refused the law Which would have placed them upon the same base With those who did not hold the Saints in awe." But here Saint Peter started from his place And cried, "You may the prisoner withdraw: Ere Heaven shall ope her portals to this Guelph, While I am guard, may I be damned myself!
    </CONTENT>
  </SAMPLE>

  <SAMPLE>
    <AUTHOR>Shakespeare</AUTHOR>
    <CONTENT>
Yet thou didst kill my children. But in your daughter's womb I bury them; Where, in that nest of spicery, they will breed Selves of themselves, to your recomforture. Shall I go win my daughter to thy will? And be a happy mother by the deed. go. Write to me very shortly, And you shall understand from me her mind. Bear her my true love's kiss; and so, farewell. Kissing her. Exit QUEEN ELIZABETH Relenting fool, and shallow, changing woman!
    </CONTENT>
  </SAMPLE>

  <SAMPLE>
    <AUTHOR>Byron</AUTHOR>
    <CONTENT>
stalking oracle of awful phrase, The approving "Good!" (by no means good in law) Humming like flies around the newest blaze, The bluest of bluebottles you e'er saw, Teasing with blame, excruciating with praise, Gorging the little fame he gets all raw, Translating tongues he knows not even by letter, And sweating plays so middling, bad were better.
    </CONTENT>
  </SAMPLE>

  <SAMPLE>
    <AUTHOR>Shakespeare</AUTHOR>
    <CONTENT>
There's not a man I meet but doth salute me As if I were their well-acquainted friend; And every one doth call me by my name. Some tender money to me, some invite me, Some other give me thanks for kindnesses, Some offer me commodities to buy; Even now a tailor call'd me in his shop, And show'd me silks that he had bought for me, And therewithal took measure of my body. Sure, these are but imaginary wiles, And Lapland sorcerers inhabit here.
    </CONTENT>
  </SAMPLE>

  <SAMPLE>
    <AUTHOR>Shakespeare</AUTHOR>
    <CONTENT>
Here, here, here he comes. Ah, sweet ducks! Troilus! Troilus!  Brother Troilus! Good brother, come you hither; And bring Aeneas and the Grecian with you. My lord, will you be true? Who, I? Alas, it is my vice, my fault! Whiles others fish with craft for great opinion, with great truth catch mere simplicity; Whilst some with cunning gild their copper crowns, With truth and plainness I do wear mine bare.
    </CONTENT>
  </SAMPLE>

  <SAMPLE>
    <AUTHOR>Shakespeare</AUTHOR>
    <CONTENT>
How now! what's the matter? What, is the man lunatic? Sir, you seem a sober ancient gentleman by your habit, but your words show you a madman. Why, sir, what 'cerns it you if I wear pearl and gold? I thank my good father, I am able to maintain it. Thy father! O villain! he is a sailmaker in Bergamo. You mistake, sir; you mistake, sir. Pray, what do you think is his name? His name! As if I knew not his name! I have brought him up ever since he was three years old, and his name is Tranio. Away, away, mad ass! His name is Lucentio; and he is mine only son, and heir to the lands of me, Signior Vicentio. Lucentio! O, he hath murd'red his master! Lay hold on him, I charge you, in the Duke's name. O, my son, my son! Tell me, thou villain, where is my son, Lucentio? Call forth an officer.
    </CONTENT>
  </SAMPLE>

  <SAMPLE>
    <AUTHOR>Byron</AUTHOR>
    <CONTENT>
And a magic voice and verse Hath baptized thee with a curse; And a Spirit of the air Hath begirt thee with a snare; In the wind there is a voice Shall forbid thee to rejoice; And to thee shall Night deny All the quiet of her sky; And the day shall have a sun, Which shall make thee wish it done.
    </CONTENT>
  </SAMPLE>

  <SAMPLE>
    <AUTHOR>Byron</AUTHOR>
    <CONTENT>
Leonardo Aretino said already, That if, like Pepin, Charles had had a writer Of genius quick, and diligently steady, No hero would in history look brighter; He in the cabinet being always ready, And in the field a most victorious fighter, Who for the church and Christian faith had wrought, Certes, far more than yet is said or thought.
    </CONTENT>
  </SAMPLE>

  <SAMPLE>
    <AUTHOR>Byron</AUTHOR>
    <CONTENT>
She said, -- what could she say? Why, not a word; But the Count courteously invited in The Stranger, much appeased by what he heard: "Such things, perhaps, we'd best discuss within," Said he; "don't let us make ourselves absurd In public, by a scene, nor raise a din, For then the chief and only satisfaction Will be much quizzing on the whole transaction."
    </CONTENT>
  </SAMPLE>

  <SAMPLE>
    <AUTHOR>Shakespeare</AUTHOR>
    <CONTENT>
know him to be valiant. was told that by one that knows him better than you. What's he? Marry, he told me so himself; and he said he car'd not who knew it. He needs not; it is no hidden virtue in him. By my faith, sir, but it is; never anybody saw it but his lackey. 'Tis a hooded valour, and when it appears it will bate. Ill-wind never said well. will cap that proverb with 'There is flattery in
    </CONTENT>
  </SAMPLE>

  <SAMPLE>
    <AUTHOR>Shakespeare</AUTHOR>
    <CONTENT>
Behold, this is the happy wedding torch That joineth Rouen unto her countrymen, But burning fatal to the Talbotites. Exit See, noble Charles, the beacon of our friend; The burning torch in yonder turret stands. Now shine it like a comet of revenge, prophet to the fall of all our foes! Defer no time, delays have dangerous ends;
    </CONTENT>
  </SAMPLE>

  <SAMPLE>
    <AUTHOR>Shakespeare</AUTHOR>
    <CONTENT>
God save the worthy general! With all my heart, sir. The Duke and Senators of Venice greet you. Gives him a letter. kiss the instrument of their pleasures. Opens the letter, and reads. And what's the news, good cousin Lodovico? am very glad to see you, signior; Welcome to Cyprus. thank you. How does Lieutenant Cassio? Lives, sir. Cousin, there's fall'n between him and my lord An unkind breech; but you shall make all well. Are you sure of that? My lord?  I will not stay to offend you. Truly, an obedient lady. do beseech your lordship, call her back. Mistress! My lord? What would you with her, sir? Who, I, my lord? Ay, you did wish that I would make her turn. Sir, she can turn and turn, and yet go on, And turn again; and she can weep, sir, weep; And she's obedient, as you say, obedient, Very obedient. Proceed you in your tears. Concerning this, sir- O well-painted passion!- am commanded home. Get you away; I'll send for you anon. Sir, I obey the mandate, And will return to Venice. Hence, avaunt!
    </CONTENT>
  </SAMPLE>

  <SAMPLE>
    <AUTHOR>Byron</AUTHOR>
    <CONTENT>
Myself, and thee -- a peasant of the Alps -- Thy humble virtues, hospitable home, And spirit patient, pious, proud, and free; Thy self-respect, grafted on innocent thoughts; Thy days of health, and nights of sleep; thy toils, By danger dignified, yet guiltless; hopes Of cheerful old age and a quiet grave, With cross and garland over its green turf, And thy grandchildren's love for epitaph! This do I see -- and then I look within -- It matters not -- my Soul was scorched already!
    </CONTENT>
  </SAMPLE>

  <SAMPLE>
    <AUTHOR>Shakespeare</AUTHOR>
    <CONTENT>
Here's one comes in his shirt, with light and weapons. Who's there? Whose noise is this that cries on murther? We do not know. Did not you hear a cry? Here, here! for heaven's sake, help me! What's the matter? This is Othello's ancient, as I take it. The same indeed; a very valiant fellow. What are you here that cry so grievously? Iago? O, I am spoil'd, undone by villains! Give me some help. me, lieutenant! What villains have done this? think that one of them is hereabout, And cannot make away. treacherous villains!  What are you there? Come in and give some help. help me here! That's one of them. murtherous slave! O villain! Stabs Roderigo. damn'd Iago! O inhuman dog! Kill men i' the dark! Where be these bloody thieves? How silent is this town! Ho! Murther! Murther! What may you be? Are you of good or evil? As you shall prove us, praise us. Signior Lodovico? He, sir. cry you mercy. Here's Cassio hurt by villains. Cassio? How is't, brother? My leg is cut in two. Marry, heaven forbid! Light, gentlemen; I'll bind it with my shirt.
    </CONTENT>
  </SAMPLE>

  <SAMPLE>
    <AUTHOR>Byron</AUTHOR>
    <CONTENT>
"The third, Morgante, 's savagest by far; he Plucks up pines, beeches, poplar-trees, and oaks, And flings them, our community to bury; And all that I can do but more provokes." While thus they parley in the cemetery, stone from one of their gigantic strokes, Which nearly crushed Rondell, came tumbling over, So that he took a long leap under cover.
    </CONTENT>
  </SAMPLE>

  <SAMPLE>
    <AUTHOR>Byron</AUTHOR>
    <CONTENT>
I knew that we were gagged in life; at least All those who had not heart to risk their lives Upon their open thoughts; but still I deemed That in the last few moments, the same idle Freedom of speech accorded to the dying, Would not now be denied to us; but since --  --
    </CONTENT>
  </SAMPLE>

  <SAMPLE>
    <AUTHOR>Shakespeare</AUTHOR>
    <CONTENT>
We will before the walls of Rome to-morrow Set down our host. My partner in this action, You must report to th' Volscian lords how plainly have borne this business. Only their ends You have respected; stopp'd your ears against The general suit of Rome; never admitted private whisper- no, not with such friends That thought them sure of you. This last old man, Whom with crack'd heart I have sent to Rome, Lov'd me above the measure of a father; Nay, godded me indeed. Their latest refuge Was to send him; for whose old love I have- Though I show'd sourly to him- once more offer'd The first conditions, which they did refuse And cannot now accept. To grace him only, That thought he could do more, a very little have yielded to; fresh embassies and suits, Nor from the state nor private friends, hereafter Will I lend ear to.  Ha! what shout is this? Shall I be tempted to infringe my vow In the same time 'tis made? I will not.
    </CONTENT>
  </SAMPLE>

  <SAMPLE>
    <AUTHOR>Byron</AUTHOR>
    <CONTENT>
Those grand heroics acted as a spell; The Angels stopped their ears and plied their pinions; The Devils ran howling, deafened, down to Hell; The ghosts fled, gibbering, for their own dominions -- (For 'tis not yet decided where they dwell, And I leave every man to his opinions); Michael took refuge in his trump -- but, lo! His teeth were set on edge, he could not blow!
    </CONTENT>
  </SAMPLE>

  <SAMPLE>
    <AUTHOR>Byron</AUTHOR>
    <CONTENT>
"You saved at once our life and soul: such fear The Giants caused us, that the way was lost By which we could pursue a fit career In search of Jesus and the saintly Host; And your departure breeds such sorrow here, That comfortless we all are to our cost; But months and years you would not stay in sloth, Nor are you formed to wear our sober cloth,
    </CONTENT>
  </SAMPLE>

  <SAMPLE>
    <AUTHOR>Byron</AUTHOR>
    <CONTENT>
Chamois Hunter. Even so This way the Chamois leapt: her nimble feet Have baffled me; my gains to-day will scarce Repay my break-neck travail. -- What is here? Who seems not of my trade, and yet hath reached height which none even of our mountaineers, Save our best hunters, may attain: his garb Is goodly, his mien manly, and his air Proud as a free-born peasant's, at this distance: will approach him nearer.
    </CONTENT>
  </SAMPLE>

  <SAMPLE>
    <AUTHOR>Byron</AUTHOR>
    <CONTENT>
F. My princely Uncle! you are too much moved; -- grant it was a gross offence, and grossly Left without fitting punishment: but still This fury doth exceed the provocation, Or any provocation: if we are wronged, We will ask justice; if it be denied, We'll take it; but may do all this in calmness -- Deep Vengeance is the daughter of deep Silence. have yet scarce a third part of your years, love our house, I honour you, its Chief, The guardian of my youth, and its instructor -- But though I understand your grief, and enter In part of your disdain, it doth appal me To see your anger, like our Adrian waves, O'ersweep all bounds, and foam itself to air.
    </CONTENT>
  </SAMPLE>

  <SAMPLE>
    <AUTHOR>Byron</AUTHOR>
    <CONTENT>
change came o'er the spirit of my dream. The Lady of his love; -- Oh! she was changed As by the sickness of the soul; her mind Had wandered from its dwelling, and her eyes They had not their own lustre, but the look Which is not of the earth; she was become The Queen of a fantastic realm; her thoughts Were combinations of disjointed things; And forms, impalpable and unperceived Of others' sight, familiar were to hers. And this the world calls frenzy; but the wise Have a far deeper madness -- and the glance Of melancholy is a fearful gift; What is it but the telescope of truth? Which strips the distance of its fantasies, And brings life near in utter nakedness, Making the cold reality too real!
    </CONTENT>
  </SAMPLE>

  <SAMPLE>
    <AUTHOR>Byron</AUTHOR>
    <CONTENT>
Michael began: "What wouldst thou with this man, Now dead, and brought before the Lord? What ill Hath he wrought since his mortal race began, That thou canst claim him? Speak! and do thy will, If it be just: if in this earthly span He hath been greatly failing to fulfil His duties as a king and mortal, say, And he is thine; if not -- let him have way."
    </CONTENT>
  </SAMPLE>

  <SAMPLE>
    <AUTHOR>Shakespeare</AUTHOR>
    <CONTENT>
Look in thy glass and tell the face thou viewest, Now is the time that face should form another, Whose fresh repair if now thou not renewest, Thou dost beguile the world, unbless some mother. For where is she so fair whose uneared womb Disdains the tillage of thy husbandry? Or who is he so fond will be the tomb, Of his self-love to stop posterity? Thou art thy mother's glass and she in thee Calls back the lovely April of her prime, So thou through windows of thine age shalt see, Despite of wrinkles this thy golden time. But if thou live remembered not to be, Die single and thine image dies with thee.
    </CONTENT>
  </SAMPLE>

  <SAMPLE>
    <AUTHOR>Shakespeare</AUTHOR>
    <CONTENT>
If we be not reliev'd within this hour, We must return to th' court of guard. The night Is shiny, and they say we shall embattle By th' second hour i' th' morn. This last day was shrewd one to's. bear me witness, night- What man is this? Stand close and list him. Be witness to me, O thou blessed moon, When men revolted shall upon record Bear hateful memory, poor Enobarbus did Before thy face repent! Enobarbus? Peace! Hark further. sovereign mistress of true melancholy, The poisonous damp of night disponge upon me, That life, a very rebel to my will, May hang no longer on me. Throw my heart Against the flint and hardness of my fault, Which, being dried with grief, will break to powder, And finish all foul thoughts. O Antony, Nobler than my revolt is infamous, Forgive me in thine own particular, But let the world rank me in register master-leaver and a fugitive! Antony! O Antony!  Hark! the drums Demurely wake the sleepers. Let us bear him To th' court of guard; he is of note. Our hour Is fully out. Come on, then; He may recover yet. Exeunt with the body
    </CONTENT>
  </SAMPLE>

  <SAMPLE>
    <AUTHOR>Shakespeare</AUTHOR>
    <CONTENT>
He hath been most notoriously abus'd. Pursue him, and entreat him to a peace; He hath not told us of the captain yet. When that is known, and golden time convents, solemn combination shall be made Of our dear souls. Meantime, sweet sister, We will not part from hence. Cesario, come; For so you shall be while you are a man; But when in other habits you are seen, Orsino's mistress, and his fancy's queen. Exeunt all but the CLOWN
    </CONTENT>
  </SAMPLE>

  <SAMPLE>
    <AUTHOR>Byron</AUTHOR>
    <CONTENT>
Doth he so? will look on him. advances to the Window of the Hall. Glorious Orb! the idol Themselves in orisons! Thou material God! And representative of the Unknown -- Who chose thee for his shadow! Thou chief Star! Centre of many stars! which mak'st our earth Endurable and temperest the hues And hearts of all who walk within thy rays! Sire of the seasons! Monarch of the climes, And those who dwell in them! for near or far, Our inborn spirits have a tint of thee Even as our outward aspects; -- thou dost rise, And shine, and set in glory. Fare thee well! ne'er shall see thee more. As my first glance Of love and wonder was for thee, then take My latest look: thou wilt not beam on one To whom the gifts of life and warmth have been Of a more fatal nature. He is gone -- follow.
    </CONTENT>
  </SAMPLE>

  <SAMPLE>
    <AUTHOR>Byron</AUTHOR>
    <CONTENT>
At length with jostling, elbowing, and the aid Of Cherubim appointed to that post, The devil Asmodeus to the circle made His way, and looked as if his journey cost Some trouble. When his burden down he laid, "What's this?" cried Michael; "why, 'tis not a ghost?" know it," quoth the Incubus; "but he Shall be one, if you leave the affair to me.
    </CONTENT>
  </SAMPLE>

  <SAMPLE>
    <AUTHOR>Shakespeare</AUTHOR>
    <CONTENT>
Please your lordship, here is the wine. Flaminius, I have noted thee always wise. Here's to thee. Your lordship speaks your pleasure. have observed thee always for a towardly prompt spirit, give thee thy due, and one that knows what belongs to reason, and canst use the time well, if the time use thee well. Good parts in thee.  Ha! Now I see thou art a fool, and fit for thy master.
    </CONTENT>
  </SAMPLE>

  <SAMPLE>
    <AUTHOR>Byron</AUTHOR>
    <CONTENT>
Should one survive, He would be dangerous as the whole; it is not Their number, be it tens or thousands, but The spirit of this Aristocracy Which must be rooted out; and if there were single shoot of the old tree in life, 'Twould fasten in the soil, and spring again To gloomy verdure and to bitter fruit. Bertram, we must be firm!
    </CONTENT>
  </SAMPLE>

  <SAMPLE>
    <AUTHOR>Shakespeare</AUTHOR>
    <CONTENT>
Now, Master Slender! Love him, daughter Anne- Why, how now, what does Master Fenton here? You wrong me, sir, thus still to haunt my house. told you, sir, my daughter is dispos'd of. Nay, Master Page, be not impatient. Good Master Fenton, come not to my child. She is no match for you. Sir, will you hear me? No, good Master Fenton. Come, Master Shallow; come, son Slender; in. Knowing my mind, you wrong me, Master Fenton. Exeunt PAGE, SHALLOW, and SLENDER Speak to Mistress Page. Good Mistress Page, for that I love your daughter In such a righteous fashion as I do, Perforce, against all checks, rebukes, and manners, must advance the colours of my love, And not retire. Let me have your good will. Good mother, do not marry me to yond fool. mean it not; I seek you a better husband. That's my master, Master Doctor. Alas, I had rather be set quick i' th' earth. And bowl'd to death with turnips. Come, trouble not yourself. Good Master
    </CONTENT>
  </SAMPLE>

  <SAMPLE>
    <AUTHOR>Shakespeare</AUTHOR>
    <CONTENT>
In the old age black was not counted fair, Or if it were it bore not beauty's name: But now is black beauty's successive heir, And beauty slandered with a bastard shame, For since each hand hath put on nature's power, Fairing the foul with art's false borrowed face, Sweet beauty hath no name no holy bower, But is profaned, if not lives in disgrace. Therefore my mistress' eyes are raven black, Her eyes so suited, and they mourners seem, At such who not born fair no beauty lack, Slandering creation with a false esteem, Yet so they mourn becoming of their woe, That every tongue says beauty should look so.
    </CONTENT>
  </SAMPLE>

  <SAMPLE>
    <AUTHOR>Shakespeare</AUTHOR>
    <CONTENT>
Good Ursula, wake my cousin Beatrice and desire her to rise. Urs. I will, lady. Hero. And bid her come hither. Urs. Well.  Marg. Troth, I think your other rebato were better. Hero. No, pray thee, good Meg, I'll wear this. Marg. By my troth, 's not so good, and I warrant your cousin will say so. Hero. My cousin's a fool, and thou art another. I'll wear none but
    </CONTENT>
  </SAMPLE>

  <SAMPLE>
    <AUTHOR>Shakespeare</AUTHOR>
    <CONTENT>
Upon my knowledge, he is, and lousy. Nay, look not so upon me; we shall hear of your lordship anon. What is his reputation with the Duke? The Duke knows him for no other but a poor officer of mine; and writ to me this other day to turn him out o' th' band. think I have his letter in my pocket. Marry, we'll search. In good sadness, I do not know; either it is there or it is upon a file with the Duke's other letters in my tent. Here 'tis; here's a paper. Shall I read it to you? do not know if it be it or no. Our interpreter does it well. Excellently.  'Dian, the Count's a fool, and full of
    </CONTENT>
  </SAMPLE>

  <SAMPLE>
    <AUTHOR>Shakespeare</AUTHOR>
    <CONTENT>
What potions have I drunk of Siren tears Distilled from limbecks foul as hell within, Applying fears to hopes, and hopes to fears, Still losing when I saw my self to win! What wretched errors hath my heart committed, Whilst it hath thought it self so blessed never! How have mine eyes out of their spheres been fitted In the distraction of this madding fever! benefit of ill, now I find true That better is, by evil still made better. And ruined love when it is built anew Grows fairer than at first, more strong, far greater. So I return rebuked to my content, And gain by ills thrice more than I have spent.
    </CONTENT>
  </SAMPLE>

  <SAMPLE>
    <AUTHOR>Shakespeare</AUTHOR>
    <CONTENT>
spy comfort; I cry bail. Here's a gentleman, and a friend of mine. How now, noble Pompey! What, at the wheels of Caesar? Art thou led in triumph? What, is there none of Pygmalion's images, newly made woman, to be had now for putting the hand in the pocket and extracting it clutch'd? What reply, ha? What say'st thou to this tune, matter, and method? Is't not drown'd i' th' last rain, ha? What say'st thou, trot? Is the world as it was, man? Which is the way? Is it sad, and few words? or how? The trick of it? Still thus, and thus; still worse! How doth my dear morsel, thy mistress? Procures she still,
    </CONTENT>
  </SAMPLE>

  <SAMPLE>
    <AUTHOR>Shakespeare</AUTHOR>
    <CONTENT>
Chaplain, away! Thy priesthood saves thy life. As for the brat of this accursed duke, Whose father slew my father, he shall die. And I, my lord, will bear him company. Soldiers, away with him! Ah, Clifford, murder not this innocent child, Lest thou be hated both of God and man.
    </CONTENT>
  </SAMPLE>

  <SAMPLE>
    <AUTHOR>Shakespeare</AUTHOR>
    <CONTENT>
Lawn as white as driven snow; Cypress black as e'er was crow; Gloves as sweet as damask roses; Masks for faces and for noses; Bugle bracelet, necklace amber, Perfume for a lady's chamber; Golden quoifs and stomachers, For my lads to give their dears; Pins and poking-sticks of steel- What maids lack from head to heel. Come, buy of me, come; come buy, come buy; Buy, lads, or else your lasses cry. Come, buy.
    </CONTENT>
  </SAMPLE>

  <SAMPLE>
    <AUTHOR>Byron</AUTHOR>
    <CONTENT>
Lady! this just Tribunal has resolved, Though the request be strange, to grant it, and Whatever be its purport, to accord patient hearing with the due respect Which fits your ancestry, your rank, and virtues: But you turn pale -- ho! there, look to the Lady! Place a chair instantly.
    </CONTENT>
  </SAMPLE>

  <SAMPLE>
    <AUTHOR>Shakespeare</AUTHOR>
    <CONTENT>
Heigh-ho! an it be not four by the day, I'll be hang'd. Charles' wain is over the new chimney, and yet our horse not pack'd.- What, ostler! Ost.  Anon, anon. Car. I prithee, Tom, beat Cut's saddle, put a few flocks in the point. Poor jade is wrung in the withers out of all cess.
    </CONTENT>
  </SAMPLE>

  <SAMPLE>
    <AUTHOR>Shakespeare</AUTHOR>
    <CONTENT>
Yea, two and two, Newgate fashion. Host. My lord, I pray you hear me. Prince. What say'st thou, Mistress Quickly? How doth thy husband? love him well; he is an honest man. Host. Good my lord, hear me. Fal. Prithee let her alone and list to me. Prince. What say'st thou, Jack? Fal. The other night I fell asleep here behind the arras and had my pocket pick'd. This house is turn'd bawdy house; they pick
    </CONTENT>
  </SAMPLE>

  <SAMPLE>
    <AUTHOR>Shakespeare</AUTHOR>
    <CONTENT>
Is he at Master Ford's already, think'st thou? Sure he is by this; or will be presently; but truly he is very courageous mad about his throwing into the water. Mistress Ford desires you to come suddenly. I'll be with her by and by; I'll but bring my young man here to school. Look where his master comes; 'tis a playing day, I see.
    </CONTENT>
  </SAMPLE>

  <SAMPLE>
    <AUTHOR>Byron</AUTHOR>
    <CONTENT>
"But they in Christ have firmest hope, and all Which seems to Him, to them too must appear Well done; nor could it otherwise befall; He never can in any purpose err. If sire or mother suffer endless thrall, They don't disturb themselves for him or her: What pleases God to them must joy inspire; -- Such is the observance of the eternal choir."
    </CONTENT>
  </SAMPLE>

  <SAMPLE>
    <AUTHOR>Byron</AUTHOR>
    <CONTENT>
Well, The die is thrown; but for a warlike service, Done in the field, commend me to my peasants: They made the sun shine through the host of Huns When sallow burghers slunk back to their tents, And cowered to hear their own victorious trumpet. If there be small resistance, you will find These Citizens all Lions, like their Standard; But if there's much to do, you'll wish, with me, band of iron rustics at our backs.
    </CONTENT>
  </SAMPLE>

  <SAMPLE>
    <AUTHOR>Shakespeare</AUTHOR>
    <CONTENT>
How now, Captain Fluellen! Come you from the bridge? assure you there is very excellent services committed at the bridge. Is the Duke of Exeter safe? The Duke of Exeter is as magnanimous as Agamemnon; and a man that I love and honour with my soul, and my heart, and my duty, and my live, and my living, and my uttermost power. He is not- God be praised and blessed!- any hurt in the world, but keeps the bridge most valiantly, with excellent discipline. There is an aunchient Lieutenant there at the bridge- I think in my very conscience he is as valiant a man as Mark Antony; and he is man of no estimation in the world; but I did see him do as gallant service. What do you call him? He is call'd Aunchient Pistol. know him not.
    </CONTENT>
  </SAMPLE>

  <SAMPLE>
    <AUTHOR>Shakespeare</AUTHOR>
    <CONTENT>
often came where I did hear of her, but cannot find her. Why there, there, there, there! A diamond gone, cost me two thousand ducats in Frankfort! The curse never fell upon our nation till now; I never felt it till now. Two thousand ducats in that, and other precious, precious jewels. I would my daughter were dead at my foot, and the jewels in her ear; would she were hears'd at my foot, and the ducats in her coffin! No news of them? Why, so- and I know not what's spent in the search. Why, thou- loss upon loss! The thief gone with so much, and so much to find the thief; and no satisfaction, no revenge; nor no ill luck stirring but what lights o' my shoulders; no sighs but o' my breathing; no tears but o' my shedding! Yes, other men have ill luck too: Antonio, as I heard in
    </CONTENT>
  </SAMPLE>

  <SAMPLE>
    <AUTHOR>Shakespeare</AUTHOR>
    <CONTENT>
Great Jupiter be prais'd! Lucius is taken. 'Tis thought the old man and his sons were angels. There was a fourth man, in a silly habit, That gave th' affront with them. So 'tis reported; But none of 'em can be found. Stand! who's there? Roman, Who had not now been drooping here if seconds Had answer'd him. Lay hands on him; a dog! leg of Rome shall not return to tell What crows have peck'd them here. He brags his service, As if he were of note. Bring him to th' King.
    </CONTENT>
  </SAMPLE>

  <SAMPLE>
    <AUTHOR>Byron</AUTHOR>
    <CONTENT>
Yes, Angiolina. Do not marvel; I Have let this prey upon me till I feel My life cannot be long; and fain would have you Regard the injunctions you will find within This scroll (giving her a paper) --  -- Fear not; they are for your advantage: Read them hereafter at the fitting hour.
    </CONTENT>
  </SAMPLE>

  <SAMPLE>
    <AUTHOR>Byron</AUTHOR>
    <CONTENT>
"The wood was passed; 'twas more than noon, But chill the air, although in June; Or it might be my veins ran cold -- Prolonged endurance tames the bold; And I was then not what I seem, But headlong as a wintry stream, And wore my feelings out before well could count their causes o'er: And what with fury, fear, and wrath, The tortures which beset my path --
    </CONTENT>
  </SAMPLE>

  <SAMPLE>
    <AUTHOR>Byron</AUTHOR>
    <CONTENT>
Doge (solus). He is gone, And on each footstep moves a life. 'Tis done. Which never knells but for a princely death, Or for a state in peril, pealing forth Tremendous bodements; let it do its office, And be this peal its awfullest and last Sound till the strong tower rock! -- What! silent still? would go forth, but that my post is here, To be the centre of re-union to The oft discordant elements which form Leagues of this nature, and to keep compact The wavering of the weak, in case of conflict; For if they should do battle,'twill be here, Within the palace, that the strife will thicken: Then here must be my station, as becomes The master-mover. -- Hark! he comes -- he comes, My nephew, brave Bertuccio's messenger. -- What tidings? Is he marching? hath he sped? They here!-all's lost-yet will I make an effort.
    </CONTENT>
  </SAMPLE>

  <SAMPLE>
    <AUTHOR>Shakespeare</AUTHOR>
    <CONTENT>
Thus sometimes hath the brightest day a cloud, And after summer evermore succeeds Barren winter, with his wrathful nipping cold; So cares and joys abound, as seasons fleet. Sirs, what's o'clock? Ten, my lord. Ten is the hour that was appointed me To watch the coming of my punish'd duchess. Uneath may she endure the flinty streets To tread them with her tender-feeling feet. Sweet Nell, ill can thy noble mind abrook The abject people gazing on thy face, With envious looks, laughing at thy shame, That erst did follow thy proud chariot wheels When thou didst ride in triumph through the streets. But, soft! I think she comes, and I'll prepare My tear-stain'd eyes to see her miseries.
    </CONTENT>
  </SAMPLE>

  <SAMPLE>
    <AUTHOR>Byron</AUTHOR>
    <CONTENT>
I have thought on't till -- but let me lead you back To what I urged; all these things being noted, wedded you; the world then did me justice Upon the motive, and my conduct proved They did me right, while yours was all to praise: You had all freedom -- all respect -- all trust From me and mine; and, born of those who made Princes at home, and swept Kings from their thrones On foreign shores, in all things you appeared Worthy to be our first of native dames.
    </CONTENT>
  </SAMPLE>

  <SAMPLE>
    <AUTHOR>Byron</AUTHOR>
    <CONTENT>
By the cold breast and serpent smile, By thy unfathomed gulfs of guile, By that most seeming virtuous eye, By thy shut soul's hypocrisy; By the perfection of thine art Which passed for human thine own heart; By thy delight in others' pain, And by thy brotherhood of Cain, call upon thee! and compel Thyself to be thy proper Hell!
    </CONTENT>
  </SAMPLE>

  <SAMPLE>
    <AUTHOR>Byron</AUTHOR>
    <CONTENT>
Look on me! there is an order Of mortals on the earth, who do become Old in their youth, and die ere middle age, Without the violence of warlike death; Some perishing of pleasure -- some of study -- Some worn with toil, some of mere weariness, -- Some of disease -- and some insanity -- And some of withered, or of broken hearts; For this last is a malady which slays More than are numbered in the lists of Fate, Taking all shapes, and bearing many names. Look upon me! for even of all these things Have I partaken; and of all these things, One were enough; then wonder not that I Am what I am, but that I ever was, Or having been, that I am still on earth.
    </CONTENT>
  </SAMPLE>

  <SAMPLE>
    <AUTHOR>Byron</AUTHOR>
    <CONTENT>
But bringing up the rear of this bright host Spirit of a different aspect waved His wings, like thunder-clouds above some coast Whose barren beach with frequent wrecks is paved; His brow was like the deep when tempest-tossed; Fierce and unfathomable thoughts engraved Eternal wrath on his immortal face, And where he gazed a gloom pervaded space.
    </CONTENT>
  </SAMPLE>

  <SAMPLE>
    <AUTHOR>Byron</AUTHOR>
    <CONTENT>
"And even at Aspramont thou didst begin To let him know he was a gallant knight, And by the fount did much the day to win; But I know who that day had won the fight If it had not for good Gherardo been; The victory was Almonte's else; his sight He kept upon the standard -- and the laurels, In fact and fairness, are his earning, Charles!
    </CONTENT>
  </SAMPLE>

  <SAMPLE>
    <AUTHOR>Shakespeare</AUTHOR>
    <CONTENT>
have told my neighbour how you have been solicited by a gentleman his companion. know that knave, hang him! one Parolles; a filthy officer he is in those suggestions for the young earl. Beware of them, Diana: their promises, enticements, oaths, tokens, and all these engines of lust, are not the things they go under; many a maid hath been seduced by them; and the misery is, example, that so terrible shows in the wreck of maidenhood, cannot for all that dissuade succession, but that they are limed with the twigs that threatens them. I hope I need not to advise you further; but I hope your own grace will keep you where you are, though there were no further danger known but the modesty which is so lost. You shall not need to fear me.
    </CONTENT>
  </SAMPLE>

  <SAMPLE>
    <AUTHOR>Shakespeare</AUTHOR>
    <CONTENT>
My lord, your valiant kinsman, Faulconbridge, Desires your Majesty to leave the field And send him word by me which way you go. Tell him, toward Swinstead, to the abbey there. Be of good comfort; for the great supply That was expected by the Dauphin here Are wreck'd three nights ago on Goodwin Sands; This news was brought to Richard but even now. The French fight coldly, and retire themselves. Ay me, this tyrant fever burns me up And will not let me welcome this good news. Set on toward Swinstead; to my litter straight; Weakness possesseth me, and I am faint. Exeunt
    </CONTENT>
  </SAMPLE>

  <SAMPLE>
    <AUTHOR>Byron</AUTHOR>
    <CONTENT>
They made me so; sought it not, the flattering fetters met me Returning from my Roman embassy, And never having hitherto refused Toil, charge, or duty for the state, I did not, At these late years, decline what was the highest Of all in seeming, but of all most base In what we have to do and to endure: Bear witness for me thou, my injured subject, When I can neither right myself nor thee.
    </CONTENT>
  </SAMPLE>

  <SAMPLE>
    <AUTHOR>Byron</AUTHOR>
    <CONTENT>
Thus spoke the Demon (late called "multifaced" By multo-scribbling Southey). "Then we'll call One or two persons of the myriads placed Around our congress, and dispense with all The rest," quoth Michael: "Who may be so graced As to speak first? there's choice enough -- who shall It be?" Then Satan answered, "There are many; But you may choose Jack Wilkes as well as any."
    </CONTENT>
  </SAMPLE>

  <SAMPLE>
    <AUTHOR>Byron</AUTHOR>
    <CONTENT>
'Tis true, your budding Miss is very charming, But shy and awkward at first coming out, So much alarmed, that she is quite alarming, All Giggle, Blush; half Pertness, and half Pout; And glancing at Mamma, for fear there's harm in What you, she, it, or they, may be about: The Nursery still lisps out in all they utter -- Besides, they always smell of bread and butter.
    </CONTENT>
  </SAMPLE>

  <SAMPLE>
    <AUTHOR>Byron</AUTHOR>
    <CONTENT>
"Foolish, no doubt, and wicked, to oppress poor unlucky devil without a shilling; But then I blame the man himself much less Than Bute and Grafton, and shall be unwilling To see him punished here for their excess, Since they were both damned long ago, and still in Their place below: for me, I have forgiven, And vote his habeas corpus into Heaven."
    </CONTENT>
  </SAMPLE>

  <SAMPLE>
    <AUTHOR>Shakespeare</AUTHOR>
    <CONTENT>
Here comes the clusters. And is Aufidius with him? You are they That made the air unwholesome when you cast Your stinking greasy caps in hooting at Coriolanus' exile. Now he's coming, And not a hair upon a soldier's head Which will not prove a whip; as many coxcombs As you threw caps up will he tumble down, And pay you for your voices. 'Tis no matter; If he could burn us all into one coal We have deserv'd it. Faith, we hear fearful news. For mine own part, When I said banish him, I said 'twas pity. And so did I. And so did I; and, to say the truth, so did very many of us. That we did, we did for the best; and though we willingly consented to his banishment, yet it was against our
    </CONTENT>
  </SAMPLE>

  <SAMPLE>
    <AUTHOR>Shakespeare</AUTHOR>
    <CONTENT>
Never trust me then; and by all means stir on the youth to an answer. I think oxen and wainropes cannot hale them together. For Andrew, if he were open'd and you find so much blood in his liver as will clog the foot of a flea, I'll eat the rest of th' anatomy. And his opposite, the youth, bears in his visage no great presage of cruelty.
    </CONTENT>
  </SAMPLE>

  <SAMPLE>
    <AUTHOR>Byron</AUTHOR>
    <CONTENT>
They reached the Island, he transferred his lading, And self and live stock to another bottom, And passed for a true Turkey-merchant, trading With goods of various names -- but I've forgot 'em. However, he got off by this evading, Or else the people would perhaps have shot him; And thus at Venice landed to reclaim His wife, religion, house, and Christian name.
    </CONTENT>
  </SAMPLE>

  <SAMPLE>
    <AUTHOR>Byron</AUTHOR>
    <CONTENT>
And in a certain closet, where the wall Was covered with old armour like a crust, The Abbot said to them, "I give you all." Morgante rummaged piecemeal from the dust The whole, which, save one cuirass, was too small, And that too had the mail inlaid with rust. They wondered how it fitted him exactly, Which ne'er had suited others so compactly.
    </CONTENT>
  </SAMPLE>

  <SAMPLE>
    <AUTHOR>Shakespeare</AUTHOR>
    <CONTENT>
Ham. Rest, rest, perturbed spirit! So, gentlemen, With all my love I do commend me to you; And what so poor a man as Hamlet is May do t' express his love and friending to you, God willing, shall not lack. Let us go in together; And still your fingers on your lips, I pray. The time is out of joint. O cursed spite That ever I was born to set it right! Nay, come, let's go together.
    </CONTENT>
  </SAMPLE>

  <SAMPLE>
    <AUTHOR>Shakespeare</AUTHOR>
    <CONTENT>
How now, thou core of envy! Thou crusty batch of nature, what's the news? Why, thou picture of what thou seemest, and idol of idiot worshippers, here's a letter for thee. From whence, fragment? Why, thou full dish of fool, from Troy. Who keeps the tent now? The surgeon's box or the patient's wound. Well said, Adversity! and what needs these tricks? Prithee, be silent, boy; I profit not by thy talk; thou art said to be Achilles' male varlet. Male varlet, you rogue! What's that? Why, his masculine whore. Now, the rotten diseases of the south, the guts-griping ruptures, catarrhs, loads o' gravel in the back, lethargies, cold palsies, raw eyes, dirt-rotten livers, wheezing lungs, bladders full of imposthume, sciaticas, limekilns i' th' palm, incurable bone-ache, and the rivelled fee- simple of the tetter, take and take again such preposterous
    </CONTENT>
  </SAMPLE>

  <SAMPLE>
    <AUTHOR>Byron</AUTHOR>
    <CONTENT>
"Why, my dear Lucifer, would you abuse My call for witnesses? I did not mean That you should half of Earth and Hell produce; 'Tis even superfluous, since two honest, clean, True testimonies are enough: we lose Our Time, nay, our Eternity, between The accusation and defence: if we Hear both, 'twill stretch our immortality."
    </CONTENT>
  </SAMPLE>

  <SAMPLE>
    <AUTHOR>Shakespeare</AUTHOR>
    <CONTENT>
bearing a sceptre of gold, on his head a demi-coronal of gold. With him, the EARL OF SURREY, bearing the rod of silver with the dove, crowned with an earl's coronet. Collars of Esses. in his robe of estate, his coronet on his head, bearing a long white wand, as High Steward. With him, the DUKE OF NORFOLK, with the rod of marshalship, a coronet on his head. Collars of Esses. canopy borne by four of the CINQUE-PORTS; under it the QUEEN in her robe; in her hair richly adorned with pearl, crowned. On each side her, the BISHOPS OF LONDON and WINCHESTER. The old DUCHESS OF NORFOLK, in a coronal of gold wrought with flowers, bearing the QUEEN'S train. Certain LADIES or COUNTESSES, with plain circlets of gold without flowers.
    </CONTENT>
  </SAMPLE>

  <SAMPLE>
    <AUTHOR>Shakespeare</AUTHOR>
    <CONTENT>
Roman statesman and general Triumvir after Caesar's death, later Augustus Caesar, first emperor of Rome general and friend of Caesar, a Triumvir after his death third member of the Triumvirate leader of the conspiracy against Caesar instigator of the conspiracy conspirator against Caesar wife of Caesar wife of Brutus senator tribune tribune supportor of Brutus a teacher of rhetoric a poet servant to Brutus servant to Cassius The Ghost of Caesar Soothsayer Poet Senators, Citizens, Soldiers, Commoners, Messengers, and Servants
    </CONTENT>
  </SAMPLE>

  <SAMPLE>
    <AUTHOR>Shakespeare</AUTHOR>
    <CONTENT>
He that had wit would think that I had none, To bury so much gold under a tree And never after to inherit it. Let him that thinks of me so abjectly Know that this gold must coin a stratagem, Which, cunningly effected, will beget very excellent piece of villainy. And so repose, sweet gold, for their unrest  That have their alms out of the Empress' chest.
    </CONTENT>
  </SAMPLE>

  <SAMPLE>
    <AUTHOR>Shakespeare</AUTHOR>
    <CONTENT>
Ratcliff, thyself-or Catesby; where is he? Here, my good lord. Catesby, fly to the Duke. will my lord, with all convenient haste. Ratcliff, come hither. Post to Salisbury; When thou com'st thither-  Dull, unmindfull villain, Why stay'st thou here, and go'st not to the Duke? First, mighty liege, tell me your Highness' pleasure, What from your Grace I shall deliver to him. true, good Catesby. Bid him levy straight The greatest strength and power that he can make And meet me suddenly at Salisbury. go. Exit What, may it please you, shall I do at Salisbury? Why, what wouldst thou do there before I
    </CONTENT>
  </SAMPLE>

  <SAMPLE>
    <AUTHOR>Byron</AUTHOR>
    <CONTENT>
"And one of our apostles, Saul once named, Long persecuted sore the faith of Christ, Till, one day, by the Spirit being inflamed, 'Why dost thou persecute me thus?' said Christ; And then from his offence he was reclaimed, And went for ever after preaching Christ, And of the faith became a trump, whose sounding O'er the whole earth is echoing and rebounding.
    </CONTENT>
  </SAMPLE>

  <SAMPLE>
    <AUTHOR>Byron</AUTHOR>
    <CONTENT>
Here crashed a sturdy oath of stout John Bull, Who damned away his eyes as heretofore: There Paddy brogued "By Jasus!" -- "What's your wull?" The temperate Scot exclaimed: the French ghost swore In certain terms I shan't translate in full, As the first coachman will; and 'midst the war, The voice of Jonathan was heard to express, "Our President is going to war, I guess."
    </CONTENT>
  </SAMPLE>

  <SAMPLE>
    <AUTHOR>Byron</AUTHOR>
    <CONTENT>
change came o'er the spirit of my dream. The Wanderer was alone as heretofore, The beings which surrounded him were gone, Or were at war with him; he was a mark For blight and desolation, compassed round With Hatred and Contention; Pain was mixed In all which was served up to him, until, Like to the Pontic monarch of old days, marvel and a secret -- Be it so.
    </CONTENT>
  </SAMPLE>

  <SAMPLE>
    <AUTHOR>Byron</AUTHOR>
    <CONTENT>
More mysteries, and awful ones! But now, Or thou, or I, or both, it may be, are Upon the verge of ruin; speak once out, And thou art safe and glorious: for 'tis more Glorious to save than slay, and slay i' the dark too -- Fie, Bertram! that was not a craft for thee! How would it look to see upon a spear The head of him whose heart was open to thee! Borne by thy hand before the shuddering people? And such may be my doom; for here I swear, Whate'er the peril or the penalty Of thy denunciation, I go forth, Unless thou dost detail the cause, and show The consequence of all which led thee here!
    </CONTENT>
  </SAMPLE>

  <SAMPLE>
    <AUTHOR>Shakespeare</AUTHOR>
    <CONTENT>
Forsooth, I have forgot. It is qui, quae, quod; if you forget your qui's, your quae's, and your quod's, you must be preeches. Go your ways and play; go. He is a better scholar than I thought he was. He is a good sprag memory. Farewell, Mistress Page. Adieu, good Sir Hugh. Exit SIR HUGH Get you home, boy. Come, we stay too long. Exeunt
    </CONTENT>
  </SAMPLE>

  <SAMPLE>
    <AUTHOR>Shakespeare</AUTHOR>
    <CONTENT>
Have done, have done; here comes the gentleman. Welcome, dear Proteus! Mistress, I beseech you Confirm his welcome with some special favour. His worth is warrant for his welcome hither, If this be he you oft have wish'd to hear from. Mistress, it is; sweet lady, entertain him To be my fellow-servant to your ladyship. Too low a mistress for so high a servant. Not so, sweet lady; but too mean a servant To have a look of such a worthy mistress. Leave off discourse of disability; Sweet lady, entertain him for your servant. My duty will I boast of, nothing else. And duty never yet did want his meed. Servant, you are welcome to a worthless mistress. I'll die on him that says so but yourself. That you are welcome? That you are worthless.
    </CONTENT>
  </SAMPLE>

  <SAMPLE>
    <AUTHOR>Shakespeare</AUTHOR>
    <CONTENT>
pardon me in that my boast is true! The accident which brought me to her eye Upon the moment did her force subdue, And now she would the caged cloister fly. Religious love put out religion's eye. Not to be tempted, would she be immured, And now to tempt all liberty procured.
    </CONTENT>
  </SAMPLE>

  <SAMPLE>
    <AUTHOR>Shakespeare</AUTHOR>
    <CONTENT>
father, what a hell of witchcraft lies In the small orb of one particular tear! But with the inundation of the eyes What rocky heart to water will not wear? What breast so cold that is not warmed here? cleft effect! cold modesty, hot wrath, Both fire from hence and chill extincture hath.
    </CONTENT>
  </SAMPLE>

  <SAMPLE>
    <AUTHOR>Byron</AUTHOR>
    <CONTENT>
"He is what you behold him, and his doom Depends upon his deeds," the Angel said; "If you have aught to arraign in him, the tomb Gives license to the humblest beggar's head To lift itself against the loftiest." -- "Some," Said Wilkes, "don't wait to see them laid in lead, For such a liberty -- and I, for one, Have told them what I thought beneath the sun."
    </CONTENT>
  </SAMPLE>

  <SAMPLE>
    <AUTHOR>Byron</AUTHOR>
    <CONTENT>
Oh! I but thus prolonged my words, Boasting these idle attributes, because As I approach the core of my heart's grief -- But -- to my task. I have not named to thee Father or mother, mistress, friend, or being, With whom I wore the chain of human ties; If I had such, they seemed not such to me -- Yet there was One --  --
    </CONTENT>
  </SAMPLE>

  <SAMPLE>
    <AUTHOR>Byron</AUTHOR>
    <CONTENT>
say that I can tell -- 'twas half a minute; know the solar beams take up more time Ere, packed up for their journey, they begin it; And if they ran a race, they would not win it 'Gainst Satan's couriers bound for their own clime. The sun takes up some years for every ray To reach its goal -- the Devil not half a day.
    </CONTENT>
  </SAMPLE>

  <SAMPLE>
    <AUTHOR>Byron</AUTHOR>
    <CONTENT>
But saving this, you may put on whate'er You like by way of doublet, cape, or cloak, Such as in Monmouth-street, or in Rag Fair, Would rig you out in seriousness or joke; And even in Italy such places are, With prettier name in softer accents spoke, For, bating Covent Garden, I can hit on No place that's called "Piazza" in Great Britain.
    </CONTENT>
  </SAMPLE>

  <SAMPLE>
    <AUTHOR>Byron</AUTHOR>
    <CONTENT>
And thus great honour to Morgante paid The Abbot: many days they did repose. One day, as with Orlando they both strayed, And sauntered here and there, where'er they chose, The Abbot showed a chamber, where arrayed Much armour was, and hung up certain bows; And one of these Morgante for a whim Girt on, though useless, he believed, to him.
    </CONTENT>
  </SAMPLE>

  <SAMPLE>
    <AUTHOR>Shakespeare</AUTHOR>
    <CONTENT>
But wherefore do not you a mightier way Make war upon this bloody tyrant Time? And fortify your self in your decay With means more blessed than my barren rhyme? Now stand you on the top of happy hours, And many maiden gardens yet unset, With virtuous wish would bear you living flowers, Much liker than your painted counterfeit: So should the lines of life that life repair Which this (Time's pencil) or my pupil pen Neither in inward worth nor outward fair Can make you live your self in eyes of men. To give away your self, keeps your self still, And you must live drawn by your own sweet skill.
    </CONTENT>
  </SAMPLE>

  <SAMPLE>
    <AUTHOR>Byron</AUTHOR>
    <CONTENT>
Besides, within the Alps, to every woman, (Although, God knows, it is a grievous sin,) 'Tis, I may say, permitted to have two men; can't tell who first brought the custom in, But "Cavalier Serventes" are quite common, And no one notices or cares a pin; An we may call this (not to say the worst) second marriage which corrupts the first.
    </CONTENT>
  </SAMPLE>

  <SAMPLE>
    <AUTHOR>Shakespeare</AUTHOR>
    <CONTENT>
In delivering my son from me, I bury a second husband. And I in going, madam, weep o'er my father's death anew; but I must attend his Majesty's command, to whom I am now in ward, evermore in subjection. You shall find of the King a husband, madam; you, sir, a father. He that so generally is at all times good must of necessity hold his virtue to you, whose worthiness would stir it up where it wanted, rather than lack it where there is such
    </CONTENT>
  </SAMPLE>

  <SAMPLE>
    <AUTHOR>Shakespeare</AUTHOR>
    <CONTENT>
Well, here he comes. Calmly, I do beseech you. Ay, as an ostler, that for th' poorest piece Will bear the knave by th' volume. Th' honour'd gods Keep Rome in safety, and the chairs of justice Supplied with worthy men! plant love among's! Throng our large temples with the shows of peace, And not our streets with war! Amen, amen! noble wish.
    </CONTENT>
  </SAMPLE>

  <SAMPLE>
    <AUTHOR>Shakespeare</AUTHOR>
    <CONTENT>
Thersites! Agamemnon-how if he had boils full, an over, generally? Thersites! And those boils did run-say so. Did not the general run then? Were not that a botchy core? Dog! Then there would come some matter from him; see none now. Thou bitch-wolf's son, canst thou not hear? Feel, then.  The plague of Greece upon thee, thou mongrel beef-witted
    </CONTENT>
  </SAMPLE>

  <SAMPLE>
    <AUTHOR>Byron</AUTHOR>
    <CONTENT>
Our trial! will they keep their mockery up Even to the last? but let them deal upon us, As we had dealt on them, but with less pomp. 'Tis but a game of mutual homicides, Who have cast lots for the first death, and they Have won with false dice. -- Who hath been our Judas?
    </CONTENT>
  </SAMPLE>

  <SAMPLE>
    <AUTHOR>Byron</AUTHOR>
    <CONTENT>
If my inheritance of storms hath been In other elements, and on the rocks Of perils, overlooked or unforeseen, have sustained my share of worldly shocks, The fault was mine; nor do I seek to screen My errors with defensive paradox; have been cunning in mine overthrow, The careful pilot of my proper woe.
    </CONTENT>
  </SAMPLE>

  <SAMPLE>
    <AUTHOR>Byron</AUTHOR>
    <CONTENT>
But ere he could return to his repose, Cherub flapped his right wing o'er his eyes -- At which Saint Peter yawned, and rubbed his nose: "Saint porter," said the angel, "prithee rise!" Waving a goodly wing, which glowed, as glows An earthly peacock's tail, with heavenly dyes: To which the saint replied, "Well, what's the matter? "Is Lucifer come back with all this clatter?"
    </CONTENT>
  </SAMPLE>

</CUSTOMSAMPLES>
